<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NEAR Day Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/near-day/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/near-day/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 15:41:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>NEAR Day Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/near-day/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Near at ETHDenver: the Blockchain Operating System, Near Day, and More</title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-ethdenver-the-blockchain-operating-system-near-day-and-more/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain Operating System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHDenver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Missed Near Day and ETHDenver 2023? We’ve got you covered with content from Near talks and panels. There were also …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethdenver-the-blockchain-operating-system-near-day-and-more/">Near at ETHDenver: the Blockchain Operating System, Near Day, and More</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Missed Near Day and ETHDenver 2023? We’ve got you covered with content from Near talks and panels. There were also a number of awesome announcements, including the big news out of ETHDenver — the <a href="/blog/near-announces-the-blockchain-operating-system/">Blockchain Operating System</a>. </p>



<p>Let’s take a look at all that was Near at ETHDenver. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-day-talks">Near Day talks</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_NEAR-is-the-BOS_Illia-Polosukhin_030223-1024x575.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20291" width="1024" height="575" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_NEAR-is-the-BOS_Illia-Polosukhin_030223-1024x575.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_NEAR-is-the-BOS_Illia-Polosukhin_030223-300x168.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_NEAR-is-the-BOS_Illia-Polosukhin_030223-768x431.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_NEAR-is-the-BOS_Illia-Polosukhin_030223-1536x863.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_NEAR-is-the-BOS_Illia-Polosukhin_030223-2048x1150.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Near co-founder and Pagoda CEO Illia Polosukhin unveiling the Blockchain Operating System.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Near Day, the 1-day mini summit on all things Near, was jam-packed with the latest technological and protocol updates. Chief among them was the announcement of the Blockchain Operating System. </p>



<p>Things got started with a Regenerative Finance (ReFI) talk from Open Forest Protocol&#8217;s Frederic Fournier and Flow Carbon&#8217;s Phil Fogel. Later in the morning programme, OnMachina’s Polina Aladina and Mark Collier talked about building decentralized storage on Near. As a vital Near ecosystem project, it was great for the ETHDenver crowd to hear from OnMachina on Web3 storage. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="575" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_How-to-Build-Decentralized-Storage-on-NEAR_Mark-Collier_030223-1024x575.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20293" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_How-to-Build-Decentralized-Storage-on-NEAR_Mark-Collier_030223-1024x575.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_How-to-Build-Decentralized-Storage-on-NEAR_Mark-Collier_030223-300x168.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_How-to-Build-Decentralized-Storage-on-NEAR_Mark-Collier_030223-768x431.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_How-to-Build-Decentralized-Storage-on-NEAR_Mark-Collier_030223-1536x863.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_How-to-Build-Decentralized-Storage-on-NEAR_Mark-Collier_030223-2048x1150.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">OnMachina&#8217;s Mark Collier talking decentralized storage on Near. </figcaption></figure>



<p>Keypom, which also recently launched on Near, got some much needed visibility at Near Day. In “Instant Crypto Experiences with Keypom”,&nbsp; Ben Kurrek and Matt Lockyer took the audience on a tour of their Web3 onboarding solution, in which users are given a special type of access key that can be used to experience a crypto application and later be turned into a wallet. (Read more about Keypom <a href="/blog/keypom-brings-frictionless-onboarding-to-near-and-web3/">here</a>.)</p>



<p>The morning programme also featured talks from Calimero Network’s Sandi Fatic on privacy and scaling with private sharding; Aurora Labs’ Alex Shevchenko on Containers, Aurora’s cloud computing solution for blockchains; Sweat Economy’s Oleg Fomenko on how to effectively onboard people from Web2 to Web3; and Near co-founder Alex Skidanov on how the future of AI will be decentralized. </p>



<p>In the afternoon, there were a range of talks, starting with Pagoda’s Max Zavershynskyi presentation on creating “high velocity developer communities” via Near DevGov DAO. But the big news on Near Day was the <a href="/blog/near-announces-the-blockchain-operating-system/">Blockchain Operating System</a> talk from Near co-founder Illia Polosukhin. After Illia primed the audience, Pagoda’s Chief Product Officer Alex Chiocchi elaborated on how Blockchain Operating System will help in onboarding millions of users to Near, while Pagoda’s Bowen Wang detailed the protocol innovations powering the Blockchain Operating System. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="579" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_Crypto-Winter-Bullish-Builders_Marieke-Flament_030223-1024x579.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20292" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_Crypto-Winter-Bullish-Builders_Marieke-Flament_030223-1024x579.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_Crypto-Winter-Bullish-Builders_Marieke-Flament_030223-300x170.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_Crypto-Winter-Bullish-Builders_Marieke-Flament_030223-768x435.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_Crypto-Winter-Bullish-Builders_Marieke-Flament_030223-1536x869.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes-ETHDenverDay1_MainStage_Crypto-Winter-Bullish-Builders_Marieke-Flament_030223-2048x1159.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Marieke Flament on the ETHDenver main stage for the &#8216;Crypto Winter, Bullish Builders&#8217; panel.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Near Foundation CEO Marieke Flament and Dragonfly Capital’s Haseeb Qureshi also talked about why the future remains bright for Web3 even during the crypto winter. There were also talks from Pagoda’s Pavel Kudinov on the Near data stack and Josh Ford on a fully decentralized Javascript.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Other topics included the building of infrastructure to onboard 1 billion users on Near, NFT infrastructure, a “DeFi survival kit” for the bear market, and the regulatory landscape in Web3.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-speakers-at-ethdenver">Near speakers at ETHDenver </h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="575" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_NEARs-Vision-for-Layer-1-Infrastructure_Bowen-Wang_01_030423-1024x575.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20294" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_NEARs-Vision-for-Layer-1-Infrastructure_Bowen-Wang_01_030423-1024x575.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_NEARs-Vision-for-Layer-1-Infrastructure_Bowen-Wang_01_030423-300x168.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_NEARs-Vision-for-Layer-1-Infrastructure_Bowen-Wang_01_030423-768x431.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_NEARs-Vision-for-Layer-1-Infrastructure_Bowen-Wang_01_030423-1536x863.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_NEARs-Vision-for-Layer-1-Infrastructure_Bowen-Wang_01_030423-2048x1150.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pagoda&#8217;s Bowen Wang discussing Near&#8217;s vision for Layer 1 infrastructure. </figcaption></figure>



<p>A number of speakers represented the Near ecosystem at ETHDenver talks. Topics included the Blockchain Operating System, sustainability, UX design, and more. </p>



<p>Aurora Labs’ Alex Shevchenko kicked things off with a presentation on Web3 infrastructure and scalability — specifically, how not to hack everything up in creating bridges. Alex also gave another talk on next generation user experience. Near Foundation CEO Marieke Flament delivered a talk on the three pillars of Web3 sustainability, while Proximity Labs’ Kendall Cole explored how Web3 can win in the DeFi battle against app stores. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="575" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_Next-gen-blockchain-UX_Alex-Shevchenko_02_030423-1024x575.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20295" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_Next-gen-blockchain-UX_Alex-Shevchenko_02_030423-1024x575.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_Next-gen-blockchain-UX_Alex-Shevchenko_02_030423-300x168.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_Next-gen-blockchain-UX_Alex-Shevchenko_02_030423-768x431.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_Next-gen-blockchain-UX_Alex-Shevchenko_02_030423-1536x863.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/HiRes_ETHDenverDay3_InfrastructureScalability_Next-gen-blockchain-UX_Alex-Shevchenko_02_030423-2048x1150.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Aurora Labs CEO Alex Shevchenko delivering a talk at ETHDenver.</figcaption></figure>



<p>In separate talks, Illia Polosukhin and Pagoda’s Bowen Wang spoke to the ETHDenver audience about the Blockchain Operating System. While Bowen mapped out Near&#8217;s vision for Layer 1 Infrastructure, Illia talked about reinventing Web3 development with decentralized frontends and social networking. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-announcements">Near Announcements</h2>



<p>While the <a href="/blog/near-announces-the-blockchain-operation-system/?_gl=1%2Ancfu51%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2ANTY5OTQyMjAxLjE2NzgwMjk4ODA.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY3ODAyOTg3OC4xLjAuMTY3ODAyOTg3OC4wLjAuMA..">Near is the Blockchain Operating System</a> announcement was the talk of ETHDenver, there were plenty of other announcements. Find the full run-down of Near ecosystem announcements <a href="/blog/near-at-ethdenver-highlights/?_gl=1%2Apsni5a%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2ANTY5OTQyMjAxLjE2NzgwMjk4ODA.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY3ODAyOTg3OC4xLjAuMTY3ODAyOTg3OC4wLjAuMA..">here</a>.</p>



<p>In other news, the Near ecosystem had two wins at ETHVC’s Startup Demo Day during ETHDenver — Niche Protocol, a Web3 social media platform, and Kino, a film financing platform.  </p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethdenver-the-blockchain-operating-system-near-day-and-more/">Near at ETHDenver: the Blockchain Operating System, Near Day, and More</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Near at ETHDenver Highlights </title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-ethdenver-highlights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 16:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHDenver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Few and Far]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Near will see a number of&#160;partnership and project announcements at Near Day and ETHDenver. Over a 1,000 people are attending …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethdenver-highlights/">Near at ETHDenver Highlights </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Near will see a number of&nbsp;partnership and project announcements at Near Day and ETHDenver. Over a 1,000 people are attending Near Day, with many more visiting the Near booth and dropping in on ETHDenver talks and panels featuring Near ecosystem figures. Beyond the many engaging talks and projects demos, there was also an ecosystem party, side events, a hackathon, and much more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s take a quick look at a few of the latest announcements from Near at ETHDenver.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>A number of other announcements will be rolling out over the course of Near Day and ETHDenver, so stay tuned for those below in the coming days.</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-few-and-far-raises-10-5-million-in-funding">Few and Far raises $10.5 million in funding</h2>



<p>Few and Far, a leading Digital Collectibles web3 platform, announced today that it has raised $10.5 million in a funding round led by Pantera Capital, the leading blockchain investment firm.The raise marks a significant milestone for Few and Far, which has been experiencing exponential growth since launch.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The new funds will help expand the platform&#8217;s capabilities, enhance user experience, and increase the number of Web3 developers. IP owners also stand to benefit from the platform. Few and Far features an all-inclusive platform available to carry out everything related to next generation digital collectibles, including a suite of developer tools.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The round also included top VCs, Cypher Capital, Huobi Ventures, Hypersphere, Metaweb, Mantis Partners, K5 Global and many more.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Near Blockchain Operating System now live on Alpha.Near.Org</h2>



<p><em>Read the full Near Blockchain Operating System announcement <a href="/blog/near-announces-the-blockchain-operation-system/">here</a></em></p>



<p>For Near Day on March 2nd, Near launched <a href="https://alpha.nearpages.wpengine.com/">alpha.nearpages.wpengine.com</a> — a composable frontend for Web3. It will allow end users to easily and frictionlessly discover all of Web3’s possibilities in one seamless experience. It will also empower developers to create and code interfaces in a single environment with the ability to fork a host of components to build apps faster and more efficiently than ever before.</p>



<p>Anyone in the Open Web ecosystem can create their own frontends (i.e., their own versions of alpha.nearpages.wpengine.com), compatible with the blockchain of their choice. This means that builders from any ecosystem can create components in just a few lines of code, and take advantage of fast onboarding to help make new and custom Web3 experiences.</p>



<p>This is an industry first. With the addition of composable frontends to the tech stack, Near now becomes the Blockchain Operating System, allowing seamless, one-time onboarding and removing friction points like making accounts for every experience, while supercharging development from a collection of over 1,800 components.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Alpha.nearpages.wpengine.com is the first step in Near’s Blockchain Operating System journey. It’s the Alpha version, where builders can see the frontend come to life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Try out the Alpha at <a href="https://alpha.nearpages.wpengine.com/">alpha.nearpages.wpengine.com</a> to experience the world’s first Blockchain Operating System — a revolutionary moment in Web3. If you’re a developer, see how easy it is to fork components and create new experiences. If you’re an end user, see how easy it is to explore Web3 experiences, social, and news all in one place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Blockchain Operating System is Near and it’s here. #NearistheBOS</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Carbon announces carbon-market ecosystem built on Near</h2>



<p>Near and <a href="https://www.flowcarbon.com/">Flowcarbon</a>, the pioneering climate technology company, announced the launch of a carbon-market ecosystem that will enable carbon credits to be traded on the Near network through Flowcarbon’s tokenized carbon credits. With this collaboration, Near will realize its vision of becoming a carbon-negative blockchain. As part of this partnership, Near plans to offset its carbon footprint through Flowcarbon.</p>



<p>Flow Carbon’s carbon credit token will be launched on both Near and Aurora, an Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM) built on Near. Validators will be set up for the purpose of offsetting, and large Near holders will be able to stake with these validators.</p>



<p>Designed to make carbon offsetting more accessible and transparent, this partnership will help Near become carbon-negative, solidifying Near’s position as one of the top players in Regenerative Finance (ReFi).&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">With Stacksports, parents and athletes can mint royalty-free NFTs</h2>



<p>StackNFT is teaming up with Near to offer an NFT platform that allows youth athletes of all ages and skill levels to create and capture their favorite sports memories digitally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Youth sports parents and athletes can now mint royalty-free NFTs effortlessly, without any advanced knowledge of the minting or wallet creation process. Just upload, decorate, and mint. Parents and athletes can also mint NFTs knowing that Near is a carbon-neutral, environmentally friendly blockchain, which supports several forest protection and restoration projects.</p>



<p>StackNFT is owned and operated by Stack Sports, a global technology leader in SaaS platform offerings for the sports industry, with nearly 50 million users in 35 countries. From little league to the pros, Stack Sports powers the many moments that create the story of your journey through sports.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Calimero’s private shard infrastructure now live on Near </h2>



<p>Calimero.network, a secure private shard infrastructure provider announced that after several months running in a stealth mode, during which it was tested by beta testers and partners, is ready to serve customers with unique blockchain power and a Web2 interface.</p>



<p>With roots in the Near Protocol, Calimero is a high performance blockchain that launched on mainnet in 2020. Founded by Sandi Fatic and Mario Halambek, two of the first infrastructure engineers at Near, Calimero allows projects to launch their own shard in a matter of minutes. In launching a private shard, users can be certain of the network’s performance and security, which is managed by Calimero itself.</p>



<p>Calimero is targeting so-called “Web2.5”, seeking a way to connect Web3 and Web2 worlds. For Web3 startups, Calimero provides a unique way to scale their products and leverage the privacy features, giving access to target Enterprise customers and getting access to new audiences. For classic Enterprises, Calimero offers a way to build new products and onboard chosen Web3 mechanics to find new areas to grow their businesses with growth rates compared to DeFi and NFT markets.</p>



<p>With the cheapest option starting from less than $300, Calimero provides a flexible model to maximize the cost efficiency by adjusting shard performance according to the load. Calimero also offers a 14-day grace period to test out the platform for startups who are in the very beginning of their journey.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Calimero.network is a London-based startup that has recently raised an investment round of $8.5M, co-led by Khosla Ventures, Lyrik Ventures, and Near foundation.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Near Foundation Council updates </h2>



<p>Near Foundation announced that Mona El Isa, a founding council member at Near Foundation Council (NFC), has been appointed as Chair.&nbsp; Marieke Flament, CEO of Near Foundation, has joined&nbsp;as a council member, and will govern alongside existing members Richard Muirhead, Chairman and Managing Partner at Fabric Ventures, and Jason Warner, Managing Director at Redpoint Ventures as well as Sheila Warren advisor to Near Foundation and&nbsp; CEO of the Crypto Council for Innovation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mona takes the place of Illia Polosukhin, co-founder of Near Protocol and CEO of Pagoda (formerly Near Inc.), who has stepped down as Chair and member of the&nbsp; Near Foundation Council (NFC) to focus on Web3 ecosystem development and participation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“It was an honor to serve as Chair and Council Member of the NEAR Foundation Council over the past two years,” said Illia Polosukhin. “I&#8217;m stepping down in order to focus fully on the development of products and technology at Pagoda, which is critical to the continuing success of the NEAR Ecosystem.”</p>



<p>“I will continue to be involved with NFC in my capacity as Pagoda CEO,” he added. “From a governance perspective, my departure increases the council’s independence and further decentralizes leadership and decision-making in the NEAR Ecosystem. I welcome Mona’s appointment as the new Chair and Marieke&#8217;s as council member to continue steering the Foundation in its mission of supporting NEAR’s growth.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethdenver-highlights/">Near at ETHDenver Highlights </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Day at ETHDenver: Ethereum Without Limits</title>
		<link>/blog/near-day-at-ethdenver-ethereum-without-limits/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHDenver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=19730</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>ETHDenver is once again upon us. NEAR will be there with a full schedule of talks, panels, bounties, after parties, …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-day-at-ethdenver-ethereum-without-limits/">NEAR Day at ETHDenver: Ethereum Without Limits</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>ETHDenver is once again upon us. NEAR will be there with a full schedule of talks, panels, bounties, after parties, and more, exploring why NEAR is the place where mainstream adoption of the Open Web will happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEAR makes building and innovating on Web3 simple, secure, and scalable — all well before “The Merge”. Soon, anyone in the world—devs, founders, creators, and app users — will be able to create without limits. Join us on March 2nd for <a href="/denver">NEAR Day</a> at ETHDenver — a 1-day mini summit on all things NEAR. From March 3rd to March 5th, join NEAR at ETHDenver for the Main Event and Hackathon.</p>



<p>Registering for NEAR Day is free. Sign up for a spot via the link below to meet people from the NEAR community and join the hackathon! To join NEAR Day at ETHDenver, you will also need an ETHDenver pass.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why NEAR @ ETH Denver?&nbsp;</h2>



<p>With the <a href="https://aurora.dev/">Aurora EVM</a> and <a href="https://rainbowbridge.app/transfer">Rainbow Bridge</a>, the NEAR ecosystem is basically “Ethereum without limits”. While NEAR will be in attendance to help foster a decentralized multi-chain future, NEAR is showcasing why it’s the platform of choice for Web3 builders and onboarding the masses into the Open Web.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Register for NEAR Day at ETHDenver</h2>



<p>Builders, creators, and entrepreneurs will find us at NEAR Day, a 1-day mini summit on ETHDenver’s Main Stage of the National Western Complex on March 2nd. From March 3rd &#8211; March 5th, find the NEAR ecosystem booth during ETHDenver and mingle with NEAR Devs, Community members, and others from the ecosystem.</p>



<p>To participate at NEAR Day, all you need to do is register via the link below and have an ETHDenver pass. ETHDenver is a free event. Register now to secure your spot and find out why NEAR is the easiest, most accessible, and scalable blockchain in Web3. Stay tuned for more details!</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="/denver" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Register for NEAR Day</a></div>
</div>



<p><em>For the full schedule and information about NEAR Day at ETHDenver&nbsp; as well as #BUIDLWEEK and Main Event, please visit our event page. Check out </em><a href="https://www.ethdenver.com/schedule"><em>ETHDenver’s full schedule</em></a><em> to learn more about featured NEAR sessions and more.&nbsp;</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Join the Hackathon</h2>



<p>Join ETHDenver’s Hackathon and build on NEAR. Members of NEAR Foundation, Aurora, and other projects will be on-site to help onboard devs, creators, and entrepreneurs into NEAR and advise on building dApps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Building on NEAR is easy and fun, and you’ll instantly be part of a vibrant and supportive community. Let’s get you started!</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.ethdenver.com/buidlweek">Register for Hackathon</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-notable-speakers-at-near-day-and-ethdenver"><strong>Notable Speakers at NEAR Day and ETHDenver</strong></h2>



<p>Catch a number of exciting NEAR speakers and sessions at NEAR Day and ETHDenver. The final list of participants and sessions is still being solidified. However, we do have some speakers to highlight.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Illia Polusukhin &#8211; NEAR Co-founder, CEO of NEAR</li>



<li>Marieke Flament &#8211; CEO of NEAR Foundation</li>



<li>Alex Shevchenko &#8211; CEO of Aurora Labs</li>



<li>Alex Skidanov &#8211; NEAR Co-founder</li>



<li>Polina Aladina &#8211; OnMachina Co-Founder</li>
</ul>



<p>Learn about our other speakers at the <a href="/denver">NEAR Day</a> event page. </p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-day-at-ethdenver-ethereum-without-limits/">NEAR Day at ETHDenver: Ethereum Without Limits</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
