<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Partnerships Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/partnerships/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/partnerships/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 18:59:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.orghttps://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Partnerships Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/partnerships/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</title>
		<link>/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI is NEAR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hackathon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with Edge and Polygon Labs, the NEAR Foundation will co-sponsor a Decentralized AI Summit and “Autonomous Agent,” an …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/">Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In collaboration with Edge and Polygon Labs, the NEAR Foundation will co-sponsor a Decentralized AI <a href="https://lu.ma/fvoeazk8">Summit</a> and “Autonomous Agent,” an AI x Web3 <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/autonomous-agent-hackathon">Hackathon</a>, at ETHDenver on February 26 and 27. The events will bring together visionaries, developers, and enthusiasts working at the intersection of AI and Web3 along with a hackathon for builders and researchers to dive into the buzziest tech topic of today. Speakers at the Summit will include Vitalik Buterin of the Ethereum Foundation, Illia Polosukhin of NEAR Foundation, Sandeep Nailwal of Polygon Labs, and Sreeram Kannan of EigenLayer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Autonomous Agent” is the first event in the &#8220;{Chain}-of-Thought&#8221; series from <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/">Edge</a>, which will explore and harness the potential of Web3 and open source AI. Edge is a research and development organization dedicated to democratizing access to open intelligence and advancing the evolution of next-generation web architecture. Hackers can expect hands-on hacking sessions, workshops, and mentorship opportunities with a chance to learn from those at the cutting edge of decentralized AI development. </p>



<p>The intersection of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Web3 technology is poised to revolutionize industries, with many Web3 projects now incorporating AI into decentralized applications and developer tools. Ethereum Co-Founder Vitalik Buterin recently shared his <a href="https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2024/01/30/cryptoai.html">observations</a> about the intersection, and NEAR Co-Founder Illia Polosukhin shared how AI fits into the vision for the NEAR ecosystem in a recent <a href="/blog/self-sovereignty-is-near-a-vision-for-our-ecosystem/">post</a>. </p>



<p>As the risks from centralized AI controlled primarily by major corporations become more apparent, investing in open source, transparent AI development will become increasingly important––along with community building, governance experiments, and advocacy. “{Chain} of Thought” will lead the way in bringing members of the AI and Web3 ecosystems together to advance these initiatives and make concrete progress.</p>



<p>In addition to the premier sponsors, the “Autonomous Agent” hackathon is co-sponsored by <a href="https://www.eigenlayer.xyz/">EigenLayer</a>, <a href="https://www.gensyn.ai/">Gensyn</a>, and <a href="https://www.hyperoracle.io/">Hyper Oracle</a>, with co-hosting participation from Sentient, Lightspeed, and Symbolic Capital. Benefits of participation include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Cutting-Edge Workshops:</strong> Engage with industry experts and thought leaders through immersive workshops exploring the latest trends and technologies in AI x Web3.</li>



<li><strong>Hackathon Challenges:</strong> Tackle real-world challenges and showcase your creativity by developing innovative solutions at the forefront of AI and Web3 integration.</li>



<li><strong>Networking Opportunities:</strong> Connect with like-minded individuals, potential collaborators, and industry professionals to expand your network and exchange ideas.</li>



<li><strong>Prizes and Recognition:</strong> Compete for exciting prizes and gain recognition for your contributions to the advancement of AI x Web3 technology.</li>
</ul>



<p>Join NEAR Foundation, Polygon Labs, and Edge in Denver and be a part of the next great tech revolution. Those interested in attending the Decentralized AI Summit can register <a href="https://lu.ma/fvoeazk8">here</a>. Researchers, developers, and hackers interested in participating in the <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/autonomous-agent-hackathon">hackathon</a> can apply <a href="https://lu.ma/k6dw9jk2">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/">Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation and Blumer: Pioneering Web3 Social Networking in Latin America</title>
		<link>/blog/near-foundation-and-blumer-pioneering-web3-social-networking-in-latin-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a strategic partnership with Blumer, Colombia&#8217;s first Web3 social network. This collaboration signifies a …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-and-blumer-pioneering-web3-social-networking-in-latin-america/">NEAR Foundation and Blumer: Pioneering Web3 Social Networking in Latin America</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a strategic partnership with <a href="https://blumer.cc/">Blumer</a>, Colombia&#8217;s first Web3 social network. This collaboration signifies a new era in social media where active users are incentivized for their contributions, marking a transformative shift in the user-social platform dynamic.</p>



<p>By harnessing the strengths of blockchain technology and integrating them with the vibrant world of social networking, this partnership aims to challenge the status quo, prioritizing user privacy, compensation, and education. It&#8217;s a pioneering effort that not only champions user-centric design, but also sets the stage for a more inclusive digital future in Latin America.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-blumer-revolutionizing-social-media-through-blockchain-technology">Blumer: Revolutionizing Social Media through Blockchain Technology</h2>



<p>Blumer, the first Web3 social network created and developed in Colombia, is an innovative platform that combines the functionality of traditional social networks with the advantages of blockchain technology. What makes Blumer so unique is that users are compensated for time spent on social media, distributing 18% of its advertising revenue back to its community.</p>



<p>“At Blumer, we believe in creating a social network for everyone,” says Ernesto Ruiz, Blumer’s CEO. “Our platform is designed to be a space where users can express themselves, connect with friends, and learn about the crypto world. We’re committed to creating a platform that is fun, engaging, and rewarding for everyone involved.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>As Ruiz alludes to, Blumer users can monetize their time spent on social media through a variety of activities like consuming advertisements, selling NFTs, and performing crypto transactions. This not only promotes user engagement but emphasizes a novel approach to commercial growth, derived largely from businesses undertaking digital marketing.</p>



<p>Blumer isn’t just social media landscape but reshaping the whole digital economy narrative. Its unique approach of monetizing user engagement and activity on social media paves the way for a paradigm shift in user interaction and value creation. Let&#8217;s now delve into how this innovative platform aims to advance the adoption of Web3 in Latin America, one educated user at a time.</p>



<p>“This partnership is a significant step towards creating a fair and transparent social media ecosystem,” adds Marieke Flament, CEO of NEAR Foundation. “By combining the benefits of blockchain technology with social media, we are set to revolutionize how we interact on social platforms.“</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-educating-users-and-advancing-latin-american-web3-adoption">Educating users and advancing Latin American Web3 adoption</h2>



<p>Blumer also tackles the significant challenges facing cryptocurrency adoption in Latin America —&nbsp;namely, the lack of knowledge, understanding, and real market usability. Through ZVerso, its free crypto education platform, Blumer is empowering users with the knowledge to confidently engage within the Web3 ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By providing users with essential blockchain education and tools, Blumer is making strides toward democratizing access to Web3 technologies. This proactive educational initiative aligns with a broader vision for a more decentralized, inclusive, and user-centric digital future in Latin America.</p>



<p>With an online population of over 54 million people, Latin America and the Caribbean form the fifth-largest global market for social media. South America alone boasts over 30 million users. The NEAR and Blumer partnership provides a unique opportunity to tap into this thriving hub and bolster the adoption of Web3 solutions.</p>



<p>“With NEAR&#8217;s support, we are confident that we can achieve our vision and create a social network fit to thrive in tomorrow’s landscape,” Ruiz adds.</p>



<p>The collaboration between NEAR and Blumer signifies a pivotal stride towards fostering a fair, transparent, and user-centric social media ecosystem. As Blumer forges ahead with innovative advancements in decentralized social networking, the NEAR Foundation and ecosystem give one big “Like” to Blumer’s mission of a user-empowered social network.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-and-blumer-pioneering-web3-social-networking-in-latin-america/">NEAR Foundation and Blumer: Pioneering Web3 Social Networking in Latin America</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR at ETHCC Highlights: Sustainability and the BOS Take Center Stage in Paris</title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-ethcc-highlights-sustainability-and-the-bos-take-center-stage-in-paris/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Missed out on NEAR’s rendezvous at ETHCC 2023 in Paris? No need to worry. In this roundup, all NEAR enthusiasts …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-highlights-sustainability-and-the-bos-take-center-stage-in-paris/">NEAR at ETHCC Highlights: Sustainability and the BOS Take Center Stage in Paris</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Missed out on NEAR’s rendezvous at ETHCC 2023 in Paris? No need to worry. In this roundup, all NEAR enthusiasts can catch up on the enlightening presentations by BOS, Web3, and blockchain experts. You’re in the perfect place to delve into notable announcements made during the conference, from <a href="/blog/near-foundation-signs-up-to-the-ethereum-climate-platform/?_gl=1%2A1nco86y%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTQ5MTA4NDUzMS4xNjg5Njk0NDEy%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4xLjAuMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4wLjAuMA..">NEAR signing up to the Ethereum Climate Platform</a> to an epic new <a href="/blog/interactive-polygon-zkevm-app-dashboard-launches-on-the-near-blockchain-operating-system/?_gl=1%2A1nco86y%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTQ5MTA4NDUzMS4xNjg5Njk0NDEy%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4xLjAuMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4wLjAuMA..">interactive Polygon zkEVM app dashboard</a>.</p>



<p>ICYMI, it’s time to dive into all the key speeches, events, and announcements that unfolded in the City of Lights over this past weekend.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-interactive-polygon-zkevm-app-dashboard-launches-on-the-bos">Interactive Polygon zkEVM app dashboard launches on the BOS</h2>



<p>In the most significant partnership announcement of ETHCC, an <a href="/blog/interactive-polygon-zkevm-app-dashboard-launches-on-the-near-blockchain-operating-system/?_gl=1%2A1nco86y%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTQ5MTA4NDUzMS4xNjg5Njk0NDEy%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4xLjAuMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4wLjAuMA..">interactive Polygon zkEVM app dashboard</a> has launched on the Blockchain Operating System (BOS). This integration will not only increase accessibility and discoverability for zkEVM developers and users on the open web but also vastly improve user experience. </p>



<p>The collaboration is set to accelerate the creation of dApps that will onboard billions of users into the open web. The new <a href="https://bos.quickswap.exchange/">Polygon zkEVM dashboard </a>now combines the benefits of zero-knowledge technology with the power of the BOS to unlock <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jVu4Hc1CLao">even more seamless onboarding</a> to the open web. </p>



<p>The dashboard brings a new suite of zero knowledge development capabilities to zkEVM developers and lets them build apps that can reach more users from day one. It’s a groundbreaking partnership that brings together the NEAR and Polygon ecosystems, two of the most innovative names in Ethereum and blockchain scalability.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">NEAR makes waves with sustainability commitment</h2>



<p>NEAR Foundation made a significant stride in its commitment to Web3 sustainability. As part of its ongoing efforts, NEAR signed up to the Ethereum Climate Platform, demonstrating its resolve towards minimizing the environmental impact of Web3 development. This move aligns with NEAR’s ethos and commitment to sustainable and scalable blockchain solutions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Marieke storms the BOS-tille at “Funding the Commons”</h2>



<p>Adding to the list of notable NEAR occurrences during ETHCC, NEAR Foundation CEO, Marieke Flament, was a keynote speaker at the “Funding the Commons” event held at Sorbonne Université on July 15. Marike’s message was one of bringing more ethics and equity to the entire blockchain and Web3 ecosystem.</p>



<p>In her speech, titled &#8220;The Open Web is NEAR: How the BOS, NDC, and DAOs are creating a Decentralized Web,” Marieke explored how NEAR Foundation serves the ecosystem by building public goods like the BOS, DevHub, NDC, DAOs, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Funding the Commons” is an event designed to complement the Ethereum Community Conference, promoting connection amongst participants, and fostering new collaborations and projects. The event organizers also planned a dinner on July 15 at Le Procope Paris, where Marieke was among the most notable invited guests.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Unpacking Insights: notable talks and events at ETH CC</h2>



<p>Near @ ETHCC wasn&#8217;t just a gathering of blockchain enthusiasts, but a hotbed of innovative discussions. Illia Polosukhin, co-founder of NEAR, and Nadir Dabit&#8217;s conversation around decentralized social networks piqued particular interest. They hinted at a shift in how we&#8217;ll connect and share information in the future and the potential role of decentralized social on the BOS.</p>



<p>Matt Stephenson, head of crypto economics at crypto investment firm, Pantera Capital, took the audience on a thrilling Day Two journey through the intricacies of behavioral game theory. He showcased how game theory could be leveraged in this space, offering a unique lens to examine, understand, and potentially predict blockchain trends.</p>



<p>Near @ ETHCC didn&#8217;t skimp on forward-looking conversations either. A panel featuring Max Mersch of Fabric Ventures, Maggie Love from SheFi, and Bilal El Alamy of PyratzLabs posed a pertinent question: &#8220;What’s the Next Big Use Case Being Built in the Bear Market?&#8221; Each speaker provided valuable insight about both challenges and opportunities posed by bear markets.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ecosystem Updates</h2>



<p>Despite the focus on the Near @ ETHCC side event itself, the NEAR ecosystem saw significant developments and milestones during the past few days.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>The NEAR Digital Collective’s I-AM-HUMAN</strong> movement has crossed 2,000 members in the NEAR ecosystem. The initiative allows users to vote, elect candidates for office, and shape the future of NEAR. You can sign up <a href="https://i-am-human.app/?transactionHashes=Djm4ohdiWxNETWz3xZA8BUreQFbQm63rJh67SAHkMc48">here</a>.</li>



<li><strong>MintbaseSearch</strong> has gone live on NEAR mainnet along with its own ChatGPT plugin. Mintbase now enables users to ask anything about NFTs on the NEAR Protocol. More details <a href="https://twitter.com/mintbase/status/1679487855473872897?s">here</a>.</li>



<li><strong>Opolis</strong> has raised $6.6M in a bridge fundraising round with support from NEAR Foundation, Polygon Ventures, and Draper Capital. Read more details about the full announcement <a href="https://twitter.com/opolis/status/1679477404824137732?s">here</a>.</li>



<li><strong>Black Snow: Battle For Earth,</strong> launched its demo version, offering an exciting free-to-play-and-earn experience that aims to enhance the NEAR ecosystem by boosting user count and transactions. Check out the demo<a href="https://linktr.ee/battleforearth"> here</a></li>
</ul>



<p>C&#8217;est la vie in Paris as ETHCC 2023 wraps up. As we reflect on these dynamic days, it&#8217;s clear that the future of NEAR and the BOS is exciting and full of potential. From environmental commitments to bold collaborations and fascinating talks, NEAR’s Parisian journey was full of engagement, enlightenment, and enthusiasm for everyone involved.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-highlights-sustainability-and-the-bos-take-center-stage-in-paris/">NEAR at ETHCC Highlights: Sustainability and the BOS Take Center Stage in Paris</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR at ETHCC: Horizon Pitch Contest, BOS Workshops, and More</title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-ethcc-horizon-pitch-contest-bos-workshops-and-more/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 17:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As Day One at NEAR @ ETHCC concludes, there’s palpable growing excitement for what’s in store for tomorrow. Held at …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-horizon-pitch-contest-bos-workshops-and-more/">NEAR at ETHCC: Horizon Pitch Contest, BOS Workshops, and More</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As Day One at NEAR @ ETHCC concludes, there’s palpable growing excitement for what’s in store for tomorrow. Held at the beautiful Museum National D’Histoire Naturelle in Paris, the first day of workshops and sessions proved to be an exceptional success for Ethereum and BOS builders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Day Two is gearing up to take the experience to a whole new level, with a primary focus on founders and their ventures.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-morning-and-early-afternoon-sessions-fostering-innovation">Morning and Early Afternoon Sessions: Fostering Innovation</h2>



<p>Day Two will kick off with a casual networking opportunity over café au laits and pastries. It’ll be a great way to get warmed up and connect builders, innovators, and visionaries within the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<p>The first main event of the day will be a special workshop held&nbsp; by Matt Stephenson , Head of Cryptoeconomics at Pantera Capita, along with Pantera Principal, Ryan Barney. His insights on the opportunities and challenges within blockchain economics will deepen participants&#8217; understanding of the critical economic principles underpinning blockchain ecosystems.</p>



<p>As the morning sessions conclude, the afternoon will kick off by delving into the world of interoperability, onboarding, and value generation with Vik Pandey from NEAR Foundation. Vik has been actively involved in the development of the BOS, focusing on interoperability, open-source technologies, and blockchain success efforts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During his session, &#8220;Interoperability, Onboarding, and Value Generation with the BOS,&#8221; Vik will share insights from his work, highlighting the ways in which the BOS fosters innovation and impact in the Open Web.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-late-afternoon-highlights-regulatory-discussions-and-horizon-workshop">Late Afternoon Highlights: Regulatory Discussions and Horizon Workshop</h2>



<p>Next on the agenda is a panel of experts moderated by Mya Shofany, regulatory lead at NEAR Foundation. The discussion will delve into regulatory considerations in blockchain, and tackle some of the most critical issues facing Web3&nbsp; founders in the current regulatory landscape.</p>



<p>The panel will be followed by one of the day&#8217;s most anticipated events — the Horizon afternoon. This session will be a deep dive into the cutting-edge ideas poised to redefine the blockchain world, spearheaded by NEAR’s new Web3 accelerator arm.</p>



<p>As Day Two winds down, participants can enjoy relaxed networking during the Horizon Happy Hour. Here, NEAR and Ethereum enthusiasts can reflect on the day&#8217;s learnings, forge new connections, and unwind over drinks and appetizers.</p>



<p>If you would like to browse the official schedule, head to <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/near-ethcc-tickets-655229297467">near.org.ethcc&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>Throughout the two days of NEAR @ ETHCC, participants are not just learning about the Blockchain Operating System (BOS), they&#8217;re experiencing it firsthand. Day Two promises a packed schedule of learning, building, and networking opportunities.</p>



<p>For those who couldn&#8217;t join us on Day One, you can catch up on the sessions uploaded on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCuKdIYVN8iE3fv8alyk1aMw">NEAR Protocol YouTube channel</a>. Prepare for Day Two by soaking up the insights shared by our experts.</p>



<p>Stay connected with us for more updates and insights from NEAR @ ETHCC as we continue to explore the limitless possibilities of the Blockchain Operating System (BOS).</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-horizon-pitch-contest-bos-workshops-and-more/">NEAR at ETHCC: Horizon Pitch Contest, BOS Workshops, and More</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation Partners with Hibiki Run on Open Web Digital Gachapon </title>
		<link>/blog/near-foundation-partners-with-hibiki-run-on-open-web-digital-gachapon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3 Gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is thrilled to announce a new strategic partnership with Hibiki Run, a platform lying at the nexus of …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-partners-with-hibiki-run-on-open-web-digital-gachapon/">NEAR Foundation Partners with Hibiki Run on Open Web Digital Gachapon </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation is thrilled to announce a new strategic partnership with Hibiki Run, a platform lying at the nexus of innovation in music streaming and digital collectibles. Hibiki Run is revolutionizing music discovery by melding gaming thrills with crypto-driven Listen-to-Earn&nbsp; (L2E) incentives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Together, NEAR Foundation and Hibiki Run will explore innovative paths for creating engagement between Web3 content creators and end users. With the Japanese “Gachapon” vending machine capsule toys as a model, the collaboration will meld NEAR’s cutting-edge blockchain technology with Hibiki Run’s expertise in digital music, art, and exercise, new opportunities in each vertical for creation, distribution, and ownership.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-bringing-a-digital-gachapon-economy-to-the-open-web">Bringing a ‘Digital Gachapon’ economy to the open web</h2>



<p>With “Digital Gachapon”, NEAR and Hibiki Run will bring a powerful economic tool to creators. When interacting with a Japanese Gachapon, layers insert coins into the machine, turn the knob, and receive a capsule with a random item.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hibiki Run has innovatively digitized this exciting concept, integrating it with blockchain technology. In the digital Gachapon system, users utilize their tokens to receive digital items such as NFTs or unique digital assets — anything from exclusive music tracks, collectible art pieces, and rare gaming items, to access tokens for specific events or experiences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The digital Gachapon&#8217;s strength lies in its element of surprise and the potential for rare, high-value rewards — transforming the token expenditure into an exciting event while providing a way for creators to distribute their content in a fun and engaging manner.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hibiki Run and NEAR hope that with these types of innovative concepts, blockchain technology, and user-friendly interfaces, a new frontier of digital arts will open up. One that is interactive and immersive for creators and consumers alike. Like NEAR, Hibiki Run is committed to creating a decentralized, fair, and accessible ecosystem for artists.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-partners-with-hibiki-run-on-open-web-digital-gachapon/">NEAR Foundation Partners with Hibiki Run on Open Web Digital Gachapon </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation PR Roundup for June</title>
		<link>/blog/near-foundation-pr-roundup-for-june/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Press]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As June comes to a close, summer in the NEAR ecosystem is heating up with a wave of new announcements, …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-pr-roundup-for-june/">NEAR Foundation PR Roundup for June</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As June comes to a close, summer in the NEAR ecosystem is heating up with a wave of new announcements, events, media appearances, and more. Not to mention a few notable celebrities bringing some star power into NEAR’s orbit. Here’s a rundown of all the newsworthy NEAR happenings over the past month.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sammy-hagar-and-guy-fieri-jump-into-nfts-on-near">Sammy Hagar and Guy Fieri jump into NFTs on NEAR</h2>



<p>In the US, Grammy-winning musician Sammy Hagar and celebrity chef Guy Fieri joined the NEAR ecosystem, teaming up with NEAR on-ramp Trident3 to launch an NFT loyalty program. The Santo Spirits Club loyalty program, as reported by <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/web3/2023/06/13/guy-fieri-and-sammy-hagar-launch-web3-tequila-loyalty-program/">Coindesk</a> and <a href="https://decrypt.co/144378/guy-fieri-sammy-hagar-tequila-brand-launches-nft-loyalty-program">Decrypt</a>, will enable tequila fans to earn on-chain tiered perks and an opportunity to win a virtual tasting with the duo.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-mirae-asset-marblex-and-vortex-boost-south-korea">Mirae Asset, MARBLEX, and Vortex boost South Korea</h2>



<p>&nbsp;Over in Asia, NEAR Foundation continued to make inroads in South Korea. Mirae Asset, a subsidiary of Asia’s largest financial group, announced a partnership to research Web3’s role in global business. Per&nbsp; <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/press-releases/2023-06-09/near-foundation-mirae-asset-paving-the-way-for-the-future-of-web3-finance">Bloomberg</a>, Mirae Asset will collaborate with NEAR Foundation to strengthen the Web2/3 business network and identify opportunities for real-world blockchain value creation.</p>



<p>Meanwhile,  <a href="https://blockchainreporter.net/marblex-collaborates-with-near-foundation-to-revolutionize-the-web3-gaming-sector/">Blockchain Reporter</a> broke that Marblex – a Korean blockchain infrastructure provider for high-quality gaming – will integrate NEAR protocol with Marblex’s gaming universe, enhancing user convenience and Web3 adoption. NEAR will integrate with MARBLEX’s WARP Bridge, taking advantage of NEAR’s high scalability and speed to improve the gaming experience in Web3. The partnership will also enable joint marketing initiatives and events, boosting awareness of the global blockchain gaming market. </p>



<p>Then there’s Vortex Gaming, a Web3 subsidiary of Inven, the largest game media community in Korea. Coverage by <a href="https://europeangaming.eu/portal/latest-news/2023/06/27/138269/near-protocol-completes-gaming-ecosystem-by-onboarding-vortex-gaming/">European Gaming</a> reported that Vortex will leverage NEAR protocol to integrate a&nbsp; gaming community encompassing Web2 and Web3 by building innovative infrastructure for gaming developers. The NEAR Foundation and Inven will also collaborate on marketing and business development, adding to NEAR’s exciting Web3 gaming ecosystem.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-skoda-launches-metaverse-for-auto-fans-in-india">Skoda launches metaverse for auto fans in India</h2>



<p>Czech Automobile Manufacturer Skoda entered the Metaverse in the world’s most populous country, giving users an opportunity to explore, collect and own digital art pieces on NEAR. The platform, as reported by <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/czech-automobile-conglomerate-skoda-auto-launches-nft-platform">Cointelegraph</a> and <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/en-in/news-and-trends/skoda-auto-enters-the-nft-race-with-skodaverse-india/454673">Entrepreneur India</a>, will enable NFT owners to access exclusive perks and rewards, while allowing owners to trade digital artwork in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sailgp-christens-the-dock-for-decentralized-fandom">SailGP christens The Dock for decentralized fandom</h2>



<p>In more partnership news, the Global racing league SailGP and Oracle announced the launch of “The Dock”, a decentralized fan engagement platform powered by Oracle and NEAR’s ongoing partnership to bridge the worlds of Web2 and Web3. As reported by <a href="https://www.sailweb.co.uk/2023/06/13/sailgp-and-oracle-roll-out-the-dock-loyalty-program/">SailWeb</a>, The Dock will revolutionize how fans follow SailGP, increasing engagement through exclusive content and enabling fans to earn points, redeemable for exciting rewards including VIP access to SailGP events and more.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-alibaba-cloud-and-women-in-web3-headline-collision">Alibaba Cloud and Women in Web3 headline Collision</h2>



<p>The NEAR ecosystem took over Toronto this month, showcasing the best of BOS at Collision 2023,&nbsp; one of the world’s biggest tech conferences.&nbsp; During the event, the NEAR Foundation announced a groundbreaking partnership with Alibaba, enabling developers across Asia to launch new NEAR validators with Alibaba Cloud’s infrastructure as a service.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The partnership was covered in myriad outlets such as <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/business/2023/06/26/embargo-26th-june-7am-bst-near-foundation-partners-with-alibaba-cloud-to-accelerate-web3-growth/">Coindesk</a>, <a href="https://journalducoin.com/actualites/near-alibaba-cloud-faciliter-developpement-applications-decentralisees/">Journal du Coin</a>, and <a href="https://www.btc-echo.de/schlagzeilen/near-foundation-und-alibaba-cloud-gehen-partnerschaft-ein-166623/">BTC Echo</a>. Partnering with Alibaba means the NEAR ecosystem will have access to Remote Procedure Calls (RPC) and enable users to interact with NEAR’s Blockchain Operating System while using Alibaba Cloud’s infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The NEAR Foundation also released the Women in Web3 Changemakers List 2023, celebrating the achievements of extraordinary women throughout the Web3 ecosystem. As reported by <a href="https://techfundingnews.com/breaking-the-mold-these-women-in-web3-changemakers-2023-forge-a-path-of-inclusion-and-innovation/?utm_content=cmp-true">Tech Funding News</a>, the ten women were selected by the public and hail from all corners of the globe, following hundreds of nominations from the Web3 community.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-leadership-viewpoints-on-media-and-social-fairness">Leadership viewpoints on media and social fairness</h2>



<p>Illia Polosukhin, Founder of NEAR and CEO of Pagoda, took the time to write a thought leadership piece in <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blockchain-media-governance-immutable">Blockworks</a> about crypto’s potential to transform how we interact with the media. Illia sets out the emerging problem with the status quo: bad actors are beginning to utilize generative AI to dramatically scale up misinformation campaigns.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, Illia explains that blockchain-based “sign-and-trace” systems can enable the public to reliably source and validate real news stories, with a legitimate trail of sources available online.</p>



<p>CEO of NEAR Foundation Marieke Flament also penned an article for London’s leading daily business paper <a href="https://www.cityam.com/city-am-web3-building-a-fair-open-and-inclusive-digital-world/">CityAM</a> about using Web3 to build a fair and inclusive digital world.  “Too often technology has only benefited the few: those who have money, those who have power, or those of a certain gender, ethnicity, or skin color.</p>



<p>But this doesn’t need to be the case,” she explained. “Technology can and should be in the service of all people. But to achieve this, we will need a change in perspective, something that Web3 can help us achieve.”</p>



<p>Marieke also talked about blockchain, Web3, and BOS on a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_lXz1gd9ErI">podcast hosted by the editor Journal du Coin</a> &#8211; France’s leading crypto media outlet, and for a video interview with <a href="https://ffnews.com/fintech-tv/event/event-videos-2023/paris-fintech-forum-leaders-summit-2023/marieke-flament-near-foundation-paris-fintech-forum/">Fintech Finance</a> at the Paris Fintech Forum.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s all for this month. If we missed anything or want to share anything for next month’s roundup, get in touch!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-pr-roundup-for-june/">NEAR Foundation PR Roundup for June</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Škoda Ventures into NFTs with NEAR to Create the Škodaverse India</title>
		<link>/blog/skoda-ventures-into-nfts-with-near-to-create-the-skodaverse-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3 Gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20652</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Škoda India, in collaboration with NEAR Protocol, announces its foray into the world of NFTs and blockchain technology with Škodaverse …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/skoda-ventures-into-nfts-with-near-to-create-the-skodaverse-india/">Škoda Ventures into NFTs with NEAR to Create the Škodaverse India</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.skoda-auto.co.in/">Škoda India</a>, in collaboration with NEAR Protocol, announces its foray into the world of NFTs and blockchain technology with Škodaverse India. This new platform forms a part of the global Škodaverse initiative and will bring<strong> </strong>a fresh wave of digital innovation to Škoda automobile fans in India.</p>



<p>Škoda, one of Europe’s biggest car manufacturers headquartered in the Czech Republic, is quickly becoming one of the most forward-thinking industry brands in Web3 and the metaverse. Late last year, the company announced its <a href="https://www.ledgerinsights.com/skoda-enters-metaverse-skodaverse/">global Škodaverse initiative</a>, integrating virtual test drives and NFTs into an immersive environment.</p>



<p>And now the Škodaverse is coming to the Indian market, powered by the NEAR Protocol, that will enable Škoda fans to buy, trade, and engage with NFTs in Web3. It’s a crucial step in the brand&#8217;s journey towards building a tight-knit community of Škoda loyalists, offering a space for fans to connect, co-create, and establish long-term relationships with the brand.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-steering-skoda-fans-towards-nfts-with-near"><strong>Steering Škoda fans towards NFTs with NEAR</strong></h2>



<p>Mr. Christian Cahn von Seelen – Executive Director of Sales, Marketing, and Digital, Škoda at Auto Volkswagen India – expressed excitement at the unveiling of the Škodaverse India NFT platform. He envisions it as a dynamic hub for connection and creativity, exemplifying Škoda’s commitment to its customers and fans in India. The Škodaverse India will offer unique and immersive experiences to a rapidly growing market.</p>



<p>“Škodaverse India signifies the brand&#8217;s leap into uncharted digital territory,” said von Seelen. It’s not just about creating extraordinary digital assets, it’s about forging deep connections with a community that shares an unwavering passion for the brand and its initiatives in India. It also showcases our commitment to sustainability and innovation, through leveraging carbon-neutral blockchain technology that enables secure, transparent, and decentralized transactions.”</p>



<p>Škodaverse India is designing its metaverse platform to be exciting and engaging for Škoda enthusiasts of all demographics, whether they&#8217;re familiar with blockchain technology or not. Whether it’s an image, video, sound, or ticket, each NFT collection released on the Škodaverse India platform will be curated to create memorable driving experiences</p>



<p>The first NFT collection, honoring sustainability, will be created on NEAR Protocol. As a South Pole-certified, carbon-neutral blockchain, NEAR’s eco-first philosophy aligns seamlessly with Škoda India’s sustainability efforts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-driving-skoda-india-s-web3-strategy-into-the-future"><strong>Driving Škoda India’s Web3 Strategy into the future</strong></h2>



<p>As part of the brand&#8217;s intensified Web3 strategy, Škoda Auto India is collaborating with Antier, a leading blockchain consulting firm, to foster the creation and minting of innovative NFTs. Each NFT collection released on the Škodaverse India platform will be thoughtfully curated to represent memorable driving experiences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These unique collectibles will unlock exclusive experiences, strengthening the bond between Škodaverse and its community of users. The Škodaverse India platform also ensures users stay updated with the latest in the creation and sale of NFTs. Users can sign in, create, and maintain their profiles, and monitor for updates via Škodaverse India’s Discord, Telegram, and Twitter.</p>



<p>With the launch of Škodaverse India, Škoda Auto India embraces blockchain technology, signaling a significant move towards Web3 applications. Powered by NEAR Protocol, Škodaverse India will offer engaging, community-building experiences, further solidifying Škoda&#8217;s position as a forward-thinking automobile brand in Web3 and the metaverse.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/skoda-ventures-into-nfts-with-near-to-create-the-skodaverse-india/">Škoda Ventures into NFTs with NEAR to Create the Škodaverse India</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation and MARBLEX to Expand Korea’s Web3 Gaming Industry with Aurora</title>
		<link>/blog/near-foundation-and-marblex-to-expand-koreas-web3-gaming-industry-with-warp-bridge/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 06:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aurora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3 Gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a new strategic partnership with MARBLEX, a blockchain subsidiary of Netmarble Corp, that will …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-and-marblex-to-expand-koreas-web3-gaming-industry-with-warp-bridge/">NEAR Foundation and MARBLEX to Expand Korea’s Web3 Gaming Industry with Aurora</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a new strategic partnership with MARBLEX, a blockchain subsidiary of Netmarble Corp, that will help expand Korea’s Web3 gaming industry. MARBLEX will build on Aurora, NEAR’s Ethereum-compatible layer, for maximum scalability and blockchain gaming accessibility to onboard more players to Web3.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Under the new partnership facilitated by the NEAR Korea Hub, NEAR Foundation and MARBLEX plan to achieve mutual growth by linking the NEAR blockchain and Aurora with WARP Bridge to enable interactive collaboration, promote global joint marketing events, and enhance brand awareness.&nbsp;</p>



<p></p>



<p>Through WARP Bridge, competitive and casual gamers alike will now be able to enjoy a variety of games and exclusive content through NEAR’s Blockchain Operating System (BOS). The BOS leverages the NEAR Protocol’s fast transaction speeds as well as effortless scalability and onboarding (via FastAuth) to make the onboarding experience as easy as possible for the masses.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-marblex-a-developer-and-publisher-of-mobile-games">MARBLEX: a developer and publisher of mobile games</h2>



<p>A Web3 gaming giant constantly pushing the boundaries of what&#8217;s possible, MARBLEX is a well-established developer and publisher of mobile games with more than 6,000 experts from across the globe. MARBLEX’s goal is to bring the highest quality Web3 games to market by providing key services such as a cryptocurrency wallet, decentralized exchange, token staking, and an NFT Marketplace.<br><br>“We expect NEAR’s core narrative to play a pivotal role in bolstering the overall MBX 3.0 ecosystem,” said Junki Moon, Business Division Director of MARBLEX added. “Through the collaborative integration of the NEAR Foundation’s extensive technical expertise with the content prowess of the MBX ecosystem, we will maintain our position as pioneers in the ever-evolving landscape of the global blockchain trends.”<br></p>



<p>Robbie Lim, GM of Business Development at NEAR Foundation, added: “This collaboration with MARBLEX will be an important milestone in promoting various use cases based on BOS (Blockchain Operating System). We will continuously advance the gaming ecosystem of NEAR Protocol as well as attract numerous users to enter the Web3 scene by onboarding high-quality MBX content.”</p>



<p>NEAR Korea Hub, which oversees business development in Korea and Asia, played a key role in this strategic partnership. The Hub also sees the partnership as breaking a barrier to Web3 entry for mobile gamers.&nbsp;</p>



<p></p>



<p>“NEAR Protocol provides a user experience similar to Web2 using Fast Auth account abstraction feature, greatly lowering the initial entry barrier to Web3,” said a spokesperson from NEAR Korea Hub. “We will continue to strongly partner with excellent domestic companies such as MARBLEX to implement a user-centered ecosystem where users can easily enjoy all services.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-and-marblex-to-expand-koreas-web3-gaming-industry-with-warp-bridge/">NEAR Foundation and MARBLEX to Expand Korea’s Web3 Gaming Industry with Aurora</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation Partners with Absolute Labs to Accelerate How Brands Connect with Customers in Web3</title>
		<link>/blog/near-foundation-partners-with-absolute-labs-to-accelerate-how-brands-connect-with-customers-in-web3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 13:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20444</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a new partnership with Absolute Labs, a company revolutionizing Web3’s marketing stack. Its “Wallet …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-partners-with-absolute-labs-to-accelerate-how-brands-connect-with-customers-in-web3/">NEAR Foundation Partners with Absolute Labs to Accelerate How Brands Connect with Customers in Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a new partnership with <a href="https://absolutelabs.io/">Absolute Labs</a>, a company revolutionizing Web3’s marketing stack. Its “Wallet Relationship Management™ platform can be used by Web2 brands and Web3 startups alike to acquire, convert and retain customers on the Open Web. </p>



<p>To help in this endeavor, the company <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/absolute-labs-announces-8-million-150000487.html">announced</a> an $8M seed round of funding at NFT NYC in the past week. Other funding partners include backers like Samsung Next, Aglae Ventures, Sparkle Ventures (Animoca Brands), The Luxury Fund and MoonPay. </p>



<p>”We are thrilled to have the NEAR Foundation as a partner in helping us to accelerate how marketing is done in the next Internet,” says Samir Addamine, Absolute Labs’ CEO and co-founder. “Both our organizations share a vision to accelerate the world’s transition to decentralized marketplaces and more open, transparent and valued user engagement, so it’s a great fit for us.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-is-wallet-relationship-management">What is Wallet Relationship Management</h2>



<p>Wallet Relationship Management (WRM™) starts with the premise that wallets hold the keys to everything Web3 — from proving identity, providing access to value-rich brand experiences, facilitating payments, creating “ownership” opportunities for customers, and much more. Combining on-chain data from wallets along with assets that Web2 brands can also inject from their Web2 systems, this platform supports all facets of the marketing funnel, from acquisition to conversion and retention of loyalty.</p>



<p>Users of the platform can gain deep insights into their customers and their on-chain preferences and behaviors, identify actionable segments to track and engage, and craft cross-chain and cross-channel (Web2 and Web3) campaigns to develop and nurture relationships</p>



<p>Absolute Labs customers can also use WRM to reactivate dormant wallet customers by using the WRM dashboard to distribute meaningful incentives such as rewards tokens, NFTs, and more. </p>



<p>To date, Absolute Labs has 40+ companies using their services. With WRM, these customers get an enterprise-grade suite of connectors and APIs to seamlessly integrate with their existing marketing tech stack. </p>



<p>Absolute Labs has an incredibly strong product and is a fantastic addition to the NEAR ecosystem. Their Wallet Relationship Management platform is a clear market leader in the burgeoning Web3 martech space, and is already an indispensable component of the modern marketing stack. By bringing Absolute Labs into the NEAR ecosystem, it creates a seamless Web3 on-ramp for brands  and will enable them to engage, retain, and reactivate customers like never before.</p>



<p>DISCLOSURE: <em>Any information shared in this announcement regarding our partnership with Absolute Labs should not be considered as a binding agreement or representation, and may be subject to change without notice. The information presented in this communication is for informational purposes only and should not be construed as investment advice. Any decisions made based on this information are solely the responsibility of the individual or entity making them.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-partners-with-absolute-labs-to-accelerate-how-brands-connect-with-customers-in-web3/">NEAR Foundation Partners with Absolute Labs to Accelerate How Brands Connect with Customers in Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation Backs Hydra Ventures to Create Web3’s First ‘Fund of Funds’ Investment DAO</title>
		<link>/blog/near-foundation-backs-hydra-ventures-to-create-web3s-first-fund-of-funds-investment-dao/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 18:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DAOs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20340</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce that it has joined Hydra Ventures, a “fund of funds” investment DAO. A first …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-backs-hydra-ventures-to-create-web3s-first-fund-of-funds-investment-dao/">NEAR Foundation Backs Hydra Ventures to Create Web3’s First ‘Fund of Funds’ Investment DAO</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce that it has joined <a href="https://twitter.com/HydraVentures_">Hydra Ventures</a>, a “fund of funds” investment DAO. A first in the Web3 space, Hydra Ventures is designed to help other investment DAOs get off the ground.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By partnering with NEAR Foundation, Hydra Ventures will open the doors to the eventual launch of the first investment DAO in the Near ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The combined expertise of the leaders that have created this fund offers a winning formula that will help provide critical funding to purpose-driven, socially impactful web3 startups,” said Marieke Flament, CEO of NEAR Foundation. “We are delighted to be playing a part in launching this DAO and look forward to seeing the role it will play in developing our ecosystem.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-decentralizing-web3-investment-with-daos">Decentralizing Web3 investment with DAOs</h2>



<p>To power the “fund of funds” investment DAO, Hydra Ventures has raised $10M in capital from NEAR Foundation, MetaCartel Ventures, ConsenSys, 1kx Ventures, Collab + Currency, Nonagon Ventures, CMT Digital, among others. Hydra Ventures aims to take a hands-on approach to support investment DAOs, from community coordination and investment practices to organizational design, incentive design, and back office/operations.<br></p>



<p>&#8220;While the first legally wrapped investment DAOs showed us what was possible, many of them have had major operating flaws which have been exposed over the years,” said Peter Pan, co-summoner of MetaCartel and Partner at 1kx Ventures. “Hydra looks to address many of these problems and ultimately emerge with a fundamentally better model for how investment DAOs should be operated. We are thrilled to have NEAR Foundation&#8217;s support in this venture.&#8221;<br><br>Hydra Ventures is incubated by <a href="https://twitter.com/thing3_xyz">Thing3</a> and <a href="https://metacartel.xyz/">MetaCartel Ventures</a> (the first and one of the most successful investment DAOs created), and backed by leading founders and thinkers in Web3. MetaCartel has incubated and made investments in several category-leading projects like Sky Mavis, Axie Infinity, Arweave, Open Zeppelin, DAOhaus, Zapper Finance, and Rarible, and were also one of the first investors in <a href="https://www.mintbase.xyz/">Mintbase</a>, an NFT marketplace built on Near. MetaCartel members include Ameen Soleimani (founder, Moloch DAO), Stani Kulechov (founder, AAVE), Roneil Rumburg (founder, Audius), Bobby Ong (founder, Coingecko), RAC (Grammy award winner), Peter Pan (Partner, 1kx Ventures), amongst others.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-backs-hydra-ventures-to-create-web3s-first-fund-of-funds-investment-dao/">NEAR Foundation Backs Hydra Ventures to Create Web3’s First ‘Fund of Funds’ Investment DAO</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
