<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Competition Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/competition/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/competition/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 17:04:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Competition Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/competition/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>NEAR FastAuth Competition Terms and Conditions</title>
		<link>/blog/near-fastauth-competition-terms-and-conditions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Competition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FastAuth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The following terms and conditions (the “Terms”) govern the use of the NEAR Foundation Fast Auth Competition (the “Competition”) provided …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-fastauth-competition-terms-and-conditions/">NEAR FastAuth Competition Terms and Conditions</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<ol>
<li>Introduction:</li>
</ol>



<p>The following terms and conditions (the “Terms”) govern the use of the NEAR Foundation Fast Auth Competition (the “Competition”) provided by NEAR Foundation (“we,” “us,” “our” or the “Company”). By participating in the Competition, you (“you” or “Participant”) agree to be bound by these Terms. If you do not agree to these Terms, you may not be eligible to participate in the Competition or receive any rewards. For more information on FastAuth, please visit the link <a href="https://wiki.near.org/overview/BOS/fast-auth">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<ol start="2">
<li>Eligibility:</li>
</ol>



<p>The Competition is available only to individuals who are at least 18 years old. By participating in the Competition, you represent and warrant that you are at least 18 years old.</p>



<ol start="3">
<li>Participation in the Competition:</li>
</ol>



<p>We are excited to provide NEAR users with the ability to win, you acknowledge and agree that any information you provide may be used by us in connection with the Competition. To participate, users must follow these steps:&nbsp;</p>



<ol>
<li>Participants must submit a video of their screen while opening a NEAR wallet using FastAuth. The video should be in the form of a screen recording. All videos must be legible and any sensitive information can be blacked out.&nbsp;</li>



<li>The Participant must submit the video to their personal Twitter account using the hashtags #FastAuthTimeTrial and #NEARistheBOS by June 9th, 13:00 UTC.</li>



<li>Videos submitted after the deadline will not be accepted.&nbsp;</li>



<li>The time taken to open the wallet, will be taken into consideration.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Winners will be notified via Twitter and announced on the Near social media channels on June 12th.</li>



<li>Competition Prize:</li>
</ol>



<p>Five Selected winners will be announced and contacted via email. The Competition prize consists of: 100 NEAR tokens for each winner.&nbsp;</p>



<p>5. Disclaimer:</p>



<p>The Prize is awarded &#8216;as is&#8217; and without warranty of any kind, express or implied, including without limitation any warranty of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose. The Competition organizers and affiliated companies make no representations or warranties regarding the prize or its use and are not responsible for any claims arising out of or in connection with the prize or its use. The Competition event and prizes are solely sponsored and organized by us, and any reference to third-party companies or organizations is for informational purposes only.&nbsp;</p>



<ol start="7">
<li>Limitation of Liability:</li>
</ol>



<p>The Competition organizers, sponsors, and affiliated companies are not responsible for any injury, loss, or damage to property or person, including death, arising out of participation in the Competition or use or misuse of the prize.</p>



<ol start="8">
<li>Intellectual Property:</li>
</ol>



<p>The Service, including all content provided by the expert(s) or other participants, is protected by copyright and other intellectual property laws. You may not reproduce, distribute, or create derivative works from any content provided by the Service without our prior written consent.</p>



<ol start="9">
<li>Modification of Terms:</li>
</ol>



<p>We reserve the right to modify these Terms at any time without notice. Your continued use of the Service following any changes to these Terms constitutes your acceptance of the revised Terms.</p>



<ol start="10">
<li>Governing Law:</li>
</ol>



<p>These Terms and your use of the Service are governed by the laws of Switzerland without regard to its conflict of laws provisions.</p>



<ol start="11">
<li>Dispute Resolution:</li>
</ol>



<p>Any disputes arising out of or in connection with these Terms or the Service will be resolved through binding arbitration in accordance with the rules of the Switzerland Arbitration Association.</p>



<ol start="12">
<li>Entire Agreement:</li>
</ol>



<p>These Terms constitute the entire agreement between you and us with respect to the Competition and supersede all prior or contemporaneous agreements and understandings, whether written or oral.</p>



<ol start="13">
<li>Contact Information:</li>
</ol>



<p>If you have any questions or comments about these Terms, please contact us at social@near.foundation.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-fastauth-competition-terms-and-conditions/">NEAR FastAuth Competition Terms and Conditions</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
