<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ICC Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/icc/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/icc/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 19:27:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>ICC Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/icc/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>ICC Launches ‘Captain&#8217;s Call’ Game on NEAR to Level Up Cricket Fandom During World Cup</title>
		<link>/blog/icc-launches-captains-call-game-on-near-to-level-up-cricket-fandom-during-world-cup/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Captain's Call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cricket World Cup 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cricket fans are getting a Web3-powered path to engaging with their favorite international sport. NEAR Foundation and the&#160; International Cricket …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/icc-launches-captains-call-game-on-near-to-level-up-cricket-fandom-during-world-cup/">ICC Launches ‘Captain&#8217;s Call’ Game on NEAR to Level Up Cricket Fandom During World Cup</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Cricket fans are getting a Web3-powered path to engaging with their favorite international sport. NEAR Foundation and the&nbsp; International Cricket Council (ICC), the global governing body of cricket, just teamed up&nbsp; to explore different ways of getting fans closer to their favorite teams and players.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This ICC and NEAR partnership arrives just as the cricket world is watching the Men’s Cricket World Cup 2023. The partnership’s first cricket fan experience, the <em>Captain’s Call</em> gaming app, taps into the NEAR Protocol’s infinite scalability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Watch an animated primer below on the gameplay in <em>Captain&#8217;s Call.</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-level-up-cricket-fandom-with-captain-s-call-game">Level up cricket fandom with <em>Captain’s Call</em> game</h2>



<p>In <em>Captain’s Call</em>, ICC’s first app on the NEAR blockchain, cricket fans compete against each other for the chance of winning prizes. Developed by Wincast, <em>Captain’s Call</em> allows fans to strategize around bowling, batting, and fielding actions during live cricket matches.</p>



<p>To play, fans simply navigate to the ICC’s mobile apps or website, click on the Match Centre for the game they intend to watch, and submit their predictions before the match begins. Players then compete for a chance to win prizes, merchandise, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-beyond-captain-s-call">Beyond <em>Captain’s Call</em></h2>



<p>With NEAR and ICC, Web3 and and sports are on a path of continual innovation. A fan passport is currently in early discussions, which would enable fans to record their actions and memories in a tamper proof way, both on and off chain. <em>Captain’s Call</em> will serve as a template in creating other games that fuses other Web2 and Web3 worlds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of these sporting innovations are possible thanks to the Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S). With its full stack of Web3 tools and easy onboarding, partners like the ICC and others can take advantage of the world’s most highly scalable, community-driven, and secure blockchains that deliver proven, best-in-class performance that can support any kind of Web3 strategy.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Heed the Captain&#039;s Call: Play ICC&#039;s New Game for the Cricket World Cup" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1WS7uJVoMwM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/icc-launches-captains-call-game-on-near-to-level-up-cricket-fandom-during-world-cup/">ICC Launches ‘Captain&#8217;s Call’ Game on NEAR to Level Up Cricket Fandom During World Cup</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>International Cricket Council and NEAR Foundation Sign Multiyear Partnership to Boost Global Fan Engagement Through Web3</title>
		<link>/blog/international-cricket-council-and-near-foundation-sign-multiyear-partnership-to-boost-global-fan-engagement-through-web3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICC World Cup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International Cricket Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20927</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The International Cricket Council (ICC) and the NEAR Foundation are entering into a groundbreaking new partnership that will utilize Web3 …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/international-cricket-council-and-near-foundation-sign-multiyear-partnership-to-boost-global-fan-engagement-through-web3/">International Cricket Council and NEAR Foundation Sign Multiyear Partnership to Boost Global Fan Engagement Through Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The <a href="https://www.icc-cricket.com/homepage">International Cricket Council</a> (ICC) and the NEAR Foundation are entering into a groundbreaking new partnership that will utilize Web3 tools built on the NEAR Blockchain to deepen engagement in the sport.</p>



<p>The NEAR Foundation will become the ICC’s official blockchain partner, helping cricket’s governing body create new ways for fans to get closer to their favorite teams and players using Web3 technology.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We are excited to embark on this partnership with NEAR Foundation and to use their technology and network of talent to create better and deeper fan engagement around the globe,” says Finn Bradshaw, Head of Digital at the ICC.</p>



<p>“We are looking forward to exploring ways in which we can use new technology to create lasting, valuable experiences for our fans.”</p>



<p>The partnership will launch its first collaboration as part of the <a href="https://www.cricketworldcup.com/">ICC Men’s Cricket World Cup</a>, starting on October 5 in India. Built on NEAR’s Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S), the ICC will release a pre-match strategy challenge that pits players against each other to pick the best team.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Each player can make choices across three key facets of the challenge: batting, bowling and fielding. Once a player has built their perfect strategy, as the ICC Men’s Cricket World Cup unfolds, their team will receive points based on the real life performance of the players they picked.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A leaderboard will track each fans’ performance and weekly winners will be awarded prizes including match tickets, exclusive events, Men’s Cricket World Cup merchandise, and more. This new type of engagement, built thanks to the B.O.S, helps to place fans at the center of the action, bringing them closer to the game than ever before.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-a-new-era-in-sports-engagement">A new era in sports engagement&nbsp;</h2>



<p>“We are extremely excited to be working with the ICC in this multi year deal. This is one of our biggest partnership announcements to date and solidifies our reputation as a go-to blockchain technology provider in the sporting world,” says Chris Donovan, CEO of the NEAR Foundation</p>



<p>“Given the immense size and popularity of cricket, the NEAR ecosystem will potentially be exposed to hundreds of millions of cricket fans who will have the opportunity to learn about NEAR Foundation’s mission of increasing the adoption of an open web,&nbsp; and get the chance to interact with Web3 use cases built on the Blockchain Operating System. We look forward to opportunities that this mutually beneficial agreement will bring to cricket fans and to playing a key role in using Web3 to make the world of sport more inclusive and exciting for everyone.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>After the Men’s Cricket World Cup, the partnership between the NEAR Foundation and the ICC will continue to the end of 2025. During that time, both sides have committed to work together to develop other Web3 use cases that help fans get closer to the sport.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Initial use cases include development of a fan passport that allows fans to record their actions and memories, in a tamper proof way across every touchpoint, both online and off.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>These innovations are all made possible thanks to the B.O.S. With its full stack of Web3 tools and easy onboarding, partners like the ICC can take advantage of the world’s most highly scalable, community-driven, and secure blockchains that deliver proven, best-in-class performance that can support any kind of Web3 strategy.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/international-cricket-council-and-near-foundation-sign-multiyear-partnership-to-boost-global-fan-engagement-through-web3/">International Cricket Council and NEAR Foundation Sign Multiyear Partnership to Boost Global Fan Engagement Through Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
