<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FastAuth SDK Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/fastauth-sdk/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/fastauth-sdk/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 18:17:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>FastAuth SDK Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/fastauth-sdk/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FastAuth SDK Beta Now Available</title>
		<link>/blog/fastauth-sdk-beta-now-available/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B.O.S]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FastAuth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FastAuth SDK]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20940</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Developers can now start integrating FastAuth into their dApps for a seamless, intuitive onboarding experience with the FastAuth SDK, now …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/fastauth-sdk-beta-now-available/">FastAuth SDK Beta Now Available</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>Developers can now start integrating FastAuth into their dApps for a seamless, intuitive onboarding experience with the FastAuth SDK, now in Beta.</em></p>



<p>Onboarding new users is one of the biggest hurdles for Web3 dApps. Creating a Web3 wallet is still a painful process for most users who are new to crypto, because it usually involves downloading an app or browser extension, purchasing cryptocurrency on an exchange, and understanding and saving a seed phrase. For these reasons, conversion rates for new user sign-ups tend to be very low in Web3 as compared to Web2.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-is-fastauth">What is FastAuth?</h2>



<p>FastAuth addresses this problem through a familiar, &#8220;Web2-like&#8221; onboarding flow: users can sign up with just an email, and they don&#8217;t need to save a seed phrase or password. Instead, their FastAuth account and keys are secured using &#8220;Passkeys,&#8221; a new technology that replaces passwords with biometrics such as fingerprints or FaceID linked to a device.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Users can also recover access to their account at any time by using their email through the &#8220;MPC recovery&#8221; service. Developers can also choose to subsidize gas costs for a certain smart contract so that users can start interacting with their dApp immediately, without having to fund their own account.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-who-can-apply-for-the-fastauth-sdk-beta">Who can apply for the FastAuth SDK Beta?</h2>



<p>FastAuth is currently in a closed Beta. Any developer and/or founder building NEAR apps transacting on NEAR can apply for access to the SDK. The goal of this Beta is to collect feedback from founders and developers to help inform our roadmap and upcoming releases (see more on these below).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Pagoda will request feedback from participants in the Beta, as they start building with FastAuth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-do-i-learn-more-and-get-started">How do I learn more and get started?</h2>



<p>You can try FastAuth for yourself by creating a new account on <a href="https://near.org/signup">near.org</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can also <a href="https://forms.gle/pyuW3fXPZwPffYju6">apply</a> to be part of the beta, and check out the <a href="https://docs.near.org/tools/fastauth-sdk">SDK documentation</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What&#8217;s coming next?</h2>



<p>Pagoda is planning to release some additional key features later this year, including the ability to &#8220;white-label&#8221; the sign-up and sign-in flows, as well as multi-chain support.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/fastauth-sdk-beta-now-available/">FastAuth SDK Beta Now Available</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
