<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Developer tools Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/developer-tools/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/developer-tools/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:31:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Developer tools Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/developer-tools/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Vistara Lands in the NEAR Ecosystem for Seamless Base Layer Roll-up Deployment</title>
		<link>/blog/vistara-lands-in-the-near-ecosystem-for-seamless-base-layer-roll-up-deployment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20704</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR is welcoming Vistara, the groundbreaking rollup deployment framework, into the fold. Vistara is set to seamlessly integrate with the …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/vistara-lands-in-the-near-ecosystem-for-seamless-base-layer-roll-up-deployment/">Vistara Lands in the NEAR Ecosystem for Seamless Base Layer Roll-up Deployment</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR is welcoming <a href="https://twitter.com/vistaralabs">Vistara</a>, the groundbreaking rollup deployment framework, into the fold. Vistara is set to seamlessly integrate with the BOS for the end-to-end, multi-chain deployment of rollups. This alliance will accelerate the pace of blockchain innovation, making rollup deployment faster, more efficient, and accessible across multiple chains for all developers.</p>



<p>Vistara stands out as a game-changing one-click <a href="https://docs.vistara.dev/">rollup deployment framework</a> that simplifies creating application-specific rollups across multiple blockchains. Streamlining the intricate rollup deployment process into a straightforward, single-click operation, Vistara will build a front-end on the BOS to make user-friendly, multi-chain rollup deployment a reality.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-simplifying-multi-chain-roll-ups-with-vistara-on-the-bos">Simplifying multi-chain roll-ups with Vistara on the BOS&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Existing frameworks such as Cosmos SDK and Substrate have sought to streamline certain software components in decentralized applications but often leave developers tied to one ecosystem that they must completely understand and master. Vistara will now present a unique solution by combining the BOS with backend chains like Ethereum and Celestia.</p>



<p>Vistara’s emphasis on simplifying rollup component creation aligns with NEAR&#8217;s vision of user-centric decentralization and a serverless Web3. With this new BOS front-end integration, developers in the NEAR ecosystem and beyond can now build and deploy rollups in one convenient location.</p>



<p>The result will be a user-friendly design that makes the deployment of a rollup as simple as selecting an option from a dropdown menu. The integration will also encourage a wider range of developers to build with rollups on the BOS with any chain, leading to a more diverse pool of innovations and robust growth.</p>



<p>Vistara’s integration not only simplifies the process but also expands the scope for innovation. It demystifies rollup creation, making it accessible to a broader range of developers. This inclusivity fuels a more diverse pool of applications, fostering growth and vibrancy within the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-vistara-and-bos-breaking-base-layer-building-barriers">Vistara and BOS breaking base layer building barriers</h2>



<p>Developing decentralized applications on base layers can be a complex process. Coordination of node operators, high costs, and extended development times are among the major challenges. However, Vistara is designed to confront these issues directly, streamlining the process and fostering efficiency.</p>



<p>Rollups — technologies that bundle or &#8216;roll up&#8217; side-chain transactions into a single transaction — provide an effective solution. They help developers bypass the difficulties associated with building decentralized networks. Vistara leverages this rollup technology, pushing the NEAR ecosystem towards application-specific rollups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The solution effectively untangles the complexities tied to base layer dependencies, forging a development environment on the BOS that stretches beyond traditional base layer confines. With Vistara, multi-chain developers can now bring their applications to life more swiftly and efficiently than ever before.</p>



<p>To sum up, Vistara&#8217;s user-friendly, multi-chain rollup deployment capabilities on the BOS will have a huge impact on the NEAR ecosystem and beyond. The integration will take much of the complexity out of rollup deployment for anyone, helping Web3 creators, builders, and developers bring their applications to life faster than ever.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/vistara-lands-in-the-near-ecosystem-for-seamless-base-layer-roll-up-deployment/">Vistara Lands in the NEAR Ecosystem for Seamless Base Layer Roll-up Deployment</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Releases JavaScript SDK, Bringing Web3 to 20 Million Developers</title>
		<link>/blog/near-releases-javascript-sdk-bringing-web3-to-20-million-developers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 23:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JavaScript]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://neardev.nmcgn.de/?p=17905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Blockchain development has just become a whole lot easier for Web2 developers. NEAR is thrilled to unveil its much anticipated …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-releases-javascript-sdk-bringing-web3-to-20-million-developers/">NEAR Releases JavaScript SDK, Bringing Web3 to 20 Million Developers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Blockchain development has just become a whole lot easier for Web2 developers. NEAR is thrilled to unveil its much anticipated JavaScript Software Development Kit (JS SDK) at ETHToronto, the official hackathon of the Blockchain Futurist Conference, in a significant move to democratize Web3 development.</p>



<p>With NEAR’s JS SDK, more than 20 million developers that make JavaScript the world’s most popular coding language can finally join the internet revolution and quickly build fast, scalable, and user-friendly decentralized applications. Having that many more contributors in the space could bring about a fascinating renaissance to the open web.</p>



<p>Although Rust and Solidity are the most prominent programming languages for Layer 1 blockchains, there are fewer than 2.5 million developers worldwide who use these languages. So, opening up the doors nearly 10x is a major step towards mass adoption. JS runs in every browser, the basics can be taught in an afternoon, it requires no compiler setup, and it comes pre-loaded with useful libraries like RegExp, Math, and Array. The NEAR JS SDK brings this same capability and ease of use to developing smart contracts, unlocking the power of blockchain to a much, much wider audience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Commenting on the launch, Illia Polosukhin, Founder of NEAR, says: “Developers can spend less time learning a new language and more time building their application in a language they already know. Millions of developers already know how to program in JavaScript; enabling this group to build novel applications on NEAR is a critical step in achieving our vision of a billion users interacting with NEAR.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-learn-build-and-deploy-in-minutes">Learn, build, and deploy in minutes</h2>



<p>NEAR’s commitment to putting simplicity and usability first is reinforced by this release, making the learning curve for blockchain far less steep than it has ever been. Javascript developers can now set up their first dApp in the same amount of time it takes to spin up a React app.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/near/near-sdk-js">JS SDK</a>&nbsp;release has everything you need to dive right into blockchain development including the contract framework itself, JavaScript and TypeScript contract examples, and example tests. It is implemented in TypeScript, which offers developers implicit, strict, and structural typing, along with type annotations built into your favorite IDE.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Developers can get started building their first JavaScript decentralized application by following this&nbsp;<a href="https://docs.near.org/develop/quickstart-guide">quick start guide</a><em>&nbsp;</em>or heading to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.pagoda.co/jssdk?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_campaign=js-sdk">Pagoda’s landing page</a>&nbsp;to learn more.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-a-closer-look-at-the-js-sdk">A Closer Look at the JS SDK</h2>



<p>The JS SDK provides each contract its own instance of a JS engine running inside it. This design allows developers to write contracts in pure JavaScript or TypeScript, and access all the same features, like oracles, available to Rust contracts. </p>



<p class="has-text-dark-color has-text-color">To get started, run <code><mark style="background-color:#d1d1d1" class="has-inline-color has-text-dark-02-color">npx create-near-app</mark></code>  in your terminal and select JavaScript for your smart contract. Once everything is installed you can test, compile, and deploy your newly created project with ease.</p>



<p>For a more detailed look at the contract structure and other configurations check out this<a href="https://docs.near.org/develop/quickstart-guide">&nbsp;dApp QuickStart Guide</a><em>&nbsp;</em>on NEAR’s Official Documentation site.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>About Pagoda</em></p>



<p>The JS SDK is developed by Pagoda, the engineering team that builds and maintains NEAR Protocol and some of the most important tools needed for decentralized application (dApp) development. Developers can use the Pagoda suite of tools to build, deploy, test, and interact with smart contracts on NEAR. For more information on the JS SDK, visit&nbsp;<a href="https://www.pagoda.co/jssdk?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_campaign=js-sdk">Pagoda</a>&nbsp;or join the&nbsp;<a href="http://near.chat/">NEAR Discord</a>&nbsp;and checkout the&nbsp;<em>#engineering</em>&nbsp;channels where resources like&nbsp;<a href="/office-hours">live support</a>&nbsp;are available every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-releases-javascript-sdk-bringing-web3-to-20-million-developers/">NEAR Releases JavaScript SDK, Bringing Web3 to 20 Million Developers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR partners with Ceramic on cross-chain identity and dynamic data storage</title>
		<link>/blog/near-partners-with-ceramic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 15:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=10861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Partnership with Ceramic brings streaming data and cross-chain identity protocols to NEAR developers. Developers building on NEAR Protocol now have …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-partners-with-ceramic/">NEAR partners with Ceramic on cross-chain identity and dynamic data storage</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Partnership with Ceramic brings streaming data and cross-chain identity protocols to</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em> NEAR</em> </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">developers.</span></i></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Developers building on </span><a href="https://docs.near.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR Protocol</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> now have a powerful way to manage user identities and dynamic off-chain data in their applications. </span><a href="https://ceramic.network/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ceramic</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the decentralized network for data stream processing, now supports NEAR wallets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR is currently hosting an Open Web Community <a href="https://createbase.community/hackathon/">Hackathon</a> with a prize for integrating IDX profiles on Ceramic with a NEAR Sputnik DAO. To participate, check out the </span><a href="https://gov.nearpages.wpengine.com/t/2391"><span style="font-weight: 400;">hackathon prize</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">!</span></p>
<h2><b>Blockchain, Data, &amp; Identity: a full stack for Web3 developers</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR offers developers the most dev-friendly and end-user accessible infrastructure for building decentralized apps and services. Great Web3 and DeFi apps require more than a smart contract platform. They also need sophisticated, scalable, and dependable data management infrastructure for app builders using smart contracts. Ceramic provides advanced database-like features such as mutability, version control, access control, and programmable logic. It is also the foundation for </span><a href="http://idx.xyz/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">IDX</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Web3&#8217;s first cross-chain identity model.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the integration of Ceramic on NEAR Protocol, developers on NEAR can: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Build data-rich user experiences and social features on fully decentralized tech</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Give users cloud-like backup, sync, and recovery without running a centralized server</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Publish content on the open web without the need to anchor IPFS hashes on-chain</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leverage interoperable profiles, social graphs and reputations across the Web3 ecosystem</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Ceramic now supports NEAR wallets</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Starting today, developers building applications on NEAR can easily add support for Ceramic and IDX in their application with a seamless user experience. NEAR key pairs have been added as a supported signing and </span><a href="https://developers.ceramic.network/reference/javascript/blockchain/#currently-supported-blockchains"><span style="font-weight: 400;">authentication method</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for Ceramic&#8217;s data streams, so users can now perform transactions on Ceramic with their existing NEAR wallets. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Developers have already started combining NEAR and Ceramic to create new applications such as NEAR Personas, which </span><a href="https://vitalpoint.ai/near-digital-identity/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">links</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a NEAR wallet to a DID.</span></p>
<p><iframe title="NEAR Personas - Decentralized Identity Tutorial" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v2GzFFmuWDM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h2><b>About Ceramic: Decentralized data streams</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ceramic provides developers with database-like functionality for storing all kinds of dynamic, mutable content. This finally gives developers a Web3 native way to add critical features like rich identities (profiles, reputation, social graphs), user-generated content (posts, interactions), dynamic application-data, and much more.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://developers.ceramic.network/learn/overview/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ceramic&#8217;s unique stream-based architecture</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is designed to handle any type of data model at web-scale volume and latency. Built on top of open standards including IPFS, libp2p, and DIDs and compatible with any raw storage protocol like Filecoin or Arweave, all information stored on Ceramic exists within a permissionless cross-chain network that lets developers tap into an ever growing library of identities and data while using their preferred stack.</span></p>
<h2><b>IDX: Cross-chain identity and user-centric data</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Identity is the first use case enabled by Ceramic&#8217;s building blocks for open source information. </span><a href="http://idx.xyz/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">IDX (identity index)</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a cross-chain identity protocol that inherits Ceramic’s properties to provide developers with a user-centric replacement for server-siloed user tables. By making it easy to structure and associate data to a user&#8217;s personal index, IDX lets applications save, discover, and route to users&#8217; data.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The IDX SDK makes it simple to manage users and deliver great data-driven experiences using the same NEAR keys and wallets as developers and users are already relying on. Users can also link multiple keys, from any wallet and multiple blockchains, to the same identity. This is essential to developers who want to serve users over time, as it enables key rotation, data interoperability across accounts, and rich cross-chain profiles, reputations and experiences.</span></p>
<h2><b>Getting started with Ceramic on NEAR</b></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR is currently hosting an Open Web Community </span><a href="https://createbase.community/hackathon"><span style="font-weight: 400;">hackathon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">! There is a prize for integrating IDX profiles on Ceramic with theSputnik DAO platform, built on NEAR. For more information, head to the </span><a href="https://gov.nearpages.wpengine.com/t/2391"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR Forum</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
<li aria-level="1">To install NEAR, start with our <a href="https://docs.near.org/">documentation</a>.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To add IDX to your project, follow this </span><a href="https://developers.idx.xyz/build/installation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">installation guide</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To use Ceramic for streams without IDX, follow this </span><a href="https://developers.ceramic.network/build/installation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">installation guide</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regardless of which option you choose, you should also select 3ID Connect as your DID wallet during the </span><a href="https://developers.ceramic.network/build/authentication/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">authentication</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> process which handles the integration with NEAR wallets.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For questions or support, join the </span><a href="https://chat.ceramic.network/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ceramic Discord</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and the </span><a href="https://near.chat/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR Discord</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-partners-with-ceramic/">NEAR partners with Ceramic on cross-chain identity and dynamic data storage</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
