<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ETH Denver Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/eth-denver/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/eth-denver/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 18:19:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.orghttps://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>ETH Denver Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/eth-denver/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>NEAR at ETHDenver: Get Chain-Abstracted with the Black Dragon</title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-ethdenver-get-chain-abstracted-with-the-black-dragon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Morrison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 18:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETH Denver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ditch the ETHDenver small talk and brace yourself abstractooors! The NEAR Ecosystem is crashing the scene, armed with next-level chain …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethdenver-get-chain-abstracted-with-the-black-dragon/">NEAR at ETHDenver: Get Chain-Abstracted with the Black Dragon</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Ditch the ETHDenver small talk and brace yourself abstractooors! The NEAR Ecosystem is crashing the scene, armed with next-level chain abstraction, mind-bending AI, and enough developer swag to make your node blush.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-but-first-the-tea"><strong>But First, the Tea:</strong></h2>



<p>Heard whispers of a <a href="https://forms.gle/vXxBFcCmnAj1XdhA9">Chain Abstraction Tea Party</a> hosted by the elusive Black Dragon? It&#8217;s not just rumors. Mingle with the brightest minds in the NEARverse at our booth (number 314, remember it!).<br></p>



<p>To celebrate the psychedelic &#8220;Alice in Wonderland&#8221; theme of ETHDenver, we&#8217;ve conjured up a magical animation that serves as your gateway to Chain Abstraction. Scan the code, embrace the future, and <a href="https://shard.dog/chainabstraction">claim your own NFT powered by ShardDog</a>.<br></p>



<p>Dive down rabbit holes of chain abstraction, data that never forgets, and transactions faster than a Denver blizzard. The Black Dragon&#8217;s got your back, guiding you through the mind-bending potential of Web3.</p>



<p><br>Follow the trail and join us for an exclusive event (space is limited, <a href="https://forms.gle/vXxBFcCmnAj1XdhA9">RSVP ASAP</a>) where the real secrets of Web3&#8217;s future get spilled. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ditch-the-fomo-see-what-s-near"><strong>Ditch the FOMO, See What&#8217;s NEAR:</strong></h2>



<p></p>



<p>From on-chain rewards, airdrops, and more, powered by NEAR Ecosystem projects to hackathon bounties. <a href="https://ethdenver2024.devfolio.co/">The NEAR team is ready to onboard you and answer your burning questions</a>.<br><br>Hacking not your jam? Don’t worry, there’s more!<br><br>Mark your calendars for February 26th, because the <a href="https://lu.ma/fvoeazk8">Decentralized AGI Summit</a> is where AI and Web3 collide, igniting thought-provoking discussions on decentralized systems. This isn&#8217;t just another tech event; it&#8217;s an interactive experience where you&#8217;ll witness the explosive synergy between these two cutting-edge fields. Be part of building the future!<br><br>Then on February 28th, we’re bringing you hot fire —get it? because we’re dragons, hah— by partnering with Agoric and Frontier Research for <a href="https://lu.ma/ChADay">Chain Abstraction Day</a>, an exclusive apply-to-attend event featuring the most hardcore builders and researchers in the space. Prepare to witness the future of interoperability, where users hop seamlessly between chains without a second thought (or a gas fee headache).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Space is limited, and only the most curious minds need apply. So if you&#8217;re a developer dreaming of cross-chain dApps, a creator with an NFT vision spanning universes, or an entrepreneur ready to conquer the multiverse, submit your request to attend ASAP. Don&#8217;t miss your chance to rub shoulders with the brightest minds in the biz and unlock the true power of blockchain, unchained.<br><br>For a comprehensive overview of NEAR&#8217;s presence at ETHDenver, including speaker sessions and networking opportunities, visit our dedicated NEAR at <a href="/ethdenver2024/">ETHDenver landing page</a>.</p>



<p></p>



<p>See you on the other side, chain <em>abstractooors</em>!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethdenver-get-chain-abstracted-with-the-black-dragon/">NEAR at ETHDenver: Get Chain-Abstracted with the Black Dragon</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
