<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Developers Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/category/developers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/category/developers/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 16:58:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Developers Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/category/developers/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Unlocking Web3 Usability with Account Aggregation</title>
		<link>/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Illia Polosukhin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Account Aggregation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Since the start, the focus for the NEAR ecosystem has been on advancing Chain Abstraction, or hiding the elements of …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation/">Unlocking Web3 Usability with Account Aggregation</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since the start, the focus for the NEAR ecosystem has been on advancing <a href="/blog/why-chain-abstraction-is-the-next-frontier-for-web3/">Chain Abstraction</a>, or hiding the elements of the blockchain (“abstracting away”) from users so they are not barriers to entry or participation in the decentralized Web. In Web3, the data and assets belong to the user, tied to their on-chain, noncustodial account. Currently every user has separate (usually many) accounts on each blockchain and also needs separate wallet software to manage those accounts. This requires users to manage the security for each account and wallet individually, deal with complex recovery processes if they make a mistake, and go through a thorny series of manual steps to move any assets into their wallets or across different wallets and chains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The current world, where every wallet is managing accounts on many chains, is untenable as each account slowly falls out of sync with the others. In order to provide a consistent, abstracted experience for users across all chains, we need to aggregate accounts across all chains within a single interface––account abstraction alone is not enough. Enter Account Aggregation.</p>



<p>Account Aggregation––the ability to transact on any blockchain through a single account and interface––is a critical pillar of advancing Chain Abstraction, defragmenting Web3 for app users and increasing their ability to move across networks or between applications with ease. Developers should not be building apps on single chains anymore in order to reach some specific market or pool of liquidity. Now dApps can truly become decentralized applications, yet still feel like the unified experience of using an app.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To enable an effective user experience for using all blockchains, without users needing to think about underlying infrastructure or switch networks, it’s important to have a single account from which they can navigate all of Web3. This means no manual bridging, no managing long lists of addresses on different networks, no gas tokens, and no more switching between wallets and networks. In the true spirit of Web3, this single account should be non-custodial and non-dependent on a specific wallet software or any other single service provider.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/_GsCWKS9_mqc-HYLf-kOPRH3R561qw7Y_a8y5jijWHHDzbktn3QYl2KLFd7HuCqWegaL9rpEHuPXVddEhXh4luFR7kwFcIU_OxaComsMZME0pbZcP3oKq7MZPDD-OjjezCaIGwG1wDSN0kEynQPLwg8" alt="" style="width:1050px;height:auto"/></figure>



<p>NEAR is enabling such an experience for all Web3 users with Account Aggregation, which consists of 3 core technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>NEAR Account</strong>: account abstraction for smooth onboarding and recovery of accounts.</li>



<li><strong>Chain Signatures</strong>: enabling NEAR network to have MPC nodes that are jointly signing transactions and messages.</li>



<li><strong>Intent Relayers</strong>: parties in the ecosystem that are able to execute the intent of the user on different chains.</li>
</ul>



<p>By adding Chain Signatures and Intent Relayers to the already robust NEAR account model, NEAR can become the home for multichain apps that abstract the pain points of switching networks and managing gas fees, bridging, and long lists of accounts away from end users.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This post details the 3 technical pillars of Account Aggregation and how they combine to deliver the next generation of usability for any decentralized application. Chain Signatures and Intent Relayers will be available on NEAR testnet by early March 2024.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-account">NEAR Account</h2>



<p>Account aggregation on NEAR begins with the innovative NEAR <a href="https://docs.near.org/concepts/basics/accounts/model">account model</a>. Incorporating native account abstraction since launch, NEAR’s account model offers a high degree of flexibility to developers and users alike. Ethereum introduced its version of account abstraction, EIP-4337, in March 2023.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Native account abstraction means that a given NEAR account maps to a human-readable account name instead of a public key hash, so accounts can have a large number of keys with different permissions for different functions. This means that NEAR account security is both stronger and easier to manage for users, while also allowing much broader functionality within a single account.<br></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="634" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-1024x634.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21236" style="width:1102px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-1024x634.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-300x186.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-768x475.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-1536x951.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-2048x1267.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://docs.near.org/tools/fastauth-sdk">FastAuth</a>, the industry-leading account creation experience NEAR launched in 2023, offers a Web2-like onboarding flow: users can sign up with just an email, and they don’t need to save a seed phrase or password. Instead, their FastAuth account and keys are secured using “Passkeys,” a new technology that replaces passwords with biometrics such as fingerprints or FaceID linked to a device. Users can also recover access to their account at any time by using their email through the MPC recovery service.</p>



<p>Now, with added multichain functionality on the horizon, the power of the NEAR account can extend across all of Web3 and offer easier onboarding and security management to users of any decentralized application. By having passkey integration, revocation, and recovery in one place rather than scattered across every chain, users will have a significantly streamlined experience for managing their Web3 accounts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-chain-signatures">Chain Signatures</h2>



<p>Chain signatures allow any NEAR account to have associated “remote” addresses on other chains and to sign transactions and messages from those addresses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Traditionally a user would have different private keys in different wallet providers to facilitate multichain interactions and would need to manage them manually. With Chain Signatures, the NEAR MPC network is the signer for these remote addresses, meaning there is no explicit private key.</p>



<p>MPC (multi-party computation) signing allows a number of independent nodes to sign a message with key shares separately generated by non-trusting parties without needing to assemble them anywhere. The challenge with the standard MPC signing approach is that if nodes are changed, a new public key needs to be generated. The introduction of a novel threshold signature protocol which has a procedure of key resharing allows the MPC signer to maintain the same aggregate public key even as key shares and nodes constantly change.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/rkoKA7u9NfTNCcGfc755qGg15lO539HM7CsFtf1Wg5HstDF_iTgVtg_9BlDx_Ta7BoJAsleLxdNzUwzeNKRBm4Z09DQlTMLW8FxuMoE3kd_wDvlh3qQTD1XkC3Tw4XDHidWDTJNqbo0KWyvXaI3iPNA" alt="" style="width:938px;height:auto"/></figure>



<p>Chain Signatures is the NEAR approach to make this model programmable. Making MPC signer nodes that are also nodes in the NEAR network allows for a smart contract call to instantiate a signature procedure for a given account. By using different derivations constructed from a chain ID, a NEAR account ID, and a provided path, each account receives an infinite number of remote addresses on every chain.&nbsp;<br></p>



<p>This amplifies the power and flexibility of NEAR accounts by allowing them to operate on any chain. Any NEAR smart contract can sign transactions and messages targeted for other chains––introducing another novel account programming primitive and extending the NEAR account model across all of Web3.</p>



<p>The MPC signer network will start as a subset of validators and partners of NEAR. Over time it is expected to be added to all NEAR validators on the protocol level to continue increasing the security of the system.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-intent-relayers">Intent Relayers</h2>



<p>We can’t expect app users to pay gas fees in various native tokens across different chains. We also should not require users to explicitly swap tokens on the destination chain in order to pay there. To achieve a smooth user experience, it should be easy for users to pay on the NEAR network and then be able to transact value on other chains, i.e. to relay their <em>intent</em> from NEAR to another chain.</p>



<p>With intent, a user can state what they want to achieve and leave out how it should be done. Users should be able to specify any action they want to take without having to navigate or understand the intricate complexities of multiple transactions on multiple chains they will be executed on, nor the swaps and funding required to achieve that action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although Chain Signatures is a generic technology that can be used in many ways for the first iteration of Account Aggregation, the relayer smart contract will control the remote account for users. This means that instead of the user’s account mapping to an address, the <em>relayer.near</em> will have a derivation for each user, allowing this smart contract to initiate signing and offer other services (like trading derivations).</p>



<p>Let’s look at an example of how the first iteration of intent relayer will abstract away cross-chain gas and payments for a NEAR user:&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>User has a root.near account that maps to the remote Ethereum address 0xabc via the relayer’s smart contract.</li>



<li>User initiates a transaction to buy a BAYC NFT on OpenSea using their NEAR account and pays in $NEAR by doing a transaction on the NEAR network to relayer smart contract with Ethereum transaction payload in arguments and attaching the required $NEAR amount.</li>



<li>The relayer smart contract will then forward the transaction bundle to the NEAR MPC signature contract. This bundle consists of (1) the transaction to fund the user’s 0xabc with $ETH required for gas and NFT payment and (2) user’s transaction to buy the BAYC NFT on OpenSea.</li>



<li>The Chain Signature contract will sign both transactions using different derivations respective to the relayer contract and originating user.</li>



<li>The relayer operator will observe the response from MPC service with signed transactions and submit them to the Ethereum network. This starts with initiating a fund transfer from a treasury paymaster account on Ethereum. This paymaster account will transfer ETH to the user’s 0xabc Ethereum address, equivalent to the NEAR that was originally sent by the user.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Then the relayer will submit the final transaction and the BAYC NFT will be purchased from the user&#8217;s 0xabc address using ETH to cover gas and payment.</li>
</ul>



<p>The above example showcases how an intent relayer reduces complexity for a user to complete a cross-chain transaction. This is an <em>intent</em>-based architecture, and this is only a brief initial example of what will be possible in the future to provide a seamless user experience and abstract blockchains for users.</p>



<p>The intent relayers approach allows users to pay with any assets they own, not just $NEAR, opening up wallet and application developers to offer a variety of options: using application tokens for paying for multichain transactions, offering a subscription model by charging a flat fee, or offering extra discounts to incentivize specific behaviors.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-use-cases">Use Cases</h2>



<p>One account for using apps on all chains unlocks a range of previously difficult use cases for founders and developers. Here are some examples for founders and developers to consider as the possibilities for excellent multichain user experiences expand with Account Aggregation.</p>



<p><strong>Expanding user base for existing applications.</strong> Currently applications are only targeting the user base of the single chain they have launched on. With Account Aggregation, users can log into applications from every chain as an alternative wallet option. Application developers will simply need to add “Connect with NEAR” to their wallet selector.</p>



<p>Wallet developers can also leverage NEAR’s decentralized and composable interfaces together with Account Aggregation to surface applications across all chains directly within their wallet experience.</p>



<p><strong>Bridgeless DeFi</strong>. The first example is bridgeless, cross-chain DeFi where a NEAR account can be a gateway to multiple chains through a unified app experience. This is especially useful for apps like <a href="https://dapdap.tech/">DapDap</a>, built on NEAR, which lets users discover DeFi apps and experiences from a range of L2s and start using them within a single interface.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Multichain DEX.</strong> One of the most desired but also complex-to-build use cases is a decentralized exchange (DEX) that works across most if not all chains. Currently users must default to centralized exchanges for such a multichain experience due to the complexity of bridging, gas, and handling separate wallets. With Account Aggregation, DEX smart contracts can live on NEAR while having deposit addresses across all chains. This means there is no need to bridge assets to a single chain to swap or for the user to bridge to the chain where assets have liquidity. Instead they can easily swap $BTC on the Bitcoin network for $OP on Optimism using such a NEAR smart contract.</p>



<p><strong>Bridging Assets.</strong> Although the Account Aggregation approach really focuses on using canonical assets on where they are issued, sometimes there is value in having wrapped assets. For example, in cases like Bitcoin or Ethereum where the canonical assets are too expensive and slow to move, wrapping becomes quite useful. To build a specific token bridge using Account Aggregation is just to make a NEAR smart contract that keeps an account of deposits of a given token and issues that respective token balance.</p>



<p><strong>Trading multichain asset bundles. </strong>Beyond simple trading, Account Aggregation allows users to make a NEAR account into a bundle of multichain assets. NEAR accounts themselves are tradeable (see <a href="https://namesky.app/">NEAR account marketplace NameSky</a>), which also allows the trading of everything that is deposited to such an account across all chains. For example, say the account <em>xyz.near</em> has 2 BTC, some BRC-20, a BAYC NFT on Ethereum, and some veCRV. By trading this entire account, there is no need to move each of the underlying assets on the other chains.&nbsp; Instead, the new owner comes into possession of the whole bundle when the keys are rotated to them on the account.<br></p>



<p>There is also an interesting potential approach to implement a multichain exchange of assets via a smart contract that internally maintains a mapping from an owner account to a given path derivation (which is what determines remote addresses on other chains). One can trade the derivation paths inside this smart contract, trading everything deposited on a remote account without trading the entire account. For example:</p>



<ul>
<li>Smart contract <em>dex.near </em>internally maintains:&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>derivation=/0/0/1 → root.near</li>



<li>derivation=/0/0/2 → alice.near which maps to 0xabc on Ethereum</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>alice.near can sell root.near the derivation inside this smart contract for some amount on NEAR and now it will be inside dex.near. Then root.near can request to draw Ethereum assets from it later.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>derivation=/0/0/1 → root.near</li>



<li>derivation=/0/0/2 → root.near</li>
</ul>



<p>This approach means users can trade assets across all chains at the speed (1s block time) and cost (below $0.01) of using NEAR.</p>



<p><strong>Delegated Smart Contract Permissions on NEAR.</strong> Another use case for Chain Signatures is the ability for a NEAR smart contract to execute something on behalf of other users––for example, to recover keys for an app user.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s say there is a <em>social_recovery.near</em> contract that keeps track of a mapping of friends for a given account root.near. This root.near account at some point added a public key that the social_recovery.near account can sign via Chain Signatures. Friends can initiate a recovery flow, where they send a new public key given to them by the user to social_recovery.near. If enough friends do this, the social_recovery.near requests to sign a NEAR transaction that adds a new key on behalf of its own remote key with signer root.near. When executed, this transaction adds a new key to root.near, allowing the user to recover their account via a social recovery process they can set up in case they need it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Similarly, smart contracts can execute rebalancing of pools on behalf of the user based on some condition and any other logic that the user decides to “install” on their account by adding a remote key from that account.</p>



<p><strong>DeFi on Bitcoin (and other non-smart contract chains). </strong>Using chain signatures, smart contracts on NEAR can control externally-owned accounts on non-smart contract chains like Bitcoin, Dogecoin, Ripple, Bittensor, Cosmos Hub, etc. This enables developers to use NEAR as a smart contract “layer” for chains that do not support this functionality natively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, a developer can build a decentralized exchange for Bitcoin Ordinals, using a smart contract on NEAR to manage deposits (into Bitcoin addresses controlled by the contract) and to verify and execute swaps when two users agree to trade BTC for an Ordinal or BRC20 token.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-coming-soon-to-near-testnet">Coming Soon to NEAR Testnet</h3>



<p>Excited to build with Account Aggregation? Keep an eye on NEAR’s <a href="https://docs.near.org/">docs</a>: Chain Signatures and Intent Relayers are expected to be available on testnet by March 1, 2024. And join members of the NEAR ecosystem at the <a href="https://lu.ma/ChADay">Chain Abstraction Summit</a>, co-sponsored by NEAR Foundation during ETHDenver, to learn more about Account Aggregation and exciting innovations from all the projects contributing to Chain Abstraction.</p>



<p><em>–Illia Polosukhin, David Millar-Durrant, Gautham Ravi, Dio Ortega, Mally Anderson</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation/">Unlocking Web3 Usability with Account Aggregation</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</title>
		<link>/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI is NEAR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hackathon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with Edge and Polygon Labs, the NEAR Foundation will co-sponsor a Decentralized AI Summit and “Autonomous Agent,” an …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/">Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In collaboration with Edge and Polygon Labs, the NEAR Foundation will co-sponsor a Decentralized AI <a href="https://lu.ma/fvoeazk8">Summit</a> and “Autonomous Agent,” an AI x Web3 <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/autonomous-agent-hackathon">Hackathon</a>, at ETHDenver on February 26 and 27. The events will bring together visionaries, developers, and enthusiasts working at the intersection of AI and Web3 along with a hackathon for builders and researchers to dive into the buzziest tech topic of today. Speakers at the Summit will include Vitalik Buterin of the Ethereum Foundation, Illia Polosukhin of NEAR Foundation, Sandeep Nailwal of Polygon Labs, and Sreeram Kannan of EigenLayer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Autonomous Agent” is the first event in the &#8220;{Chain}-of-Thought&#8221; series from <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/">Edge</a>, which will explore and harness the potential of Web3 and open source AI. Edge is a research and development organization dedicated to democratizing access to open intelligence and advancing the evolution of next-generation web architecture. Hackers can expect hands-on hacking sessions, workshops, and mentorship opportunities with a chance to learn from those at the cutting edge of decentralized AI development. </p>



<p>The intersection of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Web3 technology is poised to revolutionize industries, with many Web3 projects now incorporating AI into decentralized applications and developer tools. Ethereum Co-Founder Vitalik Buterin recently shared his <a href="https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2024/01/30/cryptoai.html">observations</a> about the intersection, and NEAR Co-Founder Illia Polosukhin shared how AI fits into the vision for the NEAR ecosystem in a recent <a href="/blog/self-sovereignty-is-near-a-vision-for-our-ecosystem/">post</a>. </p>



<p>As the risks from centralized AI controlled primarily by major corporations become more apparent, investing in open source, transparent AI development will become increasingly important––along with community building, governance experiments, and advocacy. “{Chain} of Thought” will lead the way in bringing members of the AI and Web3 ecosystems together to advance these initiatives and make concrete progress.</p>



<p>In addition to the premier sponsors, the “Autonomous Agent” hackathon is co-sponsored by <a href="https://www.eigenlayer.xyz/">EigenLayer</a>, <a href="https://www.gensyn.ai/">Gensyn</a>, and <a href="https://www.hyperoracle.io/">Hyper Oracle</a>, with co-hosting participation from Sentient, Lightspeed, and Symbolic Capital. Benefits of participation include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Cutting-Edge Workshops:</strong> Engage with industry experts and thought leaders through immersive workshops exploring the latest trends and technologies in AI x Web3.</li>



<li><strong>Hackathon Challenges:</strong> Tackle real-world challenges and showcase your creativity by developing innovative solutions at the forefront of AI and Web3 integration.</li>



<li><strong>Networking Opportunities:</strong> Connect with like-minded individuals, potential collaborators, and industry professionals to expand your network and exchange ideas.</li>



<li><strong>Prizes and Recognition:</strong> Compete for exciting prizes and gain recognition for your contributions to the advancement of AI x Web3 technology.</li>
</ul>



<p>Join NEAR Foundation, Polygon Labs, and Edge in Denver and be a part of the next great tech revolution. Those interested in attending the Decentralized AI Summit can register <a href="https://lu.ma/fvoeazk8">here</a>. Researchers, developers, and hackers interested in participating in the <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/autonomous-agent-hackathon">hackathon</a> can apply <a href="https://lu.ma/k6dw9jk2">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/">Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why NEAR Data Availability?</title>
		<link>/blog/why-near-data-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 16:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Abstraction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum Rollups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Modularity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Data Availability Layer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Protocol is built to onboard 1B+ users to Web3. Since its mainnet launch in October 2020, NEAR Protocol has …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/why-near-data-availability/">Why NEAR Data Availability?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Protocol is built to onboard 1B+ users to Web3. Since its mainnet launch in October 2020, NEAR Protocol has achieved 100% uptime with 4 shards and has onboarded 35M accounts, of which 16M are monthly active accounts.</p>



<p>Supporting the most users of any network in Web3 requires a scalable blockchain that is capable of having both high data availability and low-cost data posting in order for applications to scale to the level of mainstream global adoption. This post will explain NEAR’s technical approach to data availability and how <a href="http://near.org/da">NEAR DA</a>, a solution designed for Ethereum rollups, will scale the modular ecosystem and defragment all of Web3.</p>



<p>The modular Ethereum ecosystem seeks to scale the network by separating the functions of a blockchain––settlement, execution, and data availability––into separate layers. The Ethereum layer-one simply could not scale to accommodate the level of demand it reached, particularly during bull markets, without prohibitively high transaction fees. This demand becomes even more problematic when users want to do swaps on Ethereum or post transaction data for layer-twos to the layer-one network.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEAR DA offers a solution to this scalability roadblock. With a simple architecture that is easy to implement and constantly improving efficiency, and thanks to NEAR having the cheapest transaction fees of any network in Web3, NEAR DA is an incredibly fast and cost-effective data availability option. Depending on the gas fees, NEAR DA is up to 85,000x cheaper than posting blob submissions on Ethereum and 30x cheaper than doing the same on Celestia.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/Vw1qZ6OUS85XzYhXKYqIS3uHxSQ14GrzJDd4kh8eJRjFuggXqaYKAx_zWxgLsGWEMEEqUb6WjXu6lmQe0Hhkgm49HRz-OnQi_aMSZkxvAUuJ6XM4534EQ7x5bR1c8rAeaMjx14bnBC1Sv47T1LyngJw" alt=""/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-da-and-the-chain-abstraction-vision">NEAR DA and the Chain Abstraction Vision</h3>



<p>The NEAR ecosystem’s focus for 2024 is expanding <a href="/blog/why-chain-abstraction-is-the-next-frontier-for-web3">chain abstraction</a> across more chains &amp; ecosystems, with the goal of abstracting the blockchain away from the user &amp; developer experience. While the modular Ethereum ecosystem has made Ethereum more scalable in some ways, it’s also resulted in a lot of incompatible infrastructure and fractured liquidity that places a huge burden on app builders and end users to manage. The chain abstraction vision is that apps should just work with all chains, onboarding should be seamless, and things like gas fees and bridging should become invisible to end users.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Data availability and NEAR DA play an important role in chain abstraction. As zero-knowledge technology enables unification of security across chains via state proofs, as described in the chain abstraction deep dive post linked above, settlement data will be easier to fetch from different networks. As dapps become truly multichain thanks to account aggregation and decentralized frontends, they can query data from multiple chains more easily when data is all posted in one place. Doing so on NEAR will be much cheaper for rollups.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-is-near-da-implemented">How is NEAR DA Implemented?</h3>



<p>NEAR DA leverages an important part of NEAR’s consensus mechanism, known as Nightshade, which parallelizes the network into multiple shards (essentially, multiple parallel blockchains). Each shard on NEAR produces a small portion of a block, which is called a chunk. These chunks are aggregated to produce blocks. All of this happens entirely at the protocol level and so is invisible to users and developers.</p>



<p>NEAR DA uses this infrastructure to an ETH rollup’s benefit. When a chunk producer processes a receipt, there is consensus around the receipt. However, once the chunk has been processed and included in the block, the receipt is no longer required for consensus and can be pruned from the blockchain’s state. The pruning time is at least 3 NEAR epochs, where each epoch is 12 hours. In practice, this is usually around 5 NEAR epochs, so data is available in the network for around 60 hours. Once the receipt is pruned, it is the responsibility of archival nodes to retain the transaction data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This means that NEAR doesn’t slow down its consensus with more data than it requires, yet any user of NEAR DA would have ample time to query transaction data. The advantage this architecture provides to rollups is cost-effective data availability, especially to those with high transaction volume, such as gaming chains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEAR DA provides an out-of-the-box solution for developers, making it easy for rollup builders to make the most of NEAR’s infrastructure––which has 3+ years of proven reliability behind it. The Pagoda engineering team has already built three important components that are open-source and ready to be integrated into any OP Stack, Polygon CDK, or Arbitrum Nitro rollups:</p>



<ul>
<li>The Blob Store Contract: A contract that stores arbitrary data.</li>



<li>Light Client: A trustless off-chain client that provides easy access to transaction and receipt data.</li>



<li>RPC Client: A client to publish data blobs to the NEAR Protocol.</li>
</ul>



<p>Rollup builders looking to work with a cloud-like service could also leverage NEAR DA’s rollup-as-a-service (RaaS) providers (list provided <a href="https://near.org/data-availability">here</a>), in order to utilize these three components all in one place in a more abstracted manner.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-s-next-the-future-of-near-da-and-data-availability-sharding">What’s next? The Future of NEAR DA and Data Availability Sharding</h3>



<p>Another advantage NEAR’s sharding approach offers to users of NEAR DA is the future scaling roadmap. The NEAR Protocol Engineering team recently announced the move towards stateless validation, the next phase of sharding. This will further decrease the hardware requirements of certain types of validators (chunk validators) and move the state into memory, which will allow for more shards and increase the decentralization in the system by lowering the requirements to become a validator in the system. </p>



<p>This means that the number of shards will increase, greatly increasing the overall throughput of the NEAR Protocol. While NEAR is already fast, with 4 MB/s per shard with 4 shards, scaling towards <em>n</em> shards means that rollups, applications, and any other project or developer using NEAR will not have to compete for blockspace. This is a major contrast to the scaling limits of both monolithic systems as well as the modular ETH ecosystem and offers a substantial future-proof for anyone building on NEAR, including users of NEAR DA.</p>



<p>As the NEAR Protocol starts increasing the number of shards to n, the amount of data that has to be stored for a single shard decreases. Eventually, in theory every account on NEAR Protocol could potentially become its own shard. This allows running very light RPC nodes that would only track the shard that a given user is interested in. </p>



<p>For L2s that use NEAR DA, this would mean running an in-memory RPC client that would only track the shard that your data blob contract is in for your retention period (for fraud proofs), or for a given interval of time (retention is configurable on the RPC nodes). Instead of relying on data availability sampling (DAS), a rollup can rely on its own shard by running a lightweight RPC through Data Availability with Sharding. The additional benefit here is that the RPC is also applying the chunks they are tracking, essentially acting as a validator without participating in the consensus, as opposed to statistical confidence with DAS. </p>



<p>While Data Availability Sharding remains in the research phase of development, it shows the major advantages the NEAR Protocol design offers to many kinds of builders and ecosystems. As the Web3 space pursues mainstream adoption, the scalability hurdles of the first ten years of Ethereum will seem minor, and it is not clear that modularity alone will solve the problem. The NEAR ecosystem’s goal of mainstream adoption of Web3 means the network is available for all builders to use for creating great applications and delivering the next generation of the internet.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-fast-cost-effective-da-is-near">Fast, Cost-Effective DA is NEAR</h3>



<p>As Web3 adoption grows and as the number of rollups continues to climb, the need to scale the modular scalability solutions becomes greater. NEAR offers its innovative, reliable technology as a data availability solution for rollups that can save time and money while future-proofing projects for an increasingly multichain (and cross-chain) future. The bleeding-edge research driving the future development of NEAR DA will provide rollups with even more advantages over time. Interconnecting and defragmenting Web3 via chain abstraction will be a major theme of 2024 and utilizing NEAR DA puts rollups at the forefront of this evolution.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/why-near-data-availability/">Why NEAR Data Availability?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR DA Integrates with Polygon CDK for Developers Building Ethereum ZK Rollups </title>
		<link>/blog/near-da-integrates-with-polygon-cdk-for-developers-building-ethereum-zk-rollups/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 15:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21162</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The NEAR Foundation and Polygon Labs announced today that the latest technical integration for NEAR DA’s efficient and highly scalable …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-da-integrates-with-polygon-cdk-for-developers-building-ethereum-zk-rollups/">NEAR DA Integrates with Polygon CDK for Developers Building Ethereum ZK Rollups </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The NEAR Foundation and Polygon Labs announced today that the latest technical integration for NEAR DA’s efficient and highly scalable data availability is now available for <a href="https://polygon.technology/polygon-cdk">Polygon CDK</a>, the tech stack that allows developers to launch their own ZK-powered Layer 2s custom-fitted to their needs.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://near.org/data-availability">NEAR Data Availability layer</a> (NEAR DA) is a highly efficient and robust data availability layer, designed to help Ethereum rollup builders simplify their network and lower costs, while ensuring they can scale like the NEAR Protocol. Polygon CDK is a simple-to-build L2 stack and a scaling solution for Ethereum that lets developers build custom L2 chains with their own configurations. Builders can enjoy customisable features (transaction costs, native token, throughput), while still enjoying familiar EVM-compatibility and trustless security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With the latest NEAR DA integration, rollups can benefit from cheaper data availability costs to significantly reduce their overall rollup overheads. This is especially relevant considering <a href="https://dune.com/niftytable/rollup-economics">data publishing costs are at all-time highs</a> for L2s.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-da-paves-the-way-for-modular-blockchain-development">NEAR DA paves the way for modular blockchain development</h2>



<p>This integration empowers rollup builders on Polygon CDK to use NEAR DA as a complete, out-of-the-box modular DA solution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We’re excited to make NEAR DA available to Polygon CDK rollup builders and share the benefits of cost-effective, lightning-fast data availability that scales with NEAR’s sharding for the modular Ethereum ecosystem,” said Illia Polosukhin, Co-Founder of NEAR Protocol. “This is another exciting collaboration between NEAR Foundation and Polygon Labs to drive Chain Abstraction and create better experiences for developers and users.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/da-comparison-1024x576.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21165" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/da-comparison-1024x576.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/da-comparison-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/da-comparison-768x432.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/da-comparison-1536x864.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/da-comparison.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">As of December 2023, 231 kB of calldata on <a href="https://nearblocks.io/txns/HCA1dMLjYE9bTMNUpTG4sbcwhC9X1tXRtpUSxUEhjhLm">NEAR costs $0.0016</a>, while the same calldata on<a href="https://etherscan.io/tx/0x53a0d93d88e0dc050ca86ab45b26c952a79aa0116825a9e3a5276a36fa897bbe"> Ethereum L1 costs users $140.54</a>  and on <a href="https://celestia.explorers.guru/transaction/BFF52A4E7A2B523657710F36A4A917669973E3E2B8425AB21C65299BD6A90A0E">Celestia costs users $0.046</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p></p>



<p>NEAR DA helps developers reduce costs and enhance their rollup’s reliability, while maintaining the security guarantees provided by Ethereum. Another upside to NEAR DA is that high quality projects launching an app-chain or L2 will be able to get out-of-the-box NEAR DA compatibility and support.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Develop ZK L2s within the Polygon CDK ecosystem enabled by NEAR DA</h2>



<p>The NEAR-Polygon CDK integration allows developers building their own rollups to be part of the Polygon ecosystem, a network of blockchains which includes Polygon PoS, Polygon zkEVM and Polygon CDK-enabled blockchains. This is the first NEAR DA integration with a ZK-based L2 stack, increasing optionality for developers looking for scalable DA solutions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This integration also builds upon the NEAR-Polygon <a href="https://polygon.technology/blog/polygon-labs-and-near-foundation-collaborate-to-build-a-zkwasm-prover-as-a-component-for-polygon-cdk">research collaboration</a> to build zkWASM, a new type of prover for WASM blockchains. In the future, builders could even create zkWASM chains built on NEAR DA. Together, NEAR DA and zkWASM technology will play significant roles in scaling EVM and Wasm ecosystems in parallel while maximizing interoperability for a multi-chain future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Interested teams who want to work with NEAR DA are invited to fill out <a href="https://forms.gle/LWJoTpTiCbSheUL26">this form</a>, with information about your project and how you would like to integrate with NEAR DA.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-da-integrates-with-polygon-cdk-for-developers-building-ethereum-zk-rollups/">NEAR DA Integrates with Polygon CDK for Developers Building Ethereum ZK Rollups </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Q4 Protocol Roadmap Update</title>
		<link>/blog/near-q4-protocol-roadmap-update/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 19:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Core protocol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nightshade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Protocol Roadmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sharding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR: 2023 saw major experience improvements via meta transactions and zero-balance accounts, as well as node performance improvements and optimizations. Preparations are underway for a major upgrade to stateless validation, completing Phase 2 of the sharding roadmap in early 2024.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-q4-protocol-roadmap-update/">NEAR Q4 Protocol Roadmap Update</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><br><em>By Bowen Wang, Director of Protocol</em> <br><br>In this post, the NEAR Protocol work group would like to provide an update of the protocol roadmap to show what <a href="https://near.org/blog/near-q2-protocol-roadmap-update">we accomplished in 2023</a> and what is planned for 2024.<br></p>



<p>TLDR: 2023 saw major experience improvements via meta transactions and zero-balance accounts, as well as node performance improvements and optimizations. Preparations are underway for a major upgrade to stateless validation, completing Phase 2 of the sharding roadmap in early 2024.<br></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-we-accomplished-in-2023">What we accomplished in 2023</h2>



<p>There were a total of six protocol upgrades in 2023 which introduced a number of new protocol features. <strong>Meta transactions</strong> were added as a protocol feature at the beginning of the year to support gasless transactions, which means that users can transact on NEAR and start using apps without necessarily needing to pay transaction fees in NEAR. We also added <strong>zero-balance accounts</strong>, an important feature that enables users to create an account without holding NEAR to pay for storage. This makes it easy to onboard new users to applications. These two features form a solid foundation for a seamless onboarding experience for end users — a top goal for NEAR overall.<br></p>



<p>In addition to easy user onboarding, we have also been working hard to optimize the performance of NEAR. <strong>Flat storage</strong>, which was released in Q2 this year, optimized state reads and improved the stability and performance of the network overall. Another feature that optimizes NEAR nodes is <strong>cold storage</strong>, which allows for a split between hot and cold storage for a node. This means an archival node does not need to store most of the historical data on SSD and therefore can save a lot on cost. We also optimized the network communication between validator nodes by introducing the <strong>tier1 network</strong>, which reduces the latency of network messages between two validator nodes. Furthermore, we improved <strong>state sync</strong> and reduced the time it took a node to synchronize the latest state. We have also worked on improving the stability and maintainability of contract runtime with initiatives like finite wasm and limited replayability.<br></p>



<p>There are a few major initiatives that we started this year and expect to finish next year, such as stateless validation, congestion control, and transaction priority. We will dive deeper into those in the section below.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-plans-for-2024"><br>Plans for 2024</h2>



<p>There are a few major projects that we want to deliver in 2024 to improve the usability, scalability, and decentralization of NEAR Protocol:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Stateless validation</strong>. Stateless validation is a major initiative that we have been working on for a few months. It adjusts the original Nightshade sharding design to avoid implementing fraud proofs while improving the performance of each shard significantly by putting state in memory. The stateless validation work is expected to be delivered in Q2 2024, which would also mark the completion of the original goal we set for Phase 2 of sharding. We expect the launch of stateless validation to also dramatically increase the throughput of each shard and prepare NEAR for the continued growth of usage.</li>



<li><strong>Congestion control and transaction priority</strong>. While NEAR’s sharding design is horizontally scalable, it is important to provide a good user experience when there is short-term congestion on the network. This includes localizing congestion so that gas price increase does not affect the entire network and allowing users to prioritize their transactions during congestion if they are willing to pay more in transaction fees.</li>



<li><strong>Support for account aggregation</strong>. Account aggregation allows a user to control accounts on different chains with one NEAR account, an important pillar of the chain abstraction vision for NEAR. It requires chain signatures, which does MPC to sign payload. This requires a new runtime API to facilitate the asynchronous nature of chain signatures.</li>



<li><strong>zkWASM</strong>. We have been working on zkWASM with the Polygon team for a few months and the work will continue in 2024. The goal is to build a prover for WebAssembly smart contracts. This could be used as a part of the initiative to prove the state transition of NEAR in a ZK proof. Moreover, zkWASM also provides wasm as an alternative execution environment to EVM for L2s.</li>



<li><strong>Data availability improvements</strong>. We launched <a href="https://near.org/data-availability">NEAR DA</a> in early November 2023 and there are a few things that we plan to work on to further improve the efficiency of NEAR DA. Those improvements include introducing KZG commitment to avoid having data availability fraud proofs, as well as real-time bridging to allow verification of data availability on Ethereum.</li>



<li><strong>Ethereum wallet support</strong>. Supporting wallets like MetaMask natively on NEAR allows us to attract more users to NEAR and also be more Ethereum aligned. This requires changes to the protocol to support Ethereum addresses natively and support processing of RLP serialized Ethereum transactions.</li>



<li><strong>Research into the future of sharding</strong>. There are two major directions of exploration: synchronous sharding and ZK-centric sharding. Synchronous sharding enables synchronous execution of smart contracts and addresses the developer experience pain point of having to deal with asynchronous execution. ZK-centric sharding leverages zero-knowledge proofs to validate state transition of different shards and improves the scalability and decentralization of the protocol. In addition, we will also research the next and final phase of sharding: dynamically adjusting the number of shards based on usage.<br></li>
</ul>



<p>The roadmap can be seen below for those interested in more timeline specifics. It is split into two parts: <strong>Experience </strong>and <strong>Core</strong>. The Experience section encompasses user and/or developer experience and the protocol features needed to enable those experiences. As an example, synchronous execution addresses the pain point that developers feel when they implement cross-contract calls. <br></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="592" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Protocol-Roadmap-2024-Experience-1024x592.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21157" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Protocol-Roadmap-2024-Experience-1024x592.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Protocol-Roadmap-2024-Experience-300x174.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Protocol-Roadmap-2024-Experience-768x444.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Protocol-Roadmap-2024-Experience.png 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><br>The Core section, on the other hand, covers major efforts to improve the scalability and decentralization of the protocol. This includes stateless validation, zkWASM, improvements to data availability, and so on.<br></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="644" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Protocol-Roadmap-2024-Core-1024x644.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21158" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Protocol-Roadmap-2024-Core-1024x644.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Protocol-Roadmap-2024-Core-300x189.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Protocol-Roadmap-2024-Core-768x483.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Protocol-Roadmap-2024-Core.png 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><br><br>As always, the protocol team is proud to have made several important improvements to the core protocol with zero disruption for users and developers. We look forward to making some major advancements in 2024 to help the entire NEAR ecosystem deliver its vision of mainstream adoption of an Open Web, where all internet users can control their own data, assets, and power of governance. <br><br>We will share more details on Phase 2 advancements and timelines soon. If you’d like to learn more, join the NEAR Protocol <a href="https://twitter.com/nearprotocol">X Spaces</a> on Tuesday, January 16 at 5pm UTC to hear from Director of Protocol Bowen Wang and NEAR Foundation CEO Illia Polosukhin on upcoming protocol developments.<br></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-q4-protocol-roadmap-update/">NEAR Q4 Protocol Roadmap Update</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Check Out the Pagoda Product Roadmap</title>
		<link>/blog/check-out-the-pagoda-product-roadmap/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Winer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pagoda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pagoda Product Roadmap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20986</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the past year, Pagoda has been working hard to build out the B.O.S, evolve near.org, and continue developing the …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/check-out-the-pagoda-product-roadmap/">Check Out the Pagoda Product Roadmap</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Over the past year, Pagoda has been working hard to build out the B.O.S, evolve near.org, and continue developing the NEAR protocol. While Pagoda has built and launched proprietary services in the past, almost all of our work so far in 2023 and planned for the future is free open-source software,&nbsp; which we intend to become vital parts of the NEAR ecosystem. We want the community to be aware of, excited by, and engaged in this work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I’m excited to announce that Pagoda is making its product roadmap public this week <a href="https://github.com/orgs/near/projects/80/views/3">via GitHub</a>. It&#8217;s honestly a bit overdue. Given our values of transparency and collaboration, we hope to involve more members of the community in the development process. We also hope this lets teams across the NEAR ecosystem plan ahead a bit better, build in parallel to Pagoda, and even get ideas for what to build based on what you feel is missing or should be prioritized.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Right now this roadmap covers the rest of 2023 and we are committing to update the roadmap at least quarterly. The roadmap on GitHub is arranged into several views covering both the company objectives (OKRs) as well as larger workstreams (initiatives). We’ve further organized our roadmap views by product vertical and priority level, along with status and expected delivery date (which the product leads will update in real time). You may see some roadmap items displayed as “private”; this is because certain partnerships and enterprise workstreams must remain under NDA or embargo until launch. The Pagoda team will continue to iterate on this roadmap tool to make it an even richer resource for ecosystem partners and the NEAR community.</p>



<p>Delivering on the Open Web vision will take contributions far beyond Pagoda and we look forward to working alongside those who are as passionate about NEAR as we are. Please explore and leave comments or questions on the <a href="https://near.social/mob.near/widget/MainPage.N.Post.Page?accountId=pagodaplatform.near&amp;blockHeight=103737068">NEAR Social post</a> – or on the roadmap itself – if you have feedback.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>-Eric Winer, CTO Pagoda</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/check-out-the-pagoda-product-roadmap/">Check Out the Pagoda Product Roadmap</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Embracing Decentralization: What’s Next for the NEAR Wallet</title>
		<link>/blog/embracing-decentralization-whats-next-for-the-near-wallet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transfer Wizard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When NEAR Mainnet launched in late 2020, it included a wallet built and hosted by Pagoda’s (then known as Near …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/embracing-decentralization-whats-next-for-the-near-wallet/">Embracing Decentralization: What’s Next for the NEAR Wallet</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When NEAR Mainnet launched in late 2020, it included a wallet built and hosted by Pagoda’s (then known as Near Inc.) core team on <a href="https://wallet.near.org/">https://wallet.near.org/</a> to support NEAR’s unique account model. Nearly three years later, the NEAR wallet ecosystem is home to a myriad of high quality, open source wallets supported by NEAR’s community of active contributors. This significant milestone reflects NEAR’s ongoing commitment to empower users and foster decentralization. The evolution of NEAR wallets also showcases the substantial growth of the ecosystem, as NEAR now supports a diverse list of cross-chain wallets, as well as native wallets with innovative onboarding approaches such as <a href="/blog/get-to-know-the-bos-fastauth-for-easy-web2-style-onboarding-and-account-recovery/?_gl=1%2A1fvy7yq%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMjA1NTA3NTczNy4xNjg2NjY4NDc2%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY4NjY2ODQ3NC4xLjEuMTY4NjY2ODUxMC4wLjAuMA..">FastAuth</a>.</p>



<p>To celebrate these excellent contributions from across the NEAR community, and to reflect the priority of decentralization, over the next few months Pagoda will start migrating the domain <a href="https://wallet.near.org/">https://wallet.near.org/</a> from being a browser wallet to being a wallet hub. In this way, <a href="https://wallet.near.org/">https://wallet.near.org/</a> will become the reference place for all NEAR wallets, allowing users to discover and implement the right wallets for their specific needs.</p>



<p>If you currently use <a href="https://wallet.near.org/">https://wallet.near.org/</a> as your main wallet, you have nothing to worry about. The Pagoda team has been working hard to build a Wallet Transfer Wizard to help you transfer your accounts to a new wallet easily and smoothly, while keeping your funds and assets safe. The Transfer Wizard will allow you to choose between Browser and Extension-based wallets, so you will still have the same friendly wallet experience you are accustomed to after the Wizard is finished.</p>



<p>For more details, visit the <a href="https://wallet.near.org/transfer-wizard">Migrating from NEAR Wallet</a> page.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-timeline-for-transitioning-the-main-wallet-domain">Timeline for transitioning the main wallet domain&nbsp;</h3>



<p>The NEAR Wallet will remain a browser wallet until <strong>January 1st, 2024</strong>, during which time the wallet will encourage and help you to transfer your accounts to a new wallet. You can do this manually with your recovery phrase or use the Transfer Wizard to securely migrate your accounts to the wallet of your choice. </p>



<p>Do not worry if you have not transferred your accounts by <strong> <strong>January 1st, 2024</strong></strong> —<strong> </strong>the Transfer Wizard will still be available after the wallet functionality sunsets. Rest assured that your assets will remain secure until you import them to a new wallet.</p>



<p>The Transfer Wizard will remain available on the new wallet landing page at wallet.near.org indefinitely. This repurposed page will act as an introduction to the various options for wallets in the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-a-new-era-for-near-wallets">A new era for NEAR Wallets</h3>



<p>This new step moves NEAR closer to achieving a truly decentralized ecosystem driven by its own community. Thanks to the wallet hub and the wallet selector (which enables the use of any compatible NEAR wallet in web applications), users will now be able to use any wallet they like. This will not only improve their experience on NEAR, but also the full spectrum of available Web3 experiences thanks <a href="/blog/near-blockchain-operating-system-is-now-live-on-near-org/?_gl=1%2Ahbkih2%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMjAwNDA3NDY4Mi4xNjg2NjY5MjQx%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY4NjY2OTIzOS4xLjEuMTY4NjY2OTI0My4wLjAuMA..">to the BOS</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/embracing-decentralization-whats-next-for-the-near-wallet/">Embracing Decentralization: What’s Next for the NEAR Wallet</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vistara Lands in the NEAR Ecosystem for Seamless Base Layer Roll-up Deployment</title>
		<link>/blog/vistara-lands-in-the-near-ecosystem-for-seamless-base-layer-roll-up-deployment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20704</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR is welcoming Vistara, the groundbreaking rollup deployment framework, into the fold. Vistara is set to seamlessly integrate with the …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/vistara-lands-in-the-near-ecosystem-for-seamless-base-layer-roll-up-deployment/">Vistara Lands in the NEAR Ecosystem for Seamless Base Layer Roll-up Deployment</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR is welcoming <a href="https://twitter.com/vistaralabs">Vistara</a>, the groundbreaking rollup deployment framework, into the fold. Vistara is set to seamlessly integrate with the BOS for the end-to-end, multi-chain deployment of rollups. This alliance will accelerate the pace of blockchain innovation, making rollup deployment faster, more efficient, and accessible across multiple chains for all developers.</p>



<p>Vistara stands out as a game-changing one-click <a href="https://docs.vistara.dev/">rollup deployment framework</a> that simplifies creating application-specific rollups across multiple blockchains. Streamlining the intricate rollup deployment process into a straightforward, single-click operation, Vistara will build a front-end on the BOS to make user-friendly, multi-chain rollup deployment a reality.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-simplifying-multi-chain-roll-ups-with-vistara-on-the-bos">Simplifying multi-chain roll-ups with Vistara on the BOS&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Existing frameworks such as Cosmos SDK and Substrate have sought to streamline certain software components in decentralized applications but often leave developers tied to one ecosystem that they must completely understand and master. Vistara will now present a unique solution by combining the BOS with backend chains like Ethereum and Celestia.</p>



<p>Vistara’s emphasis on simplifying rollup component creation aligns with NEAR&#8217;s vision of user-centric decentralization and a serverless Web3. With this new BOS front-end integration, developers in the NEAR ecosystem and beyond can now build and deploy rollups in one convenient location.</p>



<p>The result will be a user-friendly design that makes the deployment of a rollup as simple as selecting an option from a dropdown menu. The integration will also encourage a wider range of developers to build with rollups on the BOS with any chain, leading to a more diverse pool of innovations and robust growth.</p>



<p>Vistara’s integration not only simplifies the process but also expands the scope for innovation. It demystifies rollup creation, making it accessible to a broader range of developers. This inclusivity fuels a more diverse pool of applications, fostering growth and vibrancy within the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-vistara-and-bos-breaking-base-layer-building-barriers">Vistara and BOS breaking base layer building barriers</h2>



<p>Developing decentralized applications on base layers can be a complex process. Coordination of node operators, high costs, and extended development times are among the major challenges. However, Vistara is designed to confront these issues directly, streamlining the process and fostering efficiency.</p>



<p>Rollups — technologies that bundle or &#8216;roll up&#8217; side-chain transactions into a single transaction — provide an effective solution. They help developers bypass the difficulties associated with building decentralized networks. Vistara leverages this rollup technology, pushing the NEAR ecosystem towards application-specific rollups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The solution effectively untangles the complexities tied to base layer dependencies, forging a development environment on the BOS that stretches beyond traditional base layer confines. With Vistara, multi-chain developers can now bring their applications to life more swiftly and efficiently than ever before.</p>



<p>To sum up, Vistara&#8217;s user-friendly, multi-chain rollup deployment capabilities on the BOS will have a huge impact on the NEAR ecosystem and beyond. The integration will take much of the complexity out of rollup deployment for anyone, helping Web3 creators, builders, and developers bring their applications to life faster than ever.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/vistara-lands-in-the-near-ecosystem-for-seamless-base-layer-roll-up-deployment/">Vistara Lands in the NEAR Ecosystem for Seamless Base Layer Roll-up Deployment</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Teams With Google Cloud to Accelerate Web3 Startups</title>
		<link>/blog/near-teams-with-google-cloud-to-accelerate-web3-startups/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 12:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18589</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a new partnership between Google Cloud and NEAR Protocol. Going forward, Google Cloud will …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-teams-with-google-cloud-to-accelerate-web3-startups/">NEAR Teams With Google Cloud to Accelerate Web3 Startups</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a new partnership between Google Cloud and NEAR Protocol. Going forward, Google Cloud will provide technical support for NEAR grant recipients. Open and developer-friendly, Google Cloud will support devs as they build and scale their Web3 projects and dApps.</p>



<p>If you’re developing on NEAR, this is great news—the partnership will supercharge blockchain innovations. Developers will even more easily create without limits as they build dApps and help onboard the masses into Web3.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We are thrilled to be collaborating with those who pioneered the Internet as we know it,” says Marieke Flament, CEO of the NEAR Foundation. “This partnership marks a new chapter for us as we continue to offer the best support possible for the next generation of visionaries choosing to build on the NEAR protocol.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-powering-near-developers-with-google-cloud">Powering NEAR developers with Google Cloud</h2>



<p>In the last year, NEAR has grown exponentially thanks to its super-fast, incredibly secure, and infinitely scalable protocol. There are now over 20 million accounts, 200 million transactions to date, and 300,000 to 400,000 transactions per day on the NEAR network. Building upon the momentum of NEARCON 2022, which showcased the NEAR ecosystem’s vibrancy, <a href="http://awesomenear.com/">800 projects</a> are now building on the protocol.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How will the hundreds of projects currently building on NEAR benefit from the Google Cloud partnership?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Google Cloud provides the infrastructure for NEAR’s Remote Procedure Call (RPC) node provider to <a href="https://www.pagoda.co/">Pagoda</a>, NEAR’s Web3 startup platform. This allows developers to deploy code quickly, securely, and seamlessly. Pagoda helps developers easily and rapidly launch dApps on NEAR through a library of pre-audited templates and auto-generated contract user interfaces.</p>



<p>&nbsp;“We will be supporting NEAR and giving Web3 developers the most secure, reliable, and sustainable cloud infrastructure on which they can build and scale,” Carlos Arena, Director of&nbsp;<a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/financial-services/google-cloud-launches-dedicated-digital-asset-team">Digital Assets</a> at Google Cloud. “We continue to support tomorrow’s leaders in creating new products and services on blockchain-based platforms.”</p>



<p>For more information on how Google Cloud is working to support Web3 innovation, check out <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/financial-services/google-cloud-launches-dedicated-digital-asset-team">Google Cloud’s Digital Assets blog</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-teams-with-google-cloud-to-accelerate-web3-startups/">NEAR Teams With Google Cloud to Accelerate Web3 Startups</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hacking a New World with MetaBUILD III</title>
		<link>/blog/hacking-a-new-world-with-metabuild-iii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 20:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>UPDATE: MetaBUILD III&#8217;s Pre-Accelerator Program has some new details. Scroll down to the &#8220;After the Hack&#8221; section for more information.   …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/hacking-a-new-world-with-metabuild-iii/">Hacking a New World with MetaBUILD III</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong><em> MetaBUILD III&#8217;s Pre-Accelerator Program has some new details. Scroll down to the &#8220;After the Hack&#8221; section for more information.  </em></p>



<p>Six months ago, NEAR wrapped up the <a href="https://medium.com/nearprotocol/metabuilding-the-history-of-near-2719ce71acbf">MetaBUILD 2 hackathon</a> just as the world shut down. New challenges emerged, both inside and outside the NEAR ecosystem. The crypto market itself was seemingly falling apart, and everyone was talking about the looming “Crypto winter”. It was clear that in order to continue, a new, creative approach would be necessary.</p>



<p>NEAR was founded during some of the gloomiest times of the previous “Crypto winter”, so at least some of this was already familiar territory. In fact, NEAR’s resilient design was informed by the uncertainty in the markets surrounding its release. This resilience is not just evident in the technology, but it can also be seen throughout the ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To maintain the health of its vibrant community, NEAR focused the aim of its hackathons towards a broader, more ambitious journey for participants—what if these hackathons could foster each team from ideation all the way to forming a Web3 start-up with a market-ready product?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-metabuild-iii-a-bigger-better-impact">MetaBUILD III: A Bigger, Better Impact</h2>



<p>MetaBUILD is considered <a href="https://metabuildii.devpost.com/">one of the biggest hackathons</a> in the blockchain community. With a $1 million in prizes pool, nearly 4,000 participants, and more than 350 submissions from across the world, it has helped realize ideas from streaming tokens to metaverse worlds. In fact, some of these winners will be featured at <a href="https://nearcon.org/">NEARCON in September</a>, so the community can listen to their stories and learn from their challenges.</p>



<p>This year, <strong>MetaBUILD III</strong> returns with its $1 million in prizes, with registrations opening today and submissions starting September 23rd. But participants should expect to see the hackathon’s format evolve. It’s shaping it up to become an <strong>8-week product-oriented incubation program, hosted by Pagoda,</strong> focused on supporting teams beyond the prize money, towards securing funding, and producing a market-ready prototype. Here’s what else is new:</p>



<ul><li>Instead of the Welcome track (for newly created projects), a <strong>Web2 track </strong>will be established to help existing teams integrate NEAR blockchain into their current products.</li><li>Only <strong>newly created or substantively modified projects </strong>are allowed to enter the Native track to ensure that participants are committed to remaining in the ecosystem even after they win. Proofs of concept projects built during <a href="https://nearcon-irl-hackathon.devpost.com/">NEARCON’s 48hs IRL hackathon</a> are welcome to join MetaBUILD.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Challenges instead of bounties</strong>: MetaBUILD III is looking for sustained product teams who understand their market and are committed to building solutions addressing some of the most pressing challenges of today: rising unemployment, the energy crisis, refugee crises, climate change, access to education and other resources, media censorship, etc.</li></ul>



<p>This shift in perspective centers on an understanding of how impactful $1 million could be in the right hands. It is not only about proving great ideas, but growing them as products that can make a long-term impact in the ecosystem and beyond!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ways-to-metabuild">Ways to MetaBUILD</h2>



<p>Whether you are a solo hacker or an ecosystem partner, there are several ways to participate in MetaBUILD III:</p>



<ul><li><strong>As a developer</strong></li></ul>



<p>Incubate your project from idea to an MVP in 8 weeks. Find some talented teammates, and win $20-60k to continue building.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://metabuild.devpost.com/register?flow%5Bdata%5D%5Bchallenge_id%5D=15923&amp;flow%5Bname%5D=register_for_challenge">Learn more &gt;</a></p>



<ul><li><strong>As a non-technical person</strong></li></ul>



<p>Pivot your career into Web3, and join one of the teams as a designer, bizdev expert, product manager, or copywriter to build a winning project together.</p>



<ul><li><strong>As a NEAR community member</strong></li></ul>



<p>Host a workshop, share your success story, or provide mentorship to participants.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://forms.gle/esmF2QTPcrcwRLiu9">Learn more &gt;</a></p>



<ul><li><strong>As a Web3 company or VC</strong></li></ul>



<p>Spread the word about MetaBUILD in your community, apply to become a mentor or a judge, or host an IRL event to inspire and support the MetaBUILD community.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://forms.gle/esmF2QTPcrcwRLiu9">Learn more &gt;</a>&nbsp;</p>



<p>To help fuel the ideas for the next big wave in Web3, a whole educational program will be added to the incubation process:</p>



<ul><li><strong>The Education team</strong> behind <a href="https://www.near.university/">NEAR University</a> will provide self-paced NEAR workshops.</li><li><strong>Team Docs </strong>will present their <a href="https://docs.near.org/tutorials/welcome">Zero to Hero</a> tutorials<strong> </strong>to make sure the onboarding process is streamlined for everyone.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>The Pagoda team</strong> is already hosting monthly <a href="http://near.ai/tooling-meetings">Developer Tooling</a> meetings to demonstrate the features and capabilities of their latest releases.</li></ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">After the Hack: Pre-Accelerator Program from Pagoda and Startup Wise Guys</h2>



<p>This time, MetaBUILD is not just about building a quick project for competition. The new challenge is for developers to join and build a new product that can hit the market and make a long-term impact on the NEAR ecosystem. From MVP in the hack, to a first market release in the pre-accelerator program, MetaBUILD III is designed to get devs the resources they need to get there with a solid foundation.</p>



<p>Of the winning submissions, 30 MetaBUILD projects will be welcomed to a pre-accelerator program hosted by Pagoda and Startup Wise Guys. Projects will have access to a roster of talented NEAR ecosystem mentors, who will support them in their early stages as projects focus on the key components of their business and idea. NEAR mentors will also help winning submissions develop go-to-market strategies with clear goals and propositions, acquire their first customers, operate sustainably for the long term, and attract investment with our roster of talented NEAR ecosystem partners, amongst other things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ultimately, the pre-accelerator program will help projects prepare to successfully apply for full-time accelerator programs or first-round investment opportunities.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-we-in-web3">The “We” in Web3</h2>



<p>Navigating a bear market is a sobering experience, but it is also an inspiring one, because Web3 is ready to face new challenges, new audiences, and new use cases. All it needs are open minds, ambitious ideas, and a willingness to work together to change the world—one decentralized project at a time.</p>



<p>Ready to hack the ever changing world? <a href="https://metabuild.devpost.com/">Build your next project on NEAR</a>. MetaBUILD III is here to guide you from idea to market, and beyond. We have the expertise, the funds, and the drive to face new challenges together.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://secure.devpost.com/users/register?return_to=https%3A%2F%2Fmetabuild.devpost.com%2Fregister%3Fflow%255Bdata%255D%255Bchallenge_id%255D%3D15923%26flow%255Bname%255D%3Dregister_for_challenge">Register Today</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/hacking-a-new-world-with-metabuild-iii/">Hacking a New World with MetaBUILD III</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
