<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ZK Proofs Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/zk-proofs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/zk-proofs/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 15:43:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.orghttps://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>ZK Proofs Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/zk-proofs/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>NEAR Integrates Wormhole to Launch ZK-Enabled Cross-Chain Communication with Ethereum </title>
		<link>/blog/near-integrates-wormhole-to-launch-zk-enabled-cross-chain-communication-with-ethereum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wormhole]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zero-Knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ZK Proofs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Driving the evolution of Web3 through innovation and interoperability, bridging technology has become a critical factor in user adoption and …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-integrates-wormhole-to-launch-zk-enabled-cross-chain-communication-with-ethereum/">NEAR Integrates Wormhole to Launch ZK-Enabled Cross-Chain Communication with Ethereum </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Driving the evolution of Web3 through innovation and interoperability, bridging technology has become a critical factor in user adoption and functionality. NEAR Foundation has chosen to bolster its multi-chain interoperability by integrating with <a href="https://wormhole.com/next/">Wormhole</a>, harnessing the power of cutting-edge Zero-Knowledge (ZK) light clients. </p>



<p>This strategic move revolutionizes secure Web3 application communication, unlocking vast potential across diverse sectors including DeFi, NFTs, and governance. The integration represents a tangible stride towards a less abstract and more interconnected, trustless Web3. By incorporating Wormhole&#8217;s technology, NEAR Foundation envisions a practical shift where cross-chain transactions become efficient, secure, and user-friendly.</p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s unique position as a developer-friendly platform amplifies the impact of this integration, driving the adoption of Zero-Knowledge technology to a wider audience. The NEAR Foundation is not just creating a world of possibility but is actively building it, bringing advanced blockchain solutions to the mainstream.</p>



<p>Signaling a new era of trustless cross-chain communication, this NEAR-Wormhole integration will be explored through the NEAR &lt;&gt; ETH corridor and the promise of Zero-Knowledge bridging.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-wormhole-the-key-to-near-s-vision-of-a-multi-chain-web3">Wormhole: the key to NEAR&#8217;s vision of a multi-chain Web3</h2>



<p>Wormhole is forging its place in crypto as the industry-standard cross-chain messaging protocol, reliably facilitating transfers exceeding $35 billion dollars via countless cross-chain messages. In this integration, Wormhole&#8217;s role is vital, employing its advanced technology to connect the NEAR ecosystem with over 20 other high-value blockchain networks.</p>



<p>The integration enables synergy of&nbsp; Wormhole Connect&#8217;s technology with NEAR&#8217;s Blockchain Operating System (BOS) to enhance developer access to multiple chains and diverse liquidity. It will also serve to break down barriers for casual users, blending complex blockchain tech with a user-friendly experience.</p>



<p>Moreover, Wormhole&#8217;s integration with NEAR&#8217;s BOS presents a significant opportunity for businesses using NEAR. This collaboration simplifies multi-chain interaction and introduces Zero-Knowledge proofs, making it easier for businesses to fully utilize blockchain technology in a straightforward and accessible manner.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-wormhole-s-near-eth-corridor-opens-opportunities">Wormhole’s NEAR &lt;&gt; ETH corridor opens opportunities&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Born from this integration is the trustless NEAR &lt;&gt; ETH corridor, an innovation powered by Wormhole and secured by Zero-Knowledge (ZK) Proofs. This marks a shift from NEAR&#8217;s traditional Rainbow Bridge, introducing seamless integration of NEAR assets with Wormhole-linked chains.</p>



<p>The NEAR &lt;&gt; ETH corridor represents a new class of zk-enabled bridges, offering heightened interconnectedness between the NEAR ecosystem and a multitude of Wormhole-facilitated applications. This trustless corridor is poised to catalyze more efficient and secure transactions, symbolizing a substantial stride toward a fully interoperable Web3 ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-making-tomorrow-s-crypto-verse-trustless-and-zk-based">Making tomorrow’s crypto-verse trustless and ZK-based</h2>



<p>The NEAR and Wormhole integration isn&#8217;t just a stride toward the future — it&#8217;s a giant leap toward a new era powered by ZK Proofs. As part of the integration work, developers are building the first ZK light clients, which will play a crucial role in supporting the trustless NEAR &lt;&gt; ETH corridor.</p>



<p>ZK light clients promise to revolutionize the bridging experience, discarding the need for trust assumptions and external validation. By offloading most of the computational load to an off-chain entity, these clients optimize storage and compute resources, paving the way for a streamlined and efficient bridging process. This innovation is set to redefine the standards of security and reliability in the blockchain sector.</p>



<p>The integration between NEAR and Wormhole is a decisive step towards a future where cross-chain communication is seamless, secure, and trustless. It&#8217;s a future that opens up new horizons for developers and users alike, offering improved interoperability and accessibility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With Wormhole, NEAR citizens can engage and interact with other chains in a blink of an eye.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-integrates-wormhole-to-launch-zk-enabled-cross-chain-communication-with-ethereum/">NEAR Integrates Wormhole to Launch ZK-Enabled Cross-Chain Communication with Ethereum </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
