<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>BORA Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/bora/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/bora/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 18:50:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>BORA Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/bora/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Near Partners with BORA, Web3 GameFi Platform of Kakao Games</title>
		<link>/blog/near-partners-with-bora-one-of-koreas-largest-gamefi-platforms/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BORA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GameFI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kakao Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3 Gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Near is excited to announce a new strategic partnership with BORA, a Web3&#160; gaming subsidiary of METABORA. Near and BORA …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-partners-with-bora-one-of-koreas-largest-gamefi-platforms/">Near Partners with BORA, Web3 GameFi Platform of Kakao Games</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Near is excited to announce a new strategic partnership with BORA, a Web3&nbsp; gaming subsidiary of METABORA. Near and BORA will support each other in spreading local brand awareness, invest in research and collaboration on cross-chain, host events, and generate Web3 opportunities in Korea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>An affiliate of Kakao Games and its parent company BORANETWORK, BORA is focused on game development and blockchain-based gaming ecosystems. Its mobile gaming titles include <em>Friends Popcorn</em>, <em>Friends Town</em>, and <em>Friends Shot</em>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We are thrilled to be working with Near and welcome their expertise, knowledge and network as we aim to transform the world of Web3 gaming,” said Vincent Lim, a CBO of BORA. “Together with Near we will not only explore cross-promotion opportunities, but also seek future collaborations on IP-based game development that will lead to mass adoption and give us the competitive edge we need to position ourselves as leading players in the web3 gaming space.”</p>



<p>Since the launch of Near’s Korean Hub in November of 2022, BORA has been steadily building up awareness throughout South Korea, while focusing on Web3&nbsp; innovation, business development, education, and talent. The hub is led by entrepreneurs Scott Lee and Ben Kang — both influential figures within South Korea’s growing blockchain community.</p>



<p>“One of the big ambitions of the hub&nbsp; is&nbsp; to tap into the country’s active gaming community, and to&nbsp; bring&nbsp; amazing projects and creators to the Near ecosystem.” said Robbie Lim, GM, Partners &amp; International at Near. “ The partnership with BORA is our first major win &#8211; and a big step forward for NEAR as it accelerates its ambition to become the go to layer 1 for the Web3 gaming community.”&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-partners-with-bora-one-of-koreas-largest-gamefi-platforms/">Near Partners with BORA, Web3 GameFi Platform of Kakao Games</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
