<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NEARCON 2023 Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/nearcon-2023/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/nearcon-2023/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 16:46:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.orghttps://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>NEARCON 2023 Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/nearcon-2023/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Built on NEAR: Celebrating Partners and Innovators at NEARCON &#8217;23</title>
		<link>/blog/built-on-near-celebrating-partners-and-innovators-at-nearcon-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 15:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Partnerships are one of the biggest pillars to expanding NEAR’s footprint. They help drive the ecosystem toward fostering new and …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/built-on-near-celebrating-partners-and-innovators-at-nearcon-23/">Built on NEAR: Celebrating Partners and Innovators at NEARCON &#8217;23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Partnerships are one of the biggest pillars to expanding NEAR’s footprint. They help drive the ecosystem toward fostering new and innovative use cases that will bring the next billion users to the open web. And that&#8217;s exactly what&#8217;s happening on NEAR, with partnerships ranging from sports to social taking center stage. At NEARCON&nbsp;— <a href="https://near.org/blog/nearcon-the-ultimate-web3-education-for-only-99">the ultimate Web3 education</a> — a number of NEAR partners will be on-hand to talk about Web3 partnerships and innovation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Throughout the past few years, NEAR has engaged, collaborated, and built with partners who share the vision of a decentralized, user-centric open web. Each partnership is contributing their unique, innovative flair to the ecosystem, with a scalable, user-friendly blockchain helping to propel their efforts.</p>



<p>As NEARCON ‘23 approaches, let’s celebrate and explore how NEAR&#8217;s collaborations and partnerships are shaping the future of the open web. By registering for and attending NEARCON ‘23, you’ll be able to meet some of the following founders, entrepreneurs, and innovators below.</p>



<p>And these names are just the tip of the iceberg, so don’t forget to register for NEARCON ‘23 and let’s take part in learning, networking, and building an open web together.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://nearcon.app/">Register $99</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-creating-consumer-fun-and-engagement-in-the-open-web">Creating consumer fun and engagement in the open web</h2>



<p>An area where NEAR partnerships are thriving is making the blockchain more fun and engaging for the masses. NEAR’s partnership with NFT launchpad <a href="https://www.mintbase.xyz/">Mintbase</a> is a perfect illustration. Mintbase recently celebrated the traditional Indian festival, Raksha Bandhan, by seamlessly <a href="/blog/mintbase-brings-new-open-web-wallet-tech-to-families-celebrating-raksha-bandhan/">transforming photos into NFTs</a> on the NEAR blockchain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During Raksha Bandan, sisters tie a good-luck talisman around the wrists of their brothers, a special moment often photographed and cherished by families. With Mintbase’s open web wallet built on NEAR, users could easily create an account without seed phrases and seamlessly upload their photos, transforming them into NFTs in an instant.</p>



<p>Let’s also toast to&nbsp; <a href="http://www.glass.fun/">GLASS</a>, a one-of-a-kind Web3 platform that empowers alcohol brands to engage directly with consumers. Built on the NEAR blockchain, spirit brands can <a href="/blog/how-glass-is-uncorking-adult-beverage-loyalty-with-web3-and-near/">issue token rewards</a> and other blockchain perks to social drinkers who try new cocktail recipes, socialize with friends, and vote on brand decisions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gaming is also a key entry point into the open web, and NEAR&#8217;s partnership with <a href="https://playember.com/">PlayEmber</a> is kicking the door wide open. PlayEmber’s creative gaming studio is fusing AAA quality mobile games on the blockchain, with NEAR providing the backend foundation. Decentralized mobile gaming experiences are now becoming more accessible to a wider audience.</p>



<p>Then there’s <a href="https://cosmose.co/">Cosmose AI&#8217;s</a> KaiKai, a fusion of shopping, retail, and gamification dubbed&#8221;Shoppertainment.&#8221; Built on NEAR’s Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S), <a href="/blog/cosmose-and-near-foundation-set-to-revolutionize-retail-with-web3-and-ai/?_gl=1%2A1yt7etu%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2ANjE0MjI4NTkyLjE2OTcwMzUyNTQ.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5NzAzNTI1Mi4xLjAuMTY5NzAzNTI1Mi4wLjAuMA..">KaiKai offers a captivating brand discovery</a> avenue, with features like Augmented Reality (AR) product interactions, exclusive product drops, and celebrity live streams.&nbsp;</p>



<p>More than just a shopping app, KaiKai also uses a native cryptocurrency, Kai-Ching. Shoppers earn rewards with the help of Cosmose&#8217;s AI-powered personalization, all while transacting on the NEAR blockchain. It’s all about enhancing personalization, user empowerment, and engagements in the retail space with a unique, powerful blockchain twist.</p>



<p>And in a fusion of health and blockchain, <a href="https://sweatco.in/">Sweatcoin’s</a> partnership with NEAR helps people earn SWEAT tokens with literally every step towards better fitness. With a user base of over 63 million who&#8217;ve clocked in more than 19 trillion steps, Sweatcoin and NEAR are incentivizing&nbsp; healthier lifestyles.</p>



<p>Oleg Fomenko, co-founder of Sweatcoin, believes in the <a href="https://near.org/blog/sweatcoin-partners-with-near-foundation-to-create-a-new-movement-economy">potential of merging health and blockchain</a>, enabling users to “walk into the world of crypto.” This partnership, built on the NEAR blockchain, personifies the next level of open web adoption, encouraging physical wellness via crypto-based rewards.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-financial-empowerment-and-innovation-on-near">Financial empowerment and innovation on NEAR</h2>



<p>One of the biggest challenges that the open web is addressing is financial empowerment and inclusion. NEAR Foundation’s partnerships in this area are helping bring that vision to life. The Foundation’s collaboration with Proximity Labs is helping talented builders create innovative Web3 financial solutions, with substantial grants and support.</p>



<p>Calimero Network is another example of NEAR&#8217;s commitment to financial innovation. Calimero provides what’s called ‘private sharding’ infrastructure, a feature that ensures&nbsp; data privacy in Web3 finance without sacrificing the power of open-source platforms. With both <a href="https://www.theblock.co/post/204235/private-sharding-startup-calimero-network-raises-8-5-million">financial and technical support from NEAR</a>, more business can be safely conducted on the blockchain.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-building-the-technical-foundation-for-tomorrow-s-open-web">Building the technical foundation for tomorrow’s open web</h2>



<p>The ongoing partnership between NEAR Protocol and <a href="https://oct.network/">Octopus Network</a> signifies the ecosystem’s infrastructure strides. Early on, Octopus Network selected NEAR as its “mother-chain” protocol citing speed ability to accommodate a large user base. Octopus Network and NEAR are paving the way for developers aiming to launch tailored applications using their own dedicated blockchains —&nbsp;also known as “Appchains” —&nbsp;making deployment a breeze.</p>



<p>Partnering with a tech infrastructure behemoth like <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/startups/near-building-useable-web3-infrastructure-on-google-cloud">Google Cloud</a> is another way of giving Web3 startups pathways to world-class startup expertise. It’s all part of NEAR’s commitment to making blockchain solutions more accessible, robust, and primed for mainstream adoption.</p>



<p>In collaboration with <a href="https://urbit.org/">Urbit</a>, NEAR is also continuing to make the open web more user friendly. Urbit’s vision — shared and supported by the NEAR Foundation — is to improve the frontend experience of open web apps. Urbit allows developers to easily create sleek designs so that tomorrow’s decentralized applications are as seamless as the most popular ones in the App Store.</p>



<p>On another front, NEAR&#8217;s collaboration with <a href="https://sailgp.com/">SailGP</a> is bringing Decentralized Autonomous Organizations (DAOs) to professional sports, creating a bridge between leagues and fans. The introduction of a DAO-owned racing team on the NEAR Protocol gives fans a novel way to engage, interact with, and participate in active decision making along with teams and athletes.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-partnership-innovation-rolls-on-at-nearcon">Partnership innovation rolls on at NEARCON</h2>



<p>Past, current, and future partnership will take center stage at NEARCON 2023 — now less than a month away. It’ll be four full days of full immersion into the NEAR ecosystem —&nbsp;a place for you to truly step into the open web. Build on the B.O.S and network with thousands of other blockchain enthusiasts. Get the inside scoop on onboarding Web2 companies into Web3 with Google Cloud’s James Tromans, and get the low down on SWEAT with Oleg Fomenko.</p>



<p>From raising a glass to blockchain brand loyalty with GLASS and setting sail towards new DAO horizons with SailGP, each and every NEAR partner is playing its own pivotal role in crafting how tomorrow’s open web experiences will look, feel, and even taste. Better decentralized infrastructure, financial empowerment, and exciting consumer experiences are just the start.</p>



<p><em>Ready to dive into sessions, hackathons, and more in Lisbon at NEARCON 2023? Go ahead and </em><a href="https://tickets.nearcon.org/"><em>register now</em></a><em> to secure your spot.</em></p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://nearcon.app/">Register $99</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/built-on-near-celebrating-partners-and-innovators-at-nearcon-23/">Built on NEAR: Celebrating Partners and Innovators at NEARCON &#8217;23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Estudantes terão ingressos grátis no NEARCON’23</title>
		<link>/blog/estudantes-terao-ingressos-gratis-no-nearcon23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 17:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Estudantes do mundo inteiro estão interessados em Web3. Se você é um estudante em Portugal e quer aprender mais sobre …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/estudantes-terao-ingressos-gratis-no-nearcon23/">Estudantes terão ingressos grátis no NEARCON’23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Estudantes do mundo inteiro estão interessados em Web3. Se você é um estudante em Portugal e quer aprender mais sobre o mundo do Web3 não precisa procurar mais. NEARCON 2023 em Lisboa será o melhor lugar para aprender sobre a ‘open web’ (internet aberta).</p>



<p>Para começar sua jornada educacional na Web3, a Fundação NEAR tem uma excelente oferta para você! Estudantes registados em Portugal terão acesso a um número limitado de ingressos para o maior evento do ano, o NEARCON ‘23. O evento será em Lisboa, do dia 7 a 10 de Novembro (mais detalhes sobre como conseguir o ingresso abaixo).</p>



<p><strong>O que é o NEARCON?</strong></p>



<p>Para quem ainda não sabe, NEAR é uma blockchain, um ecossistema e uma comunidade internacional de desenvolvedores, criadores, fundadores e visionários da descentralização.</p>



<p>NEARCON será um evento de 4 dias celebrando a NEAR, o sistema operacional para blockchain na internet aberta (Blockchain Operating System &#8211; B.O.S). A internet aberta é como a internet deveria ser. Uma nova internet onde todos terão a chance de criar, participar e ganhar incentivos pelos seus dados, ideias e contribuições. NEAR é um dos únicos ecossistemas que podem trazer a internet aberta para todos.</p>



<p>Todos os anos a comunidade da NEAR se junta para ouvir, aprender, se conectar e desenvolver ideias inspiradoras para o futuro. NEARCON será o melhor lugar para aprender as últimas novidades da internet aberta!</p>



<p>Se você não tem certeza o que a Web3 é, ou como o crypto funciona, esse é o seu lugar. Um dos projetos mais descentralizados, a NEAR tem paixão em conectar e inspirar a próxima geração de talentos em tecnologia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEARCON 2023 vai ser o maior evento educacional de Web3 &#8211; e o número de ingressos gratuitos é limitado. Garanta o seu!</p>



<p><strong>O que você vai aprender no NEARCON ‘23</strong></p>



<p>O ecossistema em Web3 contém muitos setores, e nós temos a sorte de contar com muitas das mais brilhantes mentes no NEARCON esse ano. Palestras, painéis e conversas nos seguintes tópicos:</p>



<ul>
<li>Internet aberta &#8211; aprenda como a tecnologia aberta e seus ideais se juntam em blockchains como NEAR para a criação de uma internet onde todos podem aproveitar o controle dos seus dados, ideias e criações.</li>



<li>AI &amp; Blockchain &#8211; o co-fundador da NEAR, Illia Polosukhin, vai te ensinar como blockchain e inteligência artificial podem trabalhar juntos em 2023 e no futuro.</li>



<li>Descentralização &#8211; Veja como a NEAR Digital Collective (NDC) está contribuindo para a descentralização do ecossistema.</li>



<li>Leis e regulamentação &#8211; se informe sobre os últimos desenvolvimentos no setor.</li>
</ul>



<p>Garanta seu ingresso grátis para o NEARCON ‘23</p>



<p>É fácil garantir o seu ingresso grátis. Para conseguir o seu cupom de desconto, você precisa:</p>



<ul>
<li>Ser estudante registrado em Portugal</li>



<li>Ser maior de 18 anos</li>



<li>Estar disponível para ir ao evento entre 7 a 10 de Novembro em pessoa.</li>
</ul>



<p>Para acessar o cupom de desconto [DISCOUNT CODE], acesse a página do [NEARCON ‘23- add link]. Você vai precisar completar o formulário (preencha todas as informacoes). O site vai direcionar você à página de pagamento, mas não se preocupe, aqui você vai poder adicionar o cupom de desconto. O recibo com o ingresso será enviado para você.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/estudantes-terao-ingressos-gratis-no-nearcon23/">Estudantes terão ingressos grátis no NEARCON’23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Entradas Gratuitas a NEARCON ‘23 para Estudiantes en España</title>
		<link>/blog/entradas-gratuitas-a-nearcon-23-para-estudiantes-en-espana/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 17:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Si eres estudiante universitario en España y estás interesado en aprender sobre Web3, la Fundación NEAR tiene una gran noticia …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/entradas-gratuitas-a-nearcon-23-para-estudiantes-en-espana/">Entradas Gratuitas a NEARCON ‘23 para Estudiantes en España</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Si eres estudiante universitario en España y estás interesado en aprender sobre Web3, la Fundación NEAR tiene una gran noticia para ti. ¡Estamos ofreciendo un número limitado de entradas gratuitas a universitarios para NEARCON ‘23!, nuestro evento insignia en Lisboa, del 7 al 10 de noviembre (más detalles sobre elegibilidad debajo).&nbsp;</p>



<p>No importa si nunca usaste una blockchain, o si eres nuevo en el mundo del Web3. NEARCON es el mejor lugar para aprender sobre Web3 y cómo ésta contribuye a la Web Abierta.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-que-es-nearcon">¿Qué es NEARCON?</h3>



<p>Si nunca escuchaste hablar de NEAR, NEAR es a la vez una blockchain, un ecosistema, y una comunidad internacional de desarrolladores, emprendedores, y visionarios de la descentralización.</p>



<p>Una de las principales misiones de NEAR es hacer realidad la visión de una web abierta. Esto es, una web donde todo el mundo puede crear, participar y ser recompensado por sus datos, ideas y esfuerzo.</p>



<p>NEARCON es el evento insignia de 4 días destinado a NEAR, donde todos los años la comunidad se junta a debatir, conectar y colaborar en ideas que contribuyan a desarrollar una web abierta.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index">NEARCON 2023</a> ofrece lo mejor en educación Web3, y hay entradas gratuitas disponibles para un número limitado de universitarios.</p>



<p>No importa si eres nuevo en el universo Blockchain, NEAR tiene una pasión por involucrar e inspirar a la próxima generación de talentos Web3, ¡y NEARCON es el lugar donde aprender lo último en tecnología Web3 y la web abierta!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/entradas-gratuitas-a-nearcon-23-para-estudiantes-en-espana/">Entradas Gratuitas a NEARCON ‘23 para Estudiantes en España</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON IRL Hackathon 2023: Build the Open Web</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-irl-hackathon-2023-build-the-open-web/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 16:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON IRL Hackathon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you attended NEARCON last year, you know the 48-hour IRL hackathon — “Building Beyond the Hype” was a great …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-irl-hackathon-2023-build-the-open-web/">NEARCON IRL Hackathon 2023: Build the Open Web</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you attended NEARCON last year, you know the 48-hour IRL hackathon — “Building Beyond the Hype” was a great event, with all sorts of exciting prototypes that helped propel NEAR through the last year.</p>



<p>For NEARCON 2023, which will be held November 7-10th, we’re leveling up the hackathon. This year’s hackathon explores NEARCON 2023’s theme — “Step into the Open Web”. And that hacking together apps and experiences that explore how the NEAR Protocol and Blockchain Operating System are paving the way for a truly open web.</p>



<p>Let’s explore what’s new for the <a href="https://nearcon-hackathon.devpost.com/">NEARCON 2023 Hackathon</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="NEARCON 2023 IRL Hackathon: Step Into the Open Web" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9RqqoKDGWG4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-hacker-hq-a-space-just-for-the-hackers">Hacker HQ: a space just for the hackers</h2>



<p>Not only do hackers get into NEARCON 2023 for free, but they also get their own space. NEARCON’s Hacker HQ will be a place for hackers to hang out, network, and build — whether that’s for the Hackathon or if you’re just interested in continuing to build your project on NEAR. Hacker HQ will be located at:&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Armazem 16<br>R. Pereira Henriques nº1, 1950-242<br>Lisboa, Portugal</strong></p>



<p>Hack the days and nights away for a chance to build on the BOS and win $140k+.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-important-nearcon-hackathon-dates-and-information">Important NEARCON Hackathon dates and information</h2>



<ul>
<li>The Hackathon is held November 7-10th.
<ul>
<li><strong>November 7th</strong> — Hackathon orientation, team matching, and a welcome party hosted by NEARWEEK.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>November 8th</strong> — Day 1 of hacking. Mentoring available.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>November 9th</strong> — Day 2 of hacking. Mentoring available. Submission Deadline.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>November 10th</strong> — Pitch competition.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdncTzQkavACE1dmTJTZqWB1iOSpfYzGnof9pdNYjbmBhmgbQ/viewform">Request a visa letter</a> to support hackers’ visa applications. All requests must be submitted via the form by October 7, 2023.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Travel stipends are available depending on your location. Please read the <a href="https://near.social/devgovgigs.near/widget/gigs-board.pages.Post?id=1390">Hacker Stipend Guidelines</a>.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>Stay tuned in the coming weeks for details on NEARCON IRL Hackathon bounties.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="NEARCON 2023 - Official Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5zd2f-5Ob9Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-irl-hackathon-2023-build-the-open-web/">NEARCON IRL Hackathon 2023: Build the Open Web</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON: The Ultimate Web3 Education for Only $99!</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-the-ultimate-web3-education-for-only-99/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As NEAR’s flagship conference, NEARCON is the place to learn all of the latest on Web3 technologies and the open …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-the-ultimate-web3-education-for-only-99/">NEARCON: The Ultimate Web3 Education for Only $99!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As NEAR’s flagship conference, <a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index">NEARCON</a> is the place to learn all of the latest on Web3 technologies and the open web. <a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index">NEARCON 2023</a> will be the ultimate Web3 education — and for only $99.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s explore what you can expect from the NEARCON crash course — from recent Web3 developments in venture capital, decentralization, and AI to NEAR technologies like the Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S), and much more.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-you-ll-learn-at-nearcon-2023">What you’ll learn at NEARCON 2023</h2>



<p>The Web3 ecosystem consists of several key roles and sectors, and we’re lucky to have some of the biggest names attending NEARCON. Over 4 days, you will hear from venture capital figures like Samantha Bohbot (RockawayX) and Nathalie Oestmann (Outlier Ventures) as well as accelerator leaders like Nicolai Reinbold (CV Labs). There will also be a number of entrepreneurs and founders, including Michael Casey (CoinDesk), Alexander Skidanov (NEAR Protocol), Rebecca Allen (Contented), Dave Balter (Flipside Crypto), Aurelie Boiteux (Nansen), Mitchell Amador (Immunefi), Marc Goldich (Proximity Labs), and many others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Featured talks, panels, and discussions will include learnings on:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Open Web </strong>— Learn how open source technologies and ideals are colliding with blockchain technologies like NEAR to create an open web where everyone can be fairly rewarded for their data, ideas, and effort.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>AI &amp; Blockchain</strong> — Learn from the OG of AI himself, NEAR co-founder Illia Polosukhin, on how Blockchain and Artificial Intelligence are intersecting in 2023, and how they will develop in the near future.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Decentralization</strong> — See how the NDC (NEAR Digital Collective) is helping to decentralize governance to the NEAR community.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Regulation &amp; Policy</strong> — Get updated on the latest Web3 regulatory developments.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-your-web3-education-doesn-t-stop-at-nearcon-take-the-next-step">Your Web3 education doesn’t stop at NEARCON — take the next step</h2>



<p>If you love what you learn at NEARCON, you can keep going with your NEAR and open web education. The NEAR ecosystem offers a number of resources to help you find success in Web3.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks to the <a href="https://near.org/horizon">NEAR Horizon</a> team — who will be on hand at NEARCON — you can get help in your journey of building, getting funding, and networking as a Web3 builder, founder, and entrepreneur.&nbsp;</p>



<p>See you in Lisbon!</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index">Register</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-the-ultimate-web3-education-for-only-99/">NEARCON: The Ultimate Web3 Education for Only $99!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON 2023: Get Tickets, Get Involved, Join the Hackathon!</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-2023-get-tickets-get-involved-join-the-hackathon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20880</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEARCON 2023 “Step into the Open Web” may be a few months away but it’s fast approaching. Since kicking off …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-2023-get-tickets-get-involved-join-the-hackathon/">NEARCON 2023: Get Tickets, Get Involved, Join the Hackathon!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEARCON 2023 “Step into the Open Web” may be a few months away but it’s fast approaching. Since kicking off this year’s edition of NEARCON, the NEAR Foundation has been hard at work building an iconic experience for the NEAR ecosystem and community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This year, NEARCON has three venues, designed to optimize spaces for the hackathon and the talks and demos.  While we are still working out the details of the third venue, here are two confirmed venues:  </p>



<p><strong>NEARCON HQ<br></strong>Convento Do Beato<br>Alameda do Beato 40, 1950-042<br>Lisboa, Portugal</p>



<p><strong>Hacker HQ</strong><br>Armazem 16<br>R. Pereira Henriques nº1, 1950-242<br>Lisboa, Portugal</p>



<p>We’ve got some exciting updates on NEARCON tickets, speakers and sessions, the hackathon, and ways of getting involved in the conference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s take a look at all of the latest from NEARCON.<br><em>To stay tuned for all of the latest updates over the next few months, join the official </em><a href="https://t.me/nearcon"><em>NEARCON 2023 Telegram channel</em></a><em>, and drop into the spirit before the event.</em></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="NEARCON 2023: The Official Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qMrJheF0ZdE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-you-get-at-nearcon">What you get at NEARCON</h2>



<ul>
<li>Join 5,000+ delegates as the NEAR community explores the power and possibilities of an open web</li>



<li>Get inspired by talks from renowned authors, economists, artists, politicians, developers, entrepreneurs, and more</li>



<li>Explore the Blockchain Operating System (BOS), try it for yourself, and find out why it&#8217;s the driving force behind an open web</li>



<li>Connect with projects, speakers, community members, builders, and multi-chain enthusiasts from around the world</li>



<li>Hack the days and nights away for a chance to build on the BOS and win $180k</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-tickets-info-update">Tickets info update</h2>



<p>If you missed our early bird NEARCON 2023 tickets a few months ago, don’t worry! While your chance at free tickets has passed, you can still receive a special prize.<br>If you refer 4 friends when you <a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index?tab=register">register for NEARCON</a>, you will get a special prize at the conference. When your friends register for NEARCON, they must name you in the referral field. Friends can refer you all the way up to the first day of the conference. </p>



<p>Stay tuned to the Near.org/blog and NEAR Protocol Twitter account for updates on the prize.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-speakers-sessions">Speakers &amp; Sessions</h2>



<p>NEARCON will host a wide array of exciting speakers, including VCs, founders, developers, and many other notable ecosystem players. Here is a sneak peak at some of the 70+ confirmed speakers:&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Michael Casey — CoinDesk</li>



<li>Samantha Bohbot — RockawayX</li>



<li>Nicolai Reinbold — CV Labs</li>



<li>Nathalie Oestmann — Outlier Ventures</li>



<li>Alexander Skidanov — NEAR Protocol</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-nearcon-hackathon-build-a-multi-chain-open-web-future">NEARCON Hackathon: Build a multi-chain, open web future.</h2>



<p>Hackers know that NEAR and NEARCON love them. This year, any builder or developer who applies for the hackathon gets in for free.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The NEARCON hackathon is a 48-hour IRL hacking session for those looking to team up, familiarize themselves with NEAR, prototype their project, and pitch it —&nbsp;all for a chance to win.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The hackathon can be the start of something amazing —&nbsp;or a way to fail fast, learn, and adapt. We appreciate both, because we know that to build the next big thing you often have to fail enough times to find just the right idea.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-if-accepted-to-the-hackathon-hackers-will-receive">If accepted to the hackathon, hackers will receive:</h2>



<ul>
<li>FREE access to NEARCON</li>



<li>24/7 access to hack at the venue</li>



<li>Hands on mentoring</li>



<li>Participation stipend in NEAR</li>



<li>Chances to win amazing prizes!</li>
</ul>



<p>For consideration to hack and get a free NEARCON pass, please complete the <a href="https://nearcon-hackathon.devpost.com/">application form</a>. We’re working on the full list of bounties, partners, and opportunities, so stay tuned to the NEARCON hackathon page.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdncTzQkavACE1dmTJTZqWB1iOSpfYzGnof9pdNYjbmBhmgbQ/viewform">Request a visa letter</a> to support hackers’ visa applications.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-get-involved-with-nearcon">Get involved with NEARCON</h2>



<p>Last year, a number of partners helped support NEARCON, including TAP Air Portugal, Business Insider, Circle, The Graph, and others. There are various ways of getting involved, from digital marketing exposure and exclusive access to side events to major visibility at the conferences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Find what’s right for you. Take a look at how you can <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1P5q35REgAn7jnm61c25dLMuEynl4oI8N/view">get involved</a> at NEARCON 2023. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-step-into-the-open-web-and-register-for-nearcon">Step into the Open Web and register for NEARCON</h2>



<p>Join the NEAR ecosystem and community and step into the open web. Let’s build a new web together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;<a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index?tab=register">Register for NEARCON</a>.<br><br></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-2023-get-tickets-get-involved-join-the-hackathon/">NEARCON 2023: Get Tickets, Get Involved, Join the Hackathon!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON Returns: Here’s Everything You Need to Know So Far</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-returns-heres-everything-you-need-to-know-so-far/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 19:56:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON Early Bird Tickets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20642</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last year’s NEARCON was epic. NEARCON 2023 will be iconic.&#160; While all of you have been diligently building NEAR into …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-returns-heres-everything-you-need-to-know-so-far/">NEARCON Returns: Here’s Everything You Need to Know So Far</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last year’s NEARCON was epic. NEARCON 2023 will be iconic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While all of you have been diligently building NEAR into one of the best ecosystems in the blockchain world, NEAR Foundation has been planning a 4-day journey into an open web.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s take a quick look at everything we have to share (so far).&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-to-expect-at-nearcon-2023">What to expect at NEARCON 2023</h2>



<p>For this year’s NEARCON, we’re expanding. There will be two venues —&nbsp;NEARCON HQ and Hack HQ.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Most of the action will happen at NEARCON HQ. But if you’re a hacker, or just like hanging with them, you can do that at Hack HQ.</p>



<p>At NEARCON, you can expect to:</p>



<ul>
<li>Join 5,000+ delegates as we explore the power and possibilities of an open web</li>



<li>Encounter a diverse melting pot of creators, builders, policy makers, and more — you’ll even find the rare thought leader in their natural environment</li>



<li>Get inspired by talks from renowned authors, economists, artists, politicians, VCS, developers, entrepreneurs, and more</li>



<li>Explore the Blockchain Operating System (BOS), try it for yourself, and find out why it&#8217;s the driving force behind an open web&nbsp;</li>



<li>Connect with projects, speakers, community members, builders, and multi-chain enthusiasts from around the world</li>



<li>Hack the days and nights away for a chance to build on the BOS and win $180+k&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>



<li>And experience so much more that you&#8217;ll be looking around and asking yourself, “What bear market?”&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-get-your-early-bird-tickets-now">Get your early bird tickets now!</h2>



<p>NEARCON 2023 tickets are $20 off until July 1. So, don’t wait — snag your ticket for $79 now because after July 1st they are $99. </p>



<p>NEAR Foundation is also offering another deal. If you refer 4 friends to NEARCON 2023, you will get a special gift upon check-in at the conference.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-become-a-speaker-or-sponsor">Become a Speaker or Sponsor</h2>



<p>Thinking about becoming a NEARCON speaker? We’d love to hear from you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Speaking spots always go fast, so make haste. Apply to speak at NEARCON <a href="https://airtable.com/shru9TnZ53F7qZT9C">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Psstt… we&#8217;re looking for technical applications that don&#8217;t just shill but highlight problems being solved — on the BOS and the wider open web.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-apply-for-the-hackathon-and-get-in-for-free">Apply for the Hackathon and get in for free</h2>



<p>NEAR and NEARCON loves its hackers. And to show it, we’ve made it so that any builder or developer who applies for the hackathon gets in for free.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Find more information about the NEARCON 2023 hackathon <a href="https://nearcon-hackathon.devpost.com/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-returns-heres-everything-you-need-to-know-so-far/">NEARCON Returns: Here’s Everything You Need to Know So Far</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
