<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Community Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/community/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/community/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 18:59:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Community Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/community/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</title>
		<link>/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI is NEAR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hackathon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with Edge and Polygon Labs, the NEAR Foundation will co-sponsor a Decentralized AI Summit and “Autonomous Agent,” an …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/">Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In collaboration with Edge and Polygon Labs, the NEAR Foundation will co-sponsor a Decentralized AI <a href="https://lu.ma/fvoeazk8">Summit</a> and “Autonomous Agent,” an AI x Web3 <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/autonomous-agent-hackathon">Hackathon</a>, at ETHDenver on February 26 and 27. The events will bring together visionaries, developers, and enthusiasts working at the intersection of AI and Web3 along with a hackathon for builders and researchers to dive into the buzziest tech topic of today. Speakers at the Summit will include Vitalik Buterin of the Ethereum Foundation, Illia Polosukhin of NEAR Foundation, Sandeep Nailwal of Polygon Labs, and Sreeram Kannan of EigenLayer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Autonomous Agent” is the first event in the &#8220;{Chain}-of-Thought&#8221; series from <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/">Edge</a>, which will explore and harness the potential of Web3 and open source AI. Edge is a research and development organization dedicated to democratizing access to open intelligence and advancing the evolution of next-generation web architecture. Hackers can expect hands-on hacking sessions, workshops, and mentorship opportunities with a chance to learn from those at the cutting edge of decentralized AI development. </p>



<p>The intersection of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Web3 technology is poised to revolutionize industries, with many Web3 projects now incorporating AI into decentralized applications and developer tools. Ethereum Co-Founder Vitalik Buterin recently shared his <a href="https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2024/01/30/cryptoai.html">observations</a> about the intersection, and NEAR Co-Founder Illia Polosukhin shared how AI fits into the vision for the NEAR ecosystem in a recent <a href="/blog/self-sovereignty-is-near-a-vision-for-our-ecosystem/">post</a>. </p>



<p>As the risks from centralized AI controlled primarily by major corporations become more apparent, investing in open source, transparent AI development will become increasingly important––along with community building, governance experiments, and advocacy. “{Chain} of Thought” will lead the way in bringing members of the AI and Web3 ecosystems together to advance these initiatives and make concrete progress.</p>



<p>In addition to the premier sponsors, the “Autonomous Agent” hackathon is co-sponsored by <a href="https://www.eigenlayer.xyz/">EigenLayer</a>, <a href="https://www.gensyn.ai/">Gensyn</a>, and <a href="https://www.hyperoracle.io/">Hyper Oracle</a>, with co-hosting participation from Sentient, Lightspeed, and Symbolic Capital. Benefits of participation include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Cutting-Edge Workshops:</strong> Engage with industry experts and thought leaders through immersive workshops exploring the latest trends and technologies in AI x Web3.</li>



<li><strong>Hackathon Challenges:</strong> Tackle real-world challenges and showcase your creativity by developing innovative solutions at the forefront of AI and Web3 integration.</li>



<li><strong>Networking Opportunities:</strong> Connect with like-minded individuals, potential collaborators, and industry professionals to expand your network and exchange ideas.</li>



<li><strong>Prizes and Recognition:</strong> Compete for exciting prizes and gain recognition for your contributions to the advancement of AI x Web3 technology.</li>
</ul>



<p>Join NEAR Foundation, Polygon Labs, and Edge in Denver and be a part of the next great tech revolution. Those interested in attending the Decentralized AI Summit can register <a href="https://lu.ma/fvoeazk8">here</a>. Researchers, developers, and hackers interested in participating in the <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/autonomous-agent-hackathon">hackathon</a> can apply <a href="https://lu.ma/k6dw9jk2">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/">Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Built on NEAR: Celebrating Partners and Innovators at NEARCON &#8217;23</title>
		<link>/blog/built-on-near-celebrating-partners-and-innovators-at-nearcon-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 15:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Partnerships are one of the biggest pillars to expanding NEAR’s footprint. They help drive the ecosystem toward fostering new and …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/built-on-near-celebrating-partners-and-innovators-at-nearcon-23/">Built on NEAR: Celebrating Partners and Innovators at NEARCON &#8217;23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Partnerships are one of the biggest pillars to expanding NEAR’s footprint. They help drive the ecosystem toward fostering new and innovative use cases that will bring the next billion users to the open web. And that&#8217;s exactly what&#8217;s happening on NEAR, with partnerships ranging from sports to social taking center stage. At NEARCON&nbsp;— <a href="https://near.org/blog/nearcon-the-ultimate-web3-education-for-only-99">the ultimate Web3 education</a> — a number of NEAR partners will be on-hand to talk about Web3 partnerships and innovation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Throughout the past few years, NEAR has engaged, collaborated, and built with partners who share the vision of a decentralized, user-centric open web. Each partnership is contributing their unique, innovative flair to the ecosystem, with a scalable, user-friendly blockchain helping to propel their efforts.</p>



<p>As NEARCON ‘23 approaches, let’s celebrate and explore how NEAR&#8217;s collaborations and partnerships are shaping the future of the open web. By registering for and attending NEARCON ‘23, you’ll be able to meet some of the following founders, entrepreneurs, and innovators below.</p>



<p>And these names are just the tip of the iceberg, so don’t forget to register for NEARCON ‘23 and let’s take part in learning, networking, and building an open web together.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://nearcon.app/">Register $99</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-creating-consumer-fun-and-engagement-in-the-open-web">Creating consumer fun and engagement in the open web</h2>



<p>An area where NEAR partnerships are thriving is making the blockchain more fun and engaging for the masses. NEAR’s partnership with NFT launchpad <a href="https://www.mintbase.xyz/">Mintbase</a> is a perfect illustration. Mintbase recently celebrated the traditional Indian festival, Raksha Bandhan, by seamlessly <a href="/blog/mintbase-brings-new-open-web-wallet-tech-to-families-celebrating-raksha-bandhan/">transforming photos into NFTs</a> on the NEAR blockchain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During Raksha Bandan, sisters tie a good-luck talisman around the wrists of their brothers, a special moment often photographed and cherished by families. With Mintbase’s open web wallet built on NEAR, users could easily create an account without seed phrases and seamlessly upload their photos, transforming them into NFTs in an instant.</p>



<p>Let’s also toast to&nbsp; <a href="http://www.glass.fun/">GLASS</a>, a one-of-a-kind Web3 platform that empowers alcohol brands to engage directly with consumers. Built on the NEAR blockchain, spirit brands can <a href="/blog/how-glass-is-uncorking-adult-beverage-loyalty-with-web3-and-near/">issue token rewards</a> and other blockchain perks to social drinkers who try new cocktail recipes, socialize with friends, and vote on brand decisions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gaming is also a key entry point into the open web, and NEAR&#8217;s partnership with <a href="https://playember.com/">PlayEmber</a> is kicking the door wide open. PlayEmber’s creative gaming studio is fusing AAA quality mobile games on the blockchain, with NEAR providing the backend foundation. Decentralized mobile gaming experiences are now becoming more accessible to a wider audience.</p>



<p>Then there’s <a href="https://cosmose.co/">Cosmose AI&#8217;s</a> KaiKai, a fusion of shopping, retail, and gamification dubbed&#8221;Shoppertainment.&#8221; Built on NEAR’s Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S), <a href="/blog/cosmose-and-near-foundation-set-to-revolutionize-retail-with-web3-and-ai/?_gl=1%2A1yt7etu%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2ANjE0MjI4NTkyLjE2OTcwMzUyNTQ.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5NzAzNTI1Mi4xLjAuMTY5NzAzNTI1Mi4wLjAuMA..">KaiKai offers a captivating brand discovery</a> avenue, with features like Augmented Reality (AR) product interactions, exclusive product drops, and celebrity live streams.&nbsp;</p>



<p>More than just a shopping app, KaiKai also uses a native cryptocurrency, Kai-Ching. Shoppers earn rewards with the help of Cosmose&#8217;s AI-powered personalization, all while transacting on the NEAR blockchain. It’s all about enhancing personalization, user empowerment, and engagements in the retail space with a unique, powerful blockchain twist.</p>



<p>And in a fusion of health and blockchain, <a href="https://sweatco.in/">Sweatcoin’s</a> partnership with NEAR helps people earn SWEAT tokens with literally every step towards better fitness. With a user base of over 63 million who&#8217;ve clocked in more than 19 trillion steps, Sweatcoin and NEAR are incentivizing&nbsp; healthier lifestyles.</p>



<p>Oleg Fomenko, co-founder of Sweatcoin, believes in the <a href="https://near.org/blog/sweatcoin-partners-with-near-foundation-to-create-a-new-movement-economy">potential of merging health and blockchain</a>, enabling users to “walk into the world of crypto.” This partnership, built on the NEAR blockchain, personifies the next level of open web adoption, encouraging physical wellness via crypto-based rewards.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-financial-empowerment-and-innovation-on-near">Financial empowerment and innovation on NEAR</h2>



<p>One of the biggest challenges that the open web is addressing is financial empowerment and inclusion. NEAR Foundation’s partnerships in this area are helping bring that vision to life. The Foundation’s collaboration with Proximity Labs is helping talented builders create innovative Web3 financial solutions, with substantial grants and support.</p>



<p>Calimero Network is another example of NEAR&#8217;s commitment to financial innovation. Calimero provides what’s called ‘private sharding’ infrastructure, a feature that ensures&nbsp; data privacy in Web3 finance without sacrificing the power of open-source platforms. With both <a href="https://www.theblock.co/post/204235/private-sharding-startup-calimero-network-raises-8-5-million">financial and technical support from NEAR</a>, more business can be safely conducted on the blockchain.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-building-the-technical-foundation-for-tomorrow-s-open-web">Building the technical foundation for tomorrow’s open web</h2>



<p>The ongoing partnership between NEAR Protocol and <a href="https://oct.network/">Octopus Network</a> signifies the ecosystem’s infrastructure strides. Early on, Octopus Network selected NEAR as its “mother-chain” protocol citing speed ability to accommodate a large user base. Octopus Network and NEAR are paving the way for developers aiming to launch tailored applications using their own dedicated blockchains —&nbsp;also known as “Appchains” —&nbsp;making deployment a breeze.</p>



<p>Partnering with a tech infrastructure behemoth like <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/startups/near-building-useable-web3-infrastructure-on-google-cloud">Google Cloud</a> is another way of giving Web3 startups pathways to world-class startup expertise. It’s all part of NEAR’s commitment to making blockchain solutions more accessible, robust, and primed for mainstream adoption.</p>



<p>In collaboration with <a href="https://urbit.org/">Urbit</a>, NEAR is also continuing to make the open web more user friendly. Urbit’s vision — shared and supported by the NEAR Foundation — is to improve the frontend experience of open web apps. Urbit allows developers to easily create sleek designs so that tomorrow’s decentralized applications are as seamless as the most popular ones in the App Store.</p>



<p>On another front, NEAR&#8217;s collaboration with <a href="https://sailgp.com/">SailGP</a> is bringing Decentralized Autonomous Organizations (DAOs) to professional sports, creating a bridge between leagues and fans. The introduction of a DAO-owned racing team on the NEAR Protocol gives fans a novel way to engage, interact with, and participate in active decision making along with teams and athletes.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-partnership-innovation-rolls-on-at-nearcon">Partnership innovation rolls on at NEARCON</h2>



<p>Past, current, and future partnership will take center stage at NEARCON 2023 — now less than a month away. It’ll be four full days of full immersion into the NEAR ecosystem —&nbsp;a place for you to truly step into the open web. Build on the B.O.S and network with thousands of other blockchain enthusiasts. Get the inside scoop on onboarding Web2 companies into Web3 with Google Cloud’s James Tromans, and get the low down on SWEAT with Oleg Fomenko.</p>



<p>From raising a glass to blockchain brand loyalty with GLASS and setting sail towards new DAO horizons with SailGP, each and every NEAR partner is playing its own pivotal role in crafting how tomorrow’s open web experiences will look, feel, and even taste. Better decentralized infrastructure, financial empowerment, and exciting consumer experiences are just the start.</p>



<p><em>Ready to dive into sessions, hackathons, and more in Lisbon at NEARCON 2023? Go ahead and </em><a href="https://tickets.nearcon.org/"><em>register now</em></a><em> to secure your spot.</em></p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://nearcon.app/">Register $99</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/built-on-near-celebrating-partners-and-innovators-at-nearcon-23/">Built on NEAR: Celebrating Partners and Innovators at NEARCON &#8217;23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ICYMI: Scootering Through Web3 at NEAR APAC&#8217;s Vietnam Showcase </title>
		<link>/blog/icymi-scootering-through-web3-at-near-apacs-vietnam-showcase/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 16:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain Operating System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR APAC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It was an incredible first-ever NEAR APAC, with the NEAR ecosystem scootering through Saigon over the last two days. Vietnam …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/icymi-scootering-through-web3-at-near-apacs-vietnam-showcase/">ICYMI: Scootering Through Web3 at NEAR APAC&#8217;s Vietnam Showcase </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It was an incredible first-ever <a href="https://nearapac.org/">NEAR APAC</a>, with the NEAR ecosystem scootering through Saigon over the last two days. Vietnam served as the perfect backdrop for NEAR’s inaugural showcase in Asia-Pacific, with community members, B.O.S. builders, and general Web3 enthusiasts coming together in one of the region&#8217;s most dynamic countries.</p>



<p>The event was spearheaded by the <a href="https://nearvietnamhub.org/">NEAR Vietnam Hub</a> with support from the NEAR Foundation, exemplifying strong commitment and collaboration between local and global ecosystem stakeholders.&nbsp; ICYMI, here are some of the biggest sessions, announcements, and events from NEAR APAC 2023.</p>



<p>ICYMI, here are some of the biggest sessions, announcements, and events from NEAR APAC 2023.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-web3-s-bright-investment-outlook-in-asia-pacific">Web3’s bright investment outlook in Asia-Pacific</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="681" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0065-1024x681.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20876" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0065-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0065-300x200.jpg 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0065-768x511.jpg 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0065-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0065-2048x1363.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>One of the most encouraging and optimistic sessions was moderated by NEAR’s Head of Finance, David Norris, focusing on the current and future outlook of blockchain investment and development in the region. David was joined by Web3 venture veterans Riccardo Pagano from <a href="https://outlierventures.io/">Outlier Ventures</a> and Whiplus Wang of <a href="https://www.ivcrypto.io/">IVC crypto</a>.</p>



<p>The trio dove into the current state of blockchain investment in APAC, and how Web3 might just ascend to becoming one of the most invested sectors in the region from a venture and infrastructure perspective. Ricardo in particular emphasized that he’s seeing a shift in perception from investors, with Web3 going from a niche technology to its own broad-based sector.</p>



<p>“Even though we’re technically in a bear market, investment in Web3 sub-sectors like gaming is still strong,” added Whiplus. “Games like<em> Angry Birds </em>and <em>Fruit Ninja</em> were instrumental in onboarding Web2 users onto the smartphone, for example. That’s why investment into blockchain game publishers is increasing — to find that killer game that onboards billions.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="681" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0058-1024x681.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20874" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0058-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0058-300x200.jpg 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0058-768x511.jpg 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0058-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0058-2048x1363.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Whiplus also likened successful blockchain startups to a bowl of Pho, with a blend of technical and business elements being integral to a delicious final dish. The panel also touched on technical nuances like ZK rollups and modular blockchains, emphasizing the need to invest in talent and innovation through initiatives like hackathons.</p>



<p>The session encapsulated a forward-looking perspective on Web3&#8217;s trajectory. With the bar for founder participation evidently rising, the panel stressed the importance of education in the space. There was unanimous optimism about Southeast Asia&#8217;s digital future as potentially outpacing even established tech hubs like Korea and Japan.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-supports-b-o-s-and-blockchain-builders-in-apac">NEAR supports B.O.S. and blockchain builders in APAC</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_0011-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20871" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_0011-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_0011-300x200.jpg 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_0011-768x512.jpg 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_0011-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_0011-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Tons of activity also took place in and around the Builder Stage, with the NEAR Foundation and local blockchain organizations teaming up to educate and assist developers, builders, and job seekers in advancing themselves into Web3. Cameron Dennis, CEO of <a href="https://www.banyan.gg/">Banyan</a>, led a panel on the stage informing developers on how to upskill from Web2 to Web3.</p>



<p>Local developer advocates from notable projects like the Graph and Khyber network also participated in sessions, workshops, and panels on the Builder Stage designed to upskill local blockchain professionals. There was something for everyone, from a job fair for Web3 newbies to a Greenhouse area connecting founders and projects to VCs for funding.</p>



<p>Exploring everything from dApp architecture to tokenomics, the Builder Stage action was highlighted by an incredible Hackathon, with participants receiving guidance from experts like Oleg Fomenko, founder of <a href="https://sweateconomy.com/">SWEAT</a>. On the final night of the festivities, NEAR co-founder Illia Polosukhin presented awards to the winners on stage in front of a packed main hall.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-pagoda-takes-the-main-stage-to-talk-user-adoption-and-fastauth">Pagoda takes the main stage to talk user adoption and FastAuth</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_9815-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20873" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_9815-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_9815-300x200.jpg 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_9815-768x512.jpg 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_9815-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/QUR_9815-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Alex Chiocchi, the CPO of <a href="https://www.pagoda.co/">Pagoda</a>, showcased FastAuth during his session titled &#8220;Unlocking the Power of B.O.S: Product Update for Founders &amp; Developers.&#8221; FastAuth aims to redefine the user experience for developers and founders, addressing the longstanding challenges of both onboarding and retaining new Web3 users.</p>



<p>A primary takeaway was how FastAuth’s next release will minimize gas fees when onboarding, thus removing barriers for end-users. The introduction of multiparty compute (MPC) allows proofs from various organizations to be combined, simplifying processes like email recovery. Chiocchi emphasized the potential for users to migrate effortlessly from Web2 logins, hinting at a seamless integration between the two web generations.</p>



<p>Discussing the nuances of retaining users in Web3, Chiocchi stressed that coin incentives alone aren&#8217;t sufficient. The &#8220;toothbrush test&#8221; was highlighted, illustrating that many apps don&#8217;t become daily necessities for users. Trust plays a pivotal role, especially with the rise of scams in the decentralized space.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-side-events-and-after-parties-storm-the-streets-of-saigon">Side events and after-parties storm the streets of Saigon</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="681" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0824-1024x681.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20872" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0824-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0824-300x200.jpg 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0824-768x511.jpg 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0824-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0824-2048x1363.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>NEAR APAC fully embraced the “work hard, play hard” ethos of Vietnam and Asia-Pacific. Even during the event, there were LED dancers, Manga Cosplay, and several massive DJs and party breaks. Not to mention the NEAR APAC Opening Night party at the Intercontinental Hotel, where Illia officially welcomed attendees and kicked things off in an intimate setting.</p>



<p>And in one of the coolest side events in recent NEAR memory, Dap Dap showcased its platform to B.O.S. enthusiasts at the My House meeting venue nestled in one of Saigon’s many cozily-lit alleyways. Dap Dap is the first commercial B.O.S. product and will act as a gateway to hundreds of chains and protocols for users from a single, user-friendly interface.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="681" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0845-1024x681.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20875" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0845-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0845-300x200.jpg 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0845-768x511.jpg 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0845-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/MIH_0845-2048x1363.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>B.O.S Beats by <a href="https://www.daorecords.org/">DAO Records</a> was the grand finale of NEAR APAC, offering a vibrant blend of hip-hop beats from prominent DJs on the decentralized record label. Held at Indika Saigon — and with pizza supplied by Pizza DAO — attendees enjoyed live performances, refreshments, and networking opportunities with the global and APAC NEAR communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEAR APAC was an incredible Web3 Bánh Mì, layering an eclectic mix of speakers, insights, and events to create something completely unique. The NEAR Foundation would like to thank every cook in the kitchen, especially local partners like the NEAR Vietnam Hub who made sure that the first ever NEAR APAC had the perfect mix of sweet, sour, and spicy.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/icymi-scootering-through-web3-at-near-apacs-vietnam-showcase/">ICYMI: Scootering Through Web3 at NEAR APAC&#8217;s Vietnam Showcase </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR APAC Day 2 Recap: Asia Gaming Trends, Interoperability, and Web3 for Brands</title>
		<link>/blog/near-apac-day-2-recap-asia-gaming-trends-interoperability-and-web3-for-brands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 14:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR APAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3 Gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It would&#8217;ve been hard to imagine topping a jam-packed Day 1 of NEAR APAC, but Day 2 managed to do …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-apac-day-2-recap-asia-gaming-trends-interoperability-and-web3-for-brands/">NEAR APAC Day 2 Recap: Asia Gaming Trends, Interoperability, and Web3 for Brands</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It would&#8217;ve been hard to imagine topping a jam-packed Day 1 of NEAR APAC, but Day 2 managed to do just that. The gorgeous Sunday in Saigon covered a wide range of topics, including significant discussions on the future trends in Web3 such as how brands can hop on board the Web3 bandwagon and a creative proposal to unite all Layer 1&#8217;s for mass adoption.</p>



<p>With each session, industry leaders shed light on challenges and the future trajectory of the fast-paced Web3 ecosystem in APAC. From the unique positioning of Web3 gaming in Asia to the potential rise of the next Web3 cycle, the discussions were varied and far-reaching. Let&#8217;s dive on into all the Day 2 happenings at NEAR APAC in Vietnam!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-apac-experts-discuss-the-next-big-trends-in-web3">APAC experts discuss the next big trends in Web3</h2>



<p>Let’s begin the Day Two recap with a standout panel diving into the next big Web3 trends. Experts agreed that it won’t just be about technological progress, but also the transformative ways that blockchain will weave into daily life. Asset tokenization, generative AI integration, and the proliferation of decentralized creator economies were some top trends on the table.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/RgVgqs1g0x-gnx5Kvaa6mVPfaIXaZxyV1m_WAE0Ce6zUb-OKD6-LI066PiE1II_S3T9bDYSHDGyGVyG5Np03ekD10YSpe6r5bbN36500oObHLrOGuQD3Q2W_po-e_vF-tBOVuvLoBIHvgM0lZiJPI5I" alt=""/></figure>



<p>“Generative AI and asset tokenization are revolutionizing Web3 ecosystems, especially in growing economies like India,” said Sudeep Choudhari, head of blockchain at the <a href="https://www.npci.org.in/">India National Payments Corporation</a>. “As integration across borders accelerates, we’ll also challenge traditional FX rates, anticipating a future with minimal cross-border payment costs.&#8221;</p>



<p>Hanna Tantoco, APAC Marketing Director at <a href="https://www.blockdaemon.com/">Blockdaemon</a>, piggybacked on the transformative role of generative AI in enhancing blockchain user experiences. She also pointed out the rising prominence of gaming in Asia, particularly on NEAR. Additionally, she highlighted Singapore&#8217;s burgeoning creator economy, powered largely by NFTs, as another future trend.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-brands-can-futureproof-themselves-with-blockchain">How brands can futureproof themselves with blockchain</h2>



<p>Another morning highlight was a panel discussion about how brands and enterprises can harness the potential of Web3 to adapt and thrive. Key points revolved around democratizing user data control, countering data monopolization by tech giants, tokenizing assets, and challenges in linking the physical and digital worlds.</p>



<p>“Enterprises often face challenges with hiring experts who may quickly move on to other projects,” observed Oleg Fomenko, founder of <a href="https://sweatco.in/">SWEAT</a>. “While consultancies can provide insights, the real breakthrough comes when you start building and experimenting with MVPs. Though initial attempts might fall short, perseverance can yield surprising results.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/Sd5LLo5KtoZlpO890p-2gemKPglzS_SZ4oWvR0pbA9WS1QOKwX-KJJCRBvObEAfU2shd5zUxumyCybxoyQT6OLdB_TbzLsOY6X-xrcfjVbRwp3UzXdhEFaVVk1sCFuO3x0PIQJ2xxlqQdk9SjCmrKVw" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Alex Chiocchi, CPO of <a href="https://www.pagoda.co/">Pagoda</a>, added that Web3 streamlines verification, challenging traditional ad networks. By using an open blockchain system, excessive fees are prevented, promoting shared value with users. This shift allows benefits like self-custody and reputation while redistributing margins back to the people.</p>



<p>Among the key takeaways from the session was that businesses harnessing blockchain&#8217;s capabilities can anticipate a transformative impact on the global economy, especially with asset tokenization&#8217;s projected growth through 2030. As brands navigate challenges like ensuring digital authenticity and early adoption, having a targeted strategy is crucial.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-web3-gaming-asia-s-landscape-and-blockchain-utilization">Web3 gaming: Asia&#8217;s landscape and blockchain utilization</h2>



<p>The Asian gaming landscape is buzzing with the rise of Web3 development, promising an unprecedented era of innovation and user empowerment. Central to discussions at the &#8220;Web3 Gaming: Asia Landscape&#8221; session was the gaming community&#8217;s appetite for asset and data ownership, often prioritizing this over the complexities of Web3 itself.</p>



<p>After attending Korea Blockchain Week, it&#8217;s evident that Japan and Korea&#8217;s mobile giants are pioneering in Web3 gaming,” said Luke Xie, founder of gaming VC fund <a href="https://pressstart.capital/">Press Start Capital</a>. “As opposed to Web3 games like Axie, creating AAA games takes much longer. Given the rapid pace of crypto, former mobile developers align better with this fast-paced dynamic.”</p>



<p>Ishank Gupta, co-founder of <a href="https://www.kratosstudios.io/">Kratos Studios</a> in India, emphasized that gamers prioritize asset and data ownership over backend Web3 tech. He predicted that blockchain games should bring benefits that gamers care about with a focus on ease of usability. For instance, leading studios in India are integrating well-known IP into Web3 games while ensuring they remain engaging.</p>



<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re witnessing a new golden age of gaming driven by indie studios,” added Xie. “Small teams, empowered by AI, are crafting games that punch above their weight. We believe that on-chain gaming, while difficult to execute at present, is the future. It’s all about selecting the right chain based on tech, community, and support. NEAR excels at all of the above.”</p>



<p>The panel agreed that the Web3 gaming industry in APAC and beyond is undergoing a transformative phase, with blockchain offering gamers more control over assets and data. As developers continue to build, the focus will be on seamless onboarding, speed, and user-centric experiences. Blockchains should be subtly integrated without disrupting the gaming experience.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-bringing-web3-together-with-multichain-a-call-for-collaboration">Bringing Web3 together with Multichain: a call for collaboration&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Today’s blockchain landscape consists of independent Layer 1’s vying for supremacy, bringing up the core question of interoperability. With users often navigating several ecosystems, creating cross-chain experiences becomes paramount. This star-studded panel explored new frameworks to address hurdles and challenges in the current siloed multi-chain user experience.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/photo_2023-09-10-21.14.09-1024x768.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-20842" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/photo_2023-09-10-21.14.09-1024x768.jpeg 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/photo_2023-09-10-21.14.09-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/photo_2023-09-10-21.14.09-768x576.jpeg 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/photo_2023-09-10-21.14.09.jpeg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>“Web3&#8217;s ethos is modularity, similar to Lego blocks,” explained NEAR CEO Marike Flament. “While we prioritize access and user growth, interoperability challenges persist. But trust and unified solutions drive adoption, not a fractured approach. It&#8217;s essential that technology seamlessly serves the end user.”</p>



<p>Cameron Dennis, CEO of <a href="https://www.banyan.gg/">Banyan</a>, added that key management is a critical issue. He pointed out ways to simplify these processes with tools like <a href="https://wiki.near.org/overview/BOS/fast-auth">FastAuth</a>. Dennis added that addressing the noticeable gap in cross-chain liquidity should be a focus. He believes that a true multichain future that drives adoption will solve key and wallet management for a better UX.</p>



<p>“Reflecting on a decade in this space, the competitive landscape has shifted,” mused Mary Beth Buchanan from the Cardano Foundation who is also an advisor to NEAR, “Earlier, exchanges hesitated to collaborate, fearing a loss of advantage. Today, there&#8217;s a collective push to learn from one another, ensuring technology works seamlessly for the end user.”</p>



<p>Cameron believes that reinforcing the current ecosystem is paramount before extending cross-chain efforts, even though creating a decentralized internet remains a resource-intensive endeavor.</p>



<p>Marieke stressed the importance of open-source technology in attracting top talent. Drawing inspiration from Web2&#8217;s approach to 5G standardization, she suggested that Layer 1 leaders could unite in an &#8216;L20&#8217; alliance to champion unified standards, fostering a unified vision for the industry&#8217;s future.</p>



<p>And that’s a wrap for the official Day 2 sessions at NEAR APAC. From gaming and brand adoption to multi-chain standards and collaboration, it was clear that this first-of-its-kind regional event was a rousing success for developers and the NEAR community alike. Sunday in Saigon rolls on with more side events and after-parties, so stay tuned for the full ICYMI tomorrow.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-apac-day-2-recap-asia-gaming-trends-interoperability-and-web3-for-brands/">NEAR APAC Day 2 Recap: Asia Gaming Trends, Interoperability, and Web3 for Brands</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR APAC Day One: Scaling Local Adoption, Regional Regulation, and AI in Web3</title>
		<link>/blog/near-apac-day-one-scaling-local-adoption-regional-regulation-and-ai-in-focus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 12:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer relations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR APAC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After many months in the making, the inaugural NEAR APAC conference kicked off today in Ho Chi Min City, Vietnam. …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-apac-day-one-scaling-local-adoption-regional-regulation-and-ai-in-focus/">NEAR APAC Day One: Scaling Local Adoption, Regional Regulation, and AI in Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After many months in the making, the inaugural NEAR APAC conference kicked off today in Ho Chi Min City, Vietnam. Held in conjunction with the <a href="https://nearvietnamhub.org/">NEAR Vietnam community</a> and NEAR Foundation, NEAR APAC is showcasing the vibrant crypto and Web3 community across the region as well as the potential of the B.O.S. and Open Web both locally and globally.</p>



<p>The day was charged with excitement, drawing over 8,000 attendees from various corners of the APAC region and beyond. With Web3 thought leaders, innovators, and enthusiasts converging in Vietnam, Day One of NEAR APAC kicked off with a slew of riveting discussions, industry insights, and speculations on the future of the Open Web with a focus on APAC.</p>



<p>From discussions around regional growth and investment potential to how AI and blockchain will transform the future of work, here’s everything that went down at an incredible start to NEAR APAC.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-setting-the-stage-for-near-apac-with-vietnam-in-focus">Setting the stage for NEAR APAC with Vietnam in focus</h2>



<p>The event kicked off with a focus on southeast Asia, with NEAR’s Vietnam country director Riley Tran welcoming attendees and providing context as to Asia’s critical role in the overarching development and expansion of Web3. Tran was followed by two NEAR luminaries, CEO Marieke Flament and co-founder Illia Polosukhin.</p>



<p>&#8220;Asia&#8217;s young demographics and rapid digital growth, especially in Vietnam, position it as a leader in crypto and blockchain growth,” Riley explained. “With over 100 million new internet users in just three years, Asia&#8217;s momentum in Web3 is accelerating”</p>



<p>Marieke added that the overall NEAR ecosystem remains strong with over 29M active wallets and 650K daily active accounts. She added that a collaborative approach to building tomorrow’s Open Web is critical for tackling significant societal and digital challenges.<br><br>&#8220;Today’s Web 2.0 is closed and siloed, with the prevailing digital culture being a toxic dialectic,&#8221; Marieke expressed. “But the value loop of an Open Web holds immense promise. We’re already seeing how projects like KaiKai, SWEAT, and PlayEmber can move the needle in the right direction.&#8221;</p>



<p>Echoing Mariek’s sentiment, Illia emphasized that it’s not necessarily about championing a specific blockchain, but about creating a common layer and interface for the Open Web. This is precisely what the Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S.) is in the process of achieving.</p>



<p>&#8220;Looking forward, tech isn&#8217;t the only focus,” said Illia. “It&#8217;s about blending scalable solutions with user-centric experiences, with the B.O.S. becoming the essential entry point into Web3 for both users and developers.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-asia-s-role-in-mainstream-adoption-and-regulatory-hurdles">Asia’s role in mainstream adoption and regulatory hurdles</h2>



<p>The push for mainstream blockchain adoption in APAC was also in focus on Day One, with NEAR Foundation CMO Jack Collier leading a panel discussion on current adoption challenges and how APAC can potentially lead the way in overcoming them.</p>



<p>“I’m extremely bullish on gaming as a key part of mass adoption,” opined Don Pham, Google Cloud’s regional Web3 specialist. “Vietnam is the birthplace of Axie Infinity, which is just the beginning of blockchain gaming’s potential. Use cases like loyalty, gaming, and music NFTs combined with better UX will likely be the path forward.”</p>



<p>The discussion dove deeper into the importance of user experience in the adoption of blockchain. Marieke reiterated that while technology forms the backbone, the real test will be simplifying the user journey, which can significantly hasten adoption across the APAC region as well as globally.</p>



<p>Regulation was also in focus with a panel about blockchain policies and APAC&#8217;s vision for governments and associations. Mary Beth Buchanan, a board member of the Cardano Foundation, drove home the need for regulatory clarity while discussing regional frameworks in countries like Hong Kong.</p>



<p>“The biggest challenge is not necessarily regulation, but lack of clarity,” observed Buchanan. “If regulations are unclear that will cause investors not to want to invest in the space. Builders become hesitant to build and users aren’t going to know what the rules are. Regulators need to recognize that clarity is what everyone wants.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-spotlight-on-artificial-intelligence-during-the-afternoon-sessions">Spotlight on Artificial Intelligence during the afternoon sessions</h2>



<p>Day One of NEAR APAC dedicated a significant chunk of its schedule to exploring the intricate interplay between AI and blockchain, particularly their role in APAC’s future technology and Web3 landscape. Illia took the stage just after the lunch break to discuss the Convergence of AI and Web3, diving deep into AI-empowered DAO and the future of AI-assisted work.</p>



<p>“While technologies like ChatGPT have found product market fit, much of AI is still siloed and doesn’t empower open source communities and projects,” Illia posited. “Web3 can operate in the middle, with AI models incorporating all participants and data sources. DAOs, for example, can be co-piloted by AI to achieve goals and KPIs faster and more efficiently.”</p>



<p>In the following panel discussion entitled “The Roles of Blockchains in an AI World,” Illia was joined by several AI and blockchain experts from the APAC region. One of the more distinguished panel members was Dr. Nguyen An Khuong, a lecturer and blockchain researcher from Ho Chi Minh University of Technology, who provided an academic perspective.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We have a lot of research endeavors in Vietnam around ensuring AI&#8217;s ethical applications using blockchain,” commented Dr. Nguyen. “We’re looking at how transparency and accountability in AI decisions can be drastically improved with blockchain technology. Combining a neutral AI with a blockchain’s public ledger could enhance the ecosystem and foster wider adoption.”</p>



<p>Illia drove home that the potential “Skynet” scenario of AI taking over the world is mostly a projection of what humans might do if they were given supercomputing powers. In reality, developments like the B.O.S. and NEAR Tasks will aid humans in success and productivity, with AI agents acting as middlemen for assistance, sourcing, and even creativity.</p>



<p>Day One of the first-ever NEAR APAC was a rousing success, with these highlights just being the tip of the iceberg. The crowd was treated to bánh mì’s and Manga cosplay during lunch, B.O.S. building and gaming workshops on the Builder Stage, and an awe-inspiring NFT gallery from APAC creators.</p>



<p>As the sun sets in Saigon, the NEAR Foundation couldn’t be more appreciative of the Vietnamese crypto community. The momentum rolls on tomorrow with Day Two, so stay tuned for more updates and insights around emerging APAC trends in Web3, how blockchain gaming is taking off in Asia-Pacific, and local DeFi developments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If Day One was any indication, the NEAR community’s growth, presence, and development in APAC will only continue accelerating through 2023 and beyond!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-apac-day-one-scaling-local-adoption-regional-regulation-and-ai-in-focus/">NEAR APAC Day One: Scaling Local Adoption, Regional Regulation, and AI in Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Update on the Grassroots Support Initiative</title>
		<link>/blog/update-on-the-grassroots-support-initiative/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 16:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grassroots Support Initiative]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20816</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the things the NEAR Foundation has always been most proud of is the passion and enthusiasm of our …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/update-on-the-grassroots-support-initiative/">Update on the Grassroots Support Initiative</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>One of the things the NEAR Foundation has always been most proud of is the passion and enthusiasm of our builders and grassroots projects — something we have seen demonstrated again since the <a href="/blog/an-update-on-the-ndc-funding-and-support-for-grassroots-projects/?_gl=1%2A1nhhje7%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTE0NTY2MjU3OS4xNjkyOTY4MDg2%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5Mjk2ODA4NC4xLjAuMTY5Mjk2ODA4NC4wLjAuMA..">recent post</a> about the NDC. Over the past week alone, over 30 projects have reached out to the Ecosystem Team and a number of conversations are already underway. This has allowed NEAR Foundation to begin mapping out current needs, and understand the best way to provide support that will ensure the NEAR ecosystem remains a vibrant, open, and accessible place to build.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For us at the Foundation, hearing directly from builders provides invaluable insight into the state of the ecosystem and how we can best continue to support the people and projects that make it what it is. What we have heard so far is that while financial support is important as the NDC fully ramps up, every project has a unique set of needs that requires a holistic approach to provide the right support, and that simply re-starting a grants program is not the right solution. To make sure that we get as many perspectives from across the ecosystem, we will be leaving the form open for one more week (until September 4th) to give anyone who needs support a chance to have their voice heard.</p>



<p>Once the form is closed and we have had a chance to review all of the inputs, we will then begin setting out a broader plan — in alignment with the NDC —&nbsp;to ensure projects get the support they need as we continue moving forward on the path to decentralization. The moment we have the full insights from these conversations, which should be within the next few weeks, we will share them in a follow-up blog post along with a clear plan on how we will be moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are excited to have so much interest from builders, and look forward to creating a plan that can help keep grassroots projects engaged and building.</p>



<p>You can sign up for a time to speak with the Ecosystem Relations Team <a href="https://airtable.com/app5mCfwTVtmOhfHW/shrbpLz5XQHqrt4rQ">here</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/update-on-the-grassroots-support-initiative/">Update on the Grassroots Support Initiative</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR at ETHCC Highlights: Sustainability and the BOS Take Center Stage in Paris</title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-ethcc-highlights-sustainability-and-the-bos-take-center-stage-in-paris/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Missed out on NEAR’s rendezvous at ETHCC 2023 in Paris? No need to worry. In this roundup, all NEAR enthusiasts …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-highlights-sustainability-and-the-bos-take-center-stage-in-paris/">NEAR at ETHCC Highlights: Sustainability and the BOS Take Center Stage in Paris</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Missed out on NEAR’s rendezvous at ETHCC 2023 in Paris? No need to worry. In this roundup, all NEAR enthusiasts can catch up on the enlightening presentations by BOS, Web3, and blockchain experts. You’re in the perfect place to delve into notable announcements made during the conference, from <a href="/blog/near-foundation-signs-up-to-the-ethereum-climate-platform/?_gl=1%2A1nco86y%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTQ5MTA4NDUzMS4xNjg5Njk0NDEy%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4xLjAuMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4wLjAuMA..">NEAR signing up to the Ethereum Climate Platform</a> to an epic new <a href="/blog/interactive-polygon-zkevm-app-dashboard-launches-on-the-near-blockchain-operating-system/?_gl=1%2A1nco86y%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTQ5MTA4NDUzMS4xNjg5Njk0NDEy%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4xLjAuMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4wLjAuMA..">interactive Polygon zkEVM app dashboard</a>.</p>



<p>ICYMI, it’s time to dive into all the key speeches, events, and announcements that unfolded in the City of Lights over this past weekend.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-interactive-polygon-zkevm-app-dashboard-launches-on-the-bos">Interactive Polygon zkEVM app dashboard launches on the BOS</h2>



<p>In the most significant partnership announcement of ETHCC, an <a href="/blog/interactive-polygon-zkevm-app-dashboard-launches-on-the-near-blockchain-operating-system/?_gl=1%2A1nco86y%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTQ5MTA4NDUzMS4xNjg5Njk0NDEy%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4xLjAuMTY4OTY5NDQxMC4wLjAuMA..">interactive Polygon zkEVM app dashboard</a> has launched on the Blockchain Operating System (BOS). This integration will not only increase accessibility and discoverability for zkEVM developers and users on the open web but also vastly improve user experience. </p>



<p>The collaboration is set to accelerate the creation of dApps that will onboard billions of users into the open web. The new <a href="https://bos.quickswap.exchange/">Polygon zkEVM dashboard </a>now combines the benefits of zero-knowledge technology with the power of the BOS to unlock <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jVu4Hc1CLao">even more seamless onboarding</a> to the open web. </p>



<p>The dashboard brings a new suite of zero knowledge development capabilities to zkEVM developers and lets them build apps that can reach more users from day one. It’s a groundbreaking partnership that brings together the NEAR and Polygon ecosystems, two of the most innovative names in Ethereum and blockchain scalability.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">NEAR makes waves with sustainability commitment</h2>



<p>NEAR Foundation made a significant stride in its commitment to Web3 sustainability. As part of its ongoing efforts, NEAR signed up to the Ethereum Climate Platform, demonstrating its resolve towards minimizing the environmental impact of Web3 development. This move aligns with NEAR’s ethos and commitment to sustainable and scalable blockchain solutions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Marieke storms the BOS-tille at “Funding the Commons”</h2>



<p>Adding to the list of notable NEAR occurrences during ETHCC, NEAR Foundation CEO, Marieke Flament, was a keynote speaker at the “Funding the Commons” event held at Sorbonne Université on July 15. Marike’s message was one of bringing more ethics and equity to the entire blockchain and Web3 ecosystem.</p>



<p>In her speech, titled &#8220;The Open Web is NEAR: How the BOS, NDC, and DAOs are creating a Decentralized Web,” Marieke explored how NEAR Foundation serves the ecosystem by building public goods like the BOS, DevHub, NDC, DAOs, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Funding the Commons” is an event designed to complement the Ethereum Community Conference, promoting connection amongst participants, and fostering new collaborations and projects. The event organizers also planned a dinner on July 15 at Le Procope Paris, where Marieke was among the most notable invited guests.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Unpacking Insights: notable talks and events at ETH CC</h2>



<p>Near @ ETHCC wasn&#8217;t just a gathering of blockchain enthusiasts, but a hotbed of innovative discussions. Illia Polosukhin, co-founder of NEAR, and Nadir Dabit&#8217;s conversation around decentralized social networks piqued particular interest. They hinted at a shift in how we&#8217;ll connect and share information in the future and the potential role of decentralized social on the BOS.</p>



<p>Matt Stephenson, head of crypto economics at crypto investment firm, Pantera Capital, took the audience on a thrilling Day Two journey through the intricacies of behavioral game theory. He showcased how game theory could be leveraged in this space, offering a unique lens to examine, understand, and potentially predict blockchain trends.</p>



<p>Near @ ETHCC didn&#8217;t skimp on forward-looking conversations either. A panel featuring Max Mersch of Fabric Ventures, Maggie Love from SheFi, and Bilal El Alamy of PyratzLabs posed a pertinent question: &#8220;What’s the Next Big Use Case Being Built in the Bear Market?&#8221; Each speaker provided valuable insight about both challenges and opportunities posed by bear markets.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ecosystem Updates</h2>



<p>Despite the focus on the Near @ ETHCC side event itself, the NEAR ecosystem saw significant developments and milestones during the past few days.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>The NEAR Digital Collective’s I-AM-HUMAN</strong> movement has crossed 2,000 members in the NEAR ecosystem. The initiative allows users to vote, elect candidates for office, and shape the future of NEAR. You can sign up <a href="https://i-am-human.app/?transactionHashes=Djm4ohdiWxNETWz3xZA8BUreQFbQm63rJh67SAHkMc48">here</a>.</li>



<li><strong>MintbaseSearch</strong> has gone live on NEAR mainnet along with its own ChatGPT plugin. Mintbase now enables users to ask anything about NFTs on the NEAR Protocol. More details <a href="https://twitter.com/mintbase/status/1679487855473872897?s">here</a>.</li>



<li><strong>Opolis</strong> has raised $6.6M in a bridge fundraising round with support from NEAR Foundation, Polygon Ventures, and Draper Capital. Read more details about the full announcement <a href="https://twitter.com/opolis/status/1679477404824137732?s">here</a>.</li>



<li><strong>Black Snow: Battle For Earth,</strong> launched its demo version, offering an exciting free-to-play-and-earn experience that aims to enhance the NEAR ecosystem by boosting user count and transactions. Check out the demo<a href="https://linktr.ee/battleforearth"> here</a></li>
</ul>



<p>C&#8217;est la vie in Paris as ETHCC 2023 wraps up. As we reflect on these dynamic days, it&#8217;s clear that the future of NEAR and the BOS is exciting and full of potential. From environmental commitments to bold collaborations and fascinating talks, NEAR’s Parisian journey was full of engagement, enlightenment, and enthusiasm for everyone involved.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-highlights-sustainability-and-the-bos-take-center-stage-in-paris/">NEAR at ETHCC Highlights: Sustainability and the BOS Take Center Stage in Paris</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation PR Roundup for June</title>
		<link>/blog/near-foundation-pr-roundup-for-june/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Press]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As June comes to a close, summer in the NEAR ecosystem is heating up with a wave of new announcements, …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-pr-roundup-for-june/">NEAR Foundation PR Roundup for June</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As June comes to a close, summer in the NEAR ecosystem is heating up with a wave of new announcements, events, media appearances, and more. Not to mention a few notable celebrities bringing some star power into NEAR’s orbit. Here’s a rundown of all the newsworthy NEAR happenings over the past month.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sammy-hagar-and-guy-fieri-jump-into-nfts-on-near">Sammy Hagar and Guy Fieri jump into NFTs on NEAR</h2>



<p>In the US, Grammy-winning musician Sammy Hagar and celebrity chef Guy Fieri joined the NEAR ecosystem, teaming up with NEAR on-ramp Trident3 to launch an NFT loyalty program. The Santo Spirits Club loyalty program, as reported by <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/web3/2023/06/13/guy-fieri-and-sammy-hagar-launch-web3-tequila-loyalty-program/">Coindesk</a> and <a href="https://decrypt.co/144378/guy-fieri-sammy-hagar-tequila-brand-launches-nft-loyalty-program">Decrypt</a>, will enable tequila fans to earn on-chain tiered perks and an opportunity to win a virtual tasting with the duo.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-mirae-asset-marblex-and-vortex-boost-south-korea">Mirae Asset, MARBLEX, and Vortex boost South Korea</h2>



<p>&nbsp;Over in Asia, NEAR Foundation continued to make inroads in South Korea. Mirae Asset, a subsidiary of Asia’s largest financial group, announced a partnership to research Web3’s role in global business. Per&nbsp; <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/press-releases/2023-06-09/near-foundation-mirae-asset-paving-the-way-for-the-future-of-web3-finance">Bloomberg</a>, Mirae Asset will collaborate with NEAR Foundation to strengthen the Web2/3 business network and identify opportunities for real-world blockchain value creation.</p>



<p>Meanwhile,  <a href="https://blockchainreporter.net/marblex-collaborates-with-near-foundation-to-revolutionize-the-web3-gaming-sector/">Blockchain Reporter</a> broke that Marblex – a Korean blockchain infrastructure provider for high-quality gaming – will integrate NEAR protocol with Marblex’s gaming universe, enhancing user convenience and Web3 adoption. NEAR will integrate with MARBLEX’s WARP Bridge, taking advantage of NEAR’s high scalability and speed to improve the gaming experience in Web3. The partnership will also enable joint marketing initiatives and events, boosting awareness of the global blockchain gaming market. </p>



<p>Then there’s Vortex Gaming, a Web3 subsidiary of Inven, the largest game media community in Korea. Coverage by <a href="https://europeangaming.eu/portal/latest-news/2023/06/27/138269/near-protocol-completes-gaming-ecosystem-by-onboarding-vortex-gaming/">European Gaming</a> reported that Vortex will leverage NEAR protocol to integrate a&nbsp; gaming community encompassing Web2 and Web3 by building innovative infrastructure for gaming developers. The NEAR Foundation and Inven will also collaborate on marketing and business development, adding to NEAR’s exciting Web3 gaming ecosystem.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-skoda-launches-metaverse-for-auto-fans-in-india">Skoda launches metaverse for auto fans in India</h2>



<p>Czech Automobile Manufacturer Skoda entered the Metaverse in the world’s most populous country, giving users an opportunity to explore, collect and own digital art pieces on NEAR. The platform, as reported by <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/czech-automobile-conglomerate-skoda-auto-launches-nft-platform">Cointelegraph</a> and <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/en-in/news-and-trends/skoda-auto-enters-the-nft-race-with-skodaverse-india/454673">Entrepreneur India</a>, will enable NFT owners to access exclusive perks and rewards, while allowing owners to trade digital artwork in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sailgp-christens-the-dock-for-decentralized-fandom">SailGP christens The Dock for decentralized fandom</h2>



<p>In more partnership news, the Global racing league SailGP and Oracle announced the launch of “The Dock”, a decentralized fan engagement platform powered by Oracle and NEAR’s ongoing partnership to bridge the worlds of Web2 and Web3. As reported by <a href="https://www.sailweb.co.uk/2023/06/13/sailgp-and-oracle-roll-out-the-dock-loyalty-program/">SailWeb</a>, The Dock will revolutionize how fans follow SailGP, increasing engagement through exclusive content and enabling fans to earn points, redeemable for exciting rewards including VIP access to SailGP events and more.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-alibaba-cloud-and-women-in-web3-headline-collision">Alibaba Cloud and Women in Web3 headline Collision</h2>



<p>The NEAR ecosystem took over Toronto this month, showcasing the best of BOS at Collision 2023,&nbsp; one of the world’s biggest tech conferences.&nbsp; During the event, the NEAR Foundation announced a groundbreaking partnership with Alibaba, enabling developers across Asia to launch new NEAR validators with Alibaba Cloud’s infrastructure as a service.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The partnership was covered in myriad outlets such as <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/business/2023/06/26/embargo-26th-june-7am-bst-near-foundation-partners-with-alibaba-cloud-to-accelerate-web3-growth/">Coindesk</a>, <a href="https://journalducoin.com/actualites/near-alibaba-cloud-faciliter-developpement-applications-decentralisees/">Journal du Coin</a>, and <a href="https://www.btc-echo.de/schlagzeilen/near-foundation-und-alibaba-cloud-gehen-partnerschaft-ein-166623/">BTC Echo</a>. Partnering with Alibaba means the NEAR ecosystem will have access to Remote Procedure Calls (RPC) and enable users to interact with NEAR’s Blockchain Operating System while using Alibaba Cloud’s infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The NEAR Foundation also released the Women in Web3 Changemakers List 2023, celebrating the achievements of extraordinary women throughout the Web3 ecosystem. As reported by <a href="https://techfundingnews.com/breaking-the-mold-these-women-in-web3-changemakers-2023-forge-a-path-of-inclusion-and-innovation/?utm_content=cmp-true">Tech Funding News</a>, the ten women were selected by the public and hail from all corners of the globe, following hundreds of nominations from the Web3 community.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-leadership-viewpoints-on-media-and-social-fairness">Leadership viewpoints on media and social fairness</h2>



<p>Illia Polosukhin, Founder of NEAR and CEO of Pagoda, took the time to write a thought leadership piece in <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blockchain-media-governance-immutable">Blockworks</a> about crypto’s potential to transform how we interact with the media. Illia sets out the emerging problem with the status quo: bad actors are beginning to utilize generative AI to dramatically scale up misinformation campaigns.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, Illia explains that blockchain-based “sign-and-trace” systems can enable the public to reliably source and validate real news stories, with a legitimate trail of sources available online.</p>



<p>CEO of NEAR Foundation Marieke Flament also penned an article for London’s leading daily business paper <a href="https://www.cityam.com/city-am-web3-building-a-fair-open-and-inclusive-digital-world/">CityAM</a> about using Web3 to build a fair and inclusive digital world.  “Too often technology has only benefited the few: those who have money, those who have power, or those of a certain gender, ethnicity, or skin color.</p>



<p>But this doesn’t need to be the case,” she explained. “Technology can and should be in the service of all people. But to achieve this, we will need a change in perspective, something that Web3 can help us achieve.”</p>



<p>Marieke also talked about blockchain, Web3, and BOS on a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_lXz1gd9ErI">podcast hosted by the editor Journal du Coin</a> &#8211; France’s leading crypto media outlet, and for a video interview with <a href="https://ffnews.com/fintech-tv/event/event-videos-2023/paris-fintech-forum-leaders-summit-2023/marieke-flament-near-foundation-paris-fintech-forum/">Fintech Finance</a> at the Paris Fintech Forum.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s all for this month. If we missed anything or want to share anything for next month’s roundup, get in touch!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-pr-roundup-for-june/">NEAR Foundation PR Roundup for June</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Korea Hub: June 2023 Highlights</title>
		<link>/blog/near-korea-hub-june-2023-highlights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Since launching in November of 2022, NEAR Korea Hub has hit a number of major milestones in the Korean Web3 …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-korea-hub-june-2023-highlights/">NEAR Korea Hub: June 2023 Highlights</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since launching in November of 2022, NEAR Korea Hub has hit a number of major milestones in the Korean Web3 industry. The Hub has significantly contributed to the expansion of the Web3 ecosystem over the past 6 months by forming partnerships with leading domestic game companies, providing generous developer support, and forging long-term relationships with college blockchain clubs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s take a look at all of the exciting things that came out of the NEAR Korea Hub during NEAR co-founder Illia Polosukhin’s visit.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">NEAR co-founder Illia Polosukhin talks Web3 and AI</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="903" height="533" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image9.png" alt="" class="wp-image-20687" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image9.png 903w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image9-300x177.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image9-768x453.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 903px) 100vw, 903px" /></figure>



<p>A number of major Korean media outlets conducted interviews with Illia on NEAR Protocol’s Web3 and AI strategy. Illia pointed out that NEAR Protocol’s principle focus is on the Blockchain Operating System (BOS) and FastAuth, an important new product that provides a better-than-Web2 onboarding experience that can help foster the mass adoption of Web3.<br>Here is a list of Illia’s interviews (the coverage is in Korean):</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.hankyung.com/it/article/202306074291g">Hankyung</a> (Korea Economy) &#8211; &#8220;Blockchain and AI will Create the Best Synergy&#8221;</li>



<li><a href="https://www.khan.co.kr/economy/economy-general/article/202306120830021">Kyunghyang</a> &#8211; Blockchain AI Synergy will be Amazing</li>



<li><a href="https://weekly.khan.co.kr/khnm.html?mode=view&amp;artid=202306091124121&amp;code=114">Kyunghyang Weekly</a> &#8211; Is Fake News the Fault of Generative AI?</li>



<li><a href="https://www.techm.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=111059">TechM</a> &#8211; Korean Games Leading in Web3.0 Business Model&#8230; Synergy with AI and Blockchain</li>



<li><a href="https://www.coindeskkorea.com/news/articleView.html?idxno=91695">CoinDesk</a> &#8211; Popularization of Web3 Starts from User-Centered Thinking</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-illia-s-talk-at-ethseoul-buidl-asia-june-2nd-june-7th">Illia’s talk at ETHSeoul &amp; Buidl Asia — June 2nd &#8211; June 7th</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/LtlFAYKHcCQAg1IIC9IfVOSkt6D7Bjy6EoboqSEW3sUbxmI0wWIoXVN3swYIefByHYlvMhTF75lEnM0H2Khv39SarLOQB6ChG9w2z3TwK9EmVvtBOak6HXXVnibqZeu-hWi-63pvOTryecxw_NcaQhM" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Illia attended ETH Seoul and BUIDL Asia —&nbsp;both major Web3 events — as the first keynote speaker, where he gave a speech entitled “Web3’s Future, BOS.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“One of the major problems with Web3 is the user inconvenience when making and using wallets,” Illia pointed out. “With BOS, which provides a Web2-like experience and ease for developers and users, NEAR Protocol wants to connect all blockchain and users to onboard 1 billion users to Web3”. He also added: “BOS acts as a gateway to combine all features such as DeFi and NFT which are scattered around the Web3 network”.</p>



<p>Illia further emphasized the importance of the Korean market and shared achievements of NEAR Korea Hub.&nbsp;<br></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-illia-s-speech-at-the-gyeonggi-province-ai-expert-policy-roundtable-june-8th">Illia’s Speech at the Gyeonggi Province &#8216;AI Expert Policy Roundtable’ — June 8th</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="602" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image12-1-1024x602.png" alt="" class="wp-image-20689" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image12-1-1024x602.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image12-1-300x176.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image12-1-768x451.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image12-1.png 1098w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Illia was invited to give his speech “The Intersection of AI and Web3” at the “AI Expert Policy Roundtable” hosted by Gyeonggi-do, the largest province in Korea. He also discussed potential partnership opportunities with the governor of Gyeonggi-do, who is also a presidential candidate.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="960" height="630" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-20688" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image2.png 960w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image2-300x197.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image2-768x504.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></figure>



<p>In his speech, Illia noted: “AI should be open source instead of closed source. We need to find institutional measures to secure and manage high-quality data based on Web3 technology in the public domain. The combination of Web3 and AI has the potential to act as a pillar of the new policy for mass adoption. NEAR Protocol will be the strongest use case if allowed to become a bridge for onboarding users to Web3”.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-business-meetings-and-major-partnerships">Business Meetings and Major Partnerships<strong>&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-meetings-with-global-companies">Meetings with global companies&nbsp;</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/lrCmKVCB_L53R_-WHJ74vYWpnB_3pJ-5yPamkmFanZmQzgGCYacwGKU33fsP9V7Q6Bbu0J9r2dO43YU5cd_DQzQ7_ZJ_KA5_Caz1upoYKblmGABRIBspKSvfk1-Mbb3wnXUscjYLjumvdLMKm3tpsfU" alt=""/></figure>



<p>NEAR Foundation and NEAR Korea Hub hosted meetings between Illia and the management of major global companies in Korea. There were constructive discussions with companies looking to expand into Web3, which have already shown significant results.</p>



<p>From having small discussions to signing MOUs with major companies including Netmarble and Mirae Asset, the Korea Hub laid the foundation for solid collaboration. This foundation will serve as an important first step in expanding the Web3 industry in Korea.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-marblex-partnership-june-5th">MARBLEX Partnership — June 5th</h3>



<p>NEAR Foundation has joined forces with <a href="https://www.marblex.io/en">MARBLEX</a>, a blockchain subsidiary of Netmarble, to Expand Korea’s Web3 Gaming Industry with Aurora. Netmarble is a global top 7 game publisher with 1M+ MAU in the last three games. </p>



<p>Through this strategic business agreement, NEAR Foundation and MARBLEX plan to achieve mutual growth by linking the NEAR blockchain and Aurora with WARP Bridge to enable interactive collaboration, promote global joint marketing events, and enhance brand awareness. Furthermore, competitive and casual gamers alike will now be able to enjoy a variety of games and exclusive content through NEAR’s Blockchain Operating System (BOS).</p>



<p>More information on the NEAR <a href="/blog/near-foundation-and-marblex-to-expand-koreas-web3-gaming-industry-with-warp-bridge/">Blog</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/NEARProtocol/status/1665519681547952128?s=20">Twitter.</a></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Mirae Asset Partnership &#8211; June 7th</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/9pOyDzVz8NZ1WoF1a2ixUL3WfWgHz9grVsnJNJPEvzTu3PAcer-AO6leROXPo1Ftx27yD406TqGjmEifoBeS_uJk8DZ0BcBAw04JVNpJZxQ3IolUN2wQmgog4FxrvpuLyjHAFzB6MmDmolEmJ3BWI04" alt=""/></figure>



<p>In a pivotal partnership for the blockchain industry, NEAR Foundation is joining forces with <a href="https://english.securities.miraeasset.com/">Mirae Asset </a>— a subsidiary of Asia’s largest financial group Mirae Asset Global — to help bridge the gap between traditional finance and Web3.</p>



<p>Through this strategic business agreement, NEAR Foundation and Mirae Asset aim to expand the Web3 business domain and lead the global financial paradigm by conducting joint research and collaboration on Real-World Assets Technology. Furthermore, both parties have agreed to organize global joint events to enhance brand awareness and establish a mutual support system to strengthen the Web2/Web3 business network.</p>



<p>More information on the NEAR<a href="https://near.org/blog/near-foundation-joins-forces-with-mirae-asset-for-the-next-leap-in-web3-finance"> Blog</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/NEARProtocol/status/1666958558649278468?s=20">Twitter</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Vortex Gaming Onboarding — June 22nd</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/NrQ2CLw_ez0KsofGcXyupvTMgw8hvriM5VItwrYxf7hhVOjS2b9UQt6iQdfuUm0edHMFHp8p8xfYt2BDSNJqPxkWp5SmujvI6vDeYxykGEC-x1gtcfqMRw20pQfgNCENeX7N9el1a4PFkE-JPPowOM8" alt=""/></figure>



<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a new partnership with <a href="https://vortexgaming.io/">Vortex Gaming</a>, a Web3 subsidiary of the leading game industry <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=inven%20korea">INVEN</a>. INVEN is the largest game media·community in Korea, with a monthly active user (MAU) count of 7.2 million.</p>



<p>With the guidance of the NEAR Korea Hub, NEAR Foundation and Vortex Gaming plan to achieve mutual growth by collaborating to support the growth of Vortex Gaming; strengthen the <a href="https://near.org/">NEAR</a> game ecosystem; conduct offline hackathons and events to foster developer talent; and enhance brand awareness and business networks.</p>



<p>Read the full announcement on the <a href="https://near.org/blog/near-foundation-partners-with-vortex-gaming-a-web3-subsidiary-of-koreas-largest-gaming-community-inven/">NEAR Foundation blog</a>. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Major Events</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Glitch Hackathon Winners Dinner &#8211; May 30th</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="468" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image13-1024x468.png" alt="" class="wp-image-20690" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image13-1024x468.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image13-300x137.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image13-768x351.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image13-1536x702.png 1536w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image13.png 1999w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>During the Glitch Hackathon, which took place from May 19th to 21st, Illia and the NEAR Korea team organized a meetup event with the participants of the NEAR Track. Despite being a multi-chain hackathon with five mainnets participating, the NEAR Track had the highest number of participants, and PokaTika from the NEAR Track won the hackathon.</p>



<p>NEAR Korea Hub’s constant support throughout the hackathon helped achieve these remarkable results. NEAR Korea Hub provided comprehensive support and mentoring to the participating teams. Furthermore, the meetup event, which was hosted to continuously build the Korean Web3 ecosystem and establish strong relationships with new builders, saw participation from over 70 builders.</p>



<p> It provided builders with valuable opportunities to showcase their products. A considerable number of teams participating in the Glitch Hackathon also took part in the ETHSeoul Hackathon, which serves as evidence of the growth of the domestic builder ecosystem for NEAR Protocol.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ethseoul-hackathon-june-2nd-4th">ETHSeoul Hackathon — June 2nd &#8211; 4th</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="588" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image11-1024x588.png" alt="" class="wp-image-20691" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image11-1024x588.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image11-300x172.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image11-768x441.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image11.png 1118w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>NEAR Protocol held “NEAR Track at ETHSeoul”, an event for the blockchain ecosystem and community. ETHSeoul served as a platform for discussions on Web3 mass adoption, with participation from 46 hackathon teams (including over 250 builders) and 800 Web3 users.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Among the 46 participating teams, 24 teams chose NEAR Protocol despite the event’s focus on Ethereum, indicating the strong interest and influence of NEAR in Korea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At NEAR Track, after an intense competition among outstanding teams, the following teams emerged victorious:</p>



<ul>
<li>1st. <a href="https://devfolio.co/projects/pokatika-6406">Pokatika</a>, is a mobile application that enhances the post-event experience with unique NFT photo cards.</li>



<li>2nd. <a href="https://devfolio.co/projects/onstage-4dc5">On Stage(What&#8217;s Next)</a>, turns artists&#8217; characters and illustrations into NFTs, providing AI training data to NFT holders for integrating them into new AI images.</li>



<li>Co-3rd. <a href="https://devfolio.co/projects/imagine-you-are-an-artist-for-nft-4483">AGLIPPA</a>, combines blockchain and AI to democratize artistic creation, allowing anyone to transform personal experiences into everlasting NFT.</li>



<li>Co-3rd. <a href="https://devfolio.co/projects/freekick-cbc3">0xtail</a>, matches football enthusiasts for a football game.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-buidl-asia-june-6th-7th">BUIDL Asia — June 6th &#8211; 7th</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="684" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image8-1024x684.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-20692" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image8-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image8-300x200.jpg 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image8-768x513.jpg 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image8-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image8.jpg 1999w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>BUIDL Asia 2023 provided a platform for various projects and communities to come together, share insights, and discuss development trends. The event, organized by Erica Kang —&nbsp;a prominent figure representing Korean Web3 women —&nbsp;garnered significant media and corporate attention.</p>



<p>Illia and Alex Shevchenko, co-founder of Aurora, participated as speakers and shared insights on the NEAR ecosystem&#8217;s current trends and future prospects. Additionally, NEAR Korea Hub operated a booth at the event, allowing attendees to experience the Blockchain Operating System (BOS) first-hand.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-x-hashed-night-june-8th">NEAR x Hashed Night —&nbsp;June 8th</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="659" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image7-1024x659.png" alt="" class="wp-image-20693" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image7-1024x659.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image7-300x193.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image7-768x494.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image7.png 1038w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>NEAR x Hashed Night was a highly successful event co-organized with Hashed, a distinguished venture capital firm representing the Web3 industry. The event witnessed the participation of 35 partner companies and an impressive attendance of 410 individuals. Illia led the event alongside key executives from the NEAR ecosystem who served as distinguished speakers. They provided insightful introductions to NEAR Protocol and its notable projects, facilitating valuable networking opportunities for all attendees.</p>



<p>Speakers like Alex Shevchenko, co-founder of Aurora, Bowen Shen, co-founder of Proximity Labs, and Ran Yi, co-founder of Orderly Network attended the event. Representatives from Mirae Asset and MARBLEX, who recently formed a strategic partnership with NEAR Foundation, were also present. It was amazing to see so many major Web2 and Web3 companies in one place, as it created a fantastic opportunity to explore new business prospects.</p>



<p>As one attendee noted: “The place was so crowded that it was running out of oxygen”. This achievement was made possible thanks to NEAR&#8217;s growing reputation in the Korean Web3 industry and the onboarding of numerous builders through Glitch and ETHSeoul Hackathon.</p>



<p>NEAR Korea is really excited about NEAR&#8217;s upcoming events, including Korea Blockchain Week(KBW), and they look forward to high expectations and participation!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Raising NEAR awareness in Korea</h2>



<p>Overall, Illia’s time in Korea along with the hard work of NEAR Korea Hub has greatly enhanced the awareness and influence of NEAR Protocol within Korea. This was made possible through the active support of the NEAR Foundation and the strong collaboration with ecosystem partners.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-korea-hub-june-2023-highlights/">NEAR Korea Hub: June 2023 Highlights</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web3&#8217;s Leading Ladies: NEAR Foundation Honors 2023&#8217;s Women Changemakers </title>
		<link>/blog/web3s-leading-ladies-near-foundation-honors-2023s-women-changemakers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women in Web3 Changemakers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As Collision 2023 rolls on, NEAR Foundation announced the ten winners of the Women in Web3 Changemakers award. These exceptional …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/web3s-leading-ladies-near-foundation-honors-2023s-women-changemakers/">Web3&#8217;s Leading Ladies: NEAR Foundation Honors 2023&#8217;s Women Changemakers </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As Collision 2023 rolls on, NEAR Foundation announced the ten winners of the <a href="https://www.womenweb3changemakers.com/">Women in Web3 Changemakers</a> award. These exceptional women, chosen from a pool of 200 nominees worldwide, underline the significant contributions women can make throughout the Web3 ecosystem.</p>



<p>&#8220;These Changemakers show us that together we can make a positive difference and shape the collective good of Web3,” says Marieke Flament, CEO of NEAR Foundation. “We must continue to help one another and nurture a strong, international community that includes both men and women.”</p>



<p>The Women in Web3 Changemakers competition illuminates the groundbreaking work of influential women in the Web3 space. As this platform appreciates the significant strides made by these remarkable women, it&#8217;s important to recognize the unique journeys of all ten winners, each of whom has contributed to the evolution of the blockchain industry.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-women-behind-the-success-of-web3-honored-at-collision">Women behind the success of Web3 honored at Collision</h2>



<p>Candidates for the Women in Web3 Changemakers award come from all corners of the globe, each making unique marks on the Web3 ecosystem in their own respective ways. Each of the following women made the final top ten because they’ve carved out a niche, advocated for transformative solutions, and been a part of breakthrough blockchain initiatives.</p>



<p>The full list of winners includes:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Emily Rose Dallara:</strong> Web3 Leadership Coach and Podcast Producer</li>



<li><strong>Janine Grainger: </strong>&nbsp;Co-founder and CEO, Easy Crypto AI</li>



<li><strong>Bridget Greenwood</strong>: Founder, The Bigger Pie</li>



<li><strong>Cathy Hackl:</strong> Chief Futurist and Chief Metaverse Officer at Journey</li>



<li><strong>Erica Kang</strong>: Founder and CEO, KrptoSeoul</li>



<li><strong>Irina Karagyaur:</strong> Founder and Director, BQ9</li>



<li><strong>Veronica Korzh:</strong> Co-founder and CEO, Geekpay</li>



<li><strong>Zoe Leavitt:</strong> Founder and CEO, Glass</li>



<li><strong>Alana Podrx:</strong> Founder and CEO, Eve Wealth</li>



<li><strong>Yaliwe Soko:</strong> Chair, United Africa Blockchain Association</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="535" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/WW3-finalists-1024x535.png" alt="" class="wp-image-20680" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/WW3-finalists-1024x535.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/WW3-finalists-300x157.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/WW3-finalists-768x401.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/WW3-finalists-1536x803.png 1536w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/WW3-finalists-2048x1070.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Handpicked by public vote from a pool of hundreds of applications, these Changemakers were assessed on criteria of inclusion, influence, and innovation. Each woman demonstrated the ability to drive societal good, make a substantial impact in the Web3 community, and contribute to critical projects, uplifting the global female presence in the Web3 landscape.</p>



<p>“The Changemakers show that we can forge our own path into the ecosystem and create a collective narrative that has the power to break down barriers to entry and make Web3 more inclusive for everyone,” Flament continues. “I’m extremely honored to be championing this initiative and to spotlight these exceptionally talented women.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-diverse-journeys-of-women-in-web3-changemakers">The diverse journeys of Women in Web3 Changemakers</h2>



<p>All ten winners of the Women in Web3 Changemakers awards come from a variety of backgrounds, geographies, and skill sets. Yaliwe Soko, for instance, is championing opportunities in Web3 to alleviate poverty and provide <a href="https://www.uaba.io/uaba-wp/">opportunities across Africa</a>. Others like <a href="https://www.thedrum.com/news/2023/03/30/cathy-hackl-day-the-life-chief-metaverse-officer">Cathy Hackle</a> are icons in spheres like the metaverse.</p>



<p>Erica Kang, meanwhile, spearheads KryptoSeoul and was responsible for&nbsp; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/kryptoseoul-launches-buidl-asia-week-in-seoul/">BUIDL ASIA 2022 conference</a>, attended by ETH co-founder Vitalik Buterin and NEAR Protocol co-founder Illia Polosukhin. And through her organization <a href="https://www.thebiggerpie.io/about">The Bigger Pie</a>, Bridget Greenwood is building an entire support ecosystem to advance both women and minorities in blockchain and crypto.</p>



<p>Another changemaker, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/emilyrosedallara/?originalSubdomain=fr">Emily Rose Dallara</a>, is a Web3 leadership coach and podcast producer, who uses a Holistic Growth Coaching method to help overwhelmed leaders thrive — without the burnout. Helping to make digital assets more accessible, Kiwi-born <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/janine-grainger-easycrypto/">Janine Grainger</a> is the co-founder and CEO of <a href="https://easycrypto.com/">Easy Crypto</a>, a simple and secure way for anyone to get involved in crypto. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/irina-karagyaur/">Irina Karagyaur</a>, the founder and director of <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/bq9/about/">BQ9</a>, is working to turn great ideas into even better Web3 products through her crypto-fintech boutique advisory firm.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With <a href="https://www.geekpay.co/">Geekpay</a>, co-founder and CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vkorzh/">Veronica Korzh</a> is streamlining and securing digital payments without the stress and need for long wallet addresses. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/zoeleavitt/">Zoe Leavitt</a>, the founder and CEO of <a href="https://www.glass.fun/">Glass</a>, has set up shop in the loyalty space, allowing customers to level up their nights out by earning rewards from their favorite alcohol brands. And <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alanapodrx/">Alana Podrx</a>, the founder and CEO of <a href="https://members.evewealth.com/">Eve Wealth</a>, has created a community of women who share portfolios, co-invest, and support each other in self-guided wealth management through peer-to-peer learning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Celebrating the individual successes and collective efforts of these Changemakers reflects the massive impact and influence of women in Web3. From Africa to Asia, from the metaverse and marketing to crypto media and education, each winner has blazed her unique trail and is impacting the Web3 ecosystem, inspiring both men and women to do the same.</p>



<p>“I’m grateful for the hundreds of nominations we received from peers and employers who took the time to highlight the many achievements that the global female workforce has made to their organizations,” Flament continues. “By casting their ballot, the international community has shown that the contributions of women are being noticed.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>By celebrating the contributions of these Changemakers, the NEAR Foundation underscores its commitment to diversity, inclusion, and innovation in the Web3 space. As females in crypto continue to make strides, it&#8217;s vital to recognize and appreciate the efforts of women who are paving the way for an equitable and inclusive future in Web3 and beyond.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/web3s-leading-ladies-near-foundation-honors-2023s-women-changemakers/">Web3&#8217;s Leading Ladies: NEAR Foundation Honors 2023&#8217;s Women Changemakers </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
