<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NEAR Wallet Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/near-wallet/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/near-wallet/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 14:00:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>NEAR Wallet Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/near-wallet/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>NEAR Wallet Will Remain Online Until the End of the Year</title>
		<link>/blog/near-wallet-will-remain-online-until-the-end-of-the-year/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Wallet Migration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>To avoid the rush of last minute transfers, and to support the inclusion of new wallets coming into the ecosystem, …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-wallet-will-remain-online-until-the-end-of-the-year/">NEAR Wallet Will Remain Online Until the End of the Year</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To avoid the rush of last minute transfers, and to support the inclusion of new wallets coming into the ecosystem, we are delaying the sunset of the NEAR wallet.</p>



<p>The NEAR wallet sunset is now targeted for <strong>December 31st, 2023</strong>.</p>



<p>We want to encourage users to continue to transfer their wallets using the Transfer Wizard available at wallet.near.org. Simply select “Get Started” on the banner at the top of the page displayed when you log in.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://wallet.near.org/transfer-wizard">Learn more</a> about how the Transfer Wizard works.</li>



<li>You can also <a href="https://near.org/blog/embracing-decentralization-whats-next-for-the-near-wallet">learn more</a> about why Pagoda is sunsetting the NEAR Wallet.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-future-of-the-wallet-near-org-landing-page">The future of the wallet.near.org landing page</h3>



<p>Previously, we had intended to make wallet.near.org into a wallet-centric landing page as a place for ecosystem users to learn about all the amazing wallets available on the NEAR platform. However, due to resource and time constraints, we no longer believe we could provide the best experience. Instead, we are asking the community to create an information site that showcases all the NEAR wallets.</p>



<p>These plans are still in progress as we work with community partners. More to follow when we have more to share.</p>



<p>Thank you for your continued support and patience as we work hard to improve the user onboarding and transaction experience.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-wallet-will-remain-online-until-the-end-of-the-year/">NEAR Wallet Will Remain Online Until the End of the Year</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Reminder to Migrate from NEAR Wallet</title>
		<link>/blog/a-reminder-to-migrate-from-near-wallet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 13:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transfer Wizard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In July, NEAR Foundation published “Embracing Decentralization: What’s Next for the NEAR Wallet”, a detailed exploration of how Pagoda is …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/a-reminder-to-migrate-from-near-wallet/">A Reminder to Migrate from NEAR Wallet</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In July, NEAR Foundation published “<a href="/blog/embracing-decentralization-whats-next-for-the-near-wallet/">Embracing Decentralization: What’s Next for the NEAR Wallet</a>”, a detailed exploration of how Pagoda is migrating NEAR Wallet from being a browser wallet into a wallet hub. As we noted at the time, this wallet evolution illustrates the substantial growth of the NEAR ecosystem, which now offers a wide range of cross-chain wallets and native wallets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As part of this wallet evolution, the NEAR Wallet is set to be discontinued on January 1, 2024.</p>



<p>You can migrate to your wallet of choice using the automatic Wallet Transfer Wizard, integrated into the current NEAR Wallet, or manually by using your recovery phrase. Whichever path you choose, understand that your account and its assets are safe.</p>



<p>Do not worry if you have not transferred your accounts by January 1, 2024 — the Transfer Wizard will still be available after the wallet functionality sunsets. And again, rest assured that your assets will remain secure until you import them to a new wallet.</p>



<p>For more details on using&nbsp; the Transfer Wizard, visit the <a href="https://wallet.near.org/transfer-wizard">Migrating from NEAR Wallet</a> page.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/a-reminder-to-migrate-from-near-wallet/">A Reminder to Migrate from NEAR Wallet</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Embracing Decentralization: What’s Next for the NEAR Wallet</title>
		<link>/blog/embracing-decentralization-whats-next-for-the-near-wallet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transfer Wizard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When NEAR Mainnet launched in late 2020, it included a wallet built and hosted by Pagoda’s (then known as Near …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/embracing-decentralization-whats-next-for-the-near-wallet/">Embracing Decentralization: What’s Next for the NEAR Wallet</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When NEAR Mainnet launched in late 2020, it included a wallet built and hosted by Pagoda’s (then known as Near Inc.) core team on <a href="https://wallet.near.org/">https://wallet.near.org/</a> to support NEAR’s unique account model. Nearly three years later, the NEAR wallet ecosystem is home to a myriad of high quality, open source wallets supported by NEAR’s community of active contributors. This significant milestone reflects NEAR’s ongoing commitment to empower users and foster decentralization. The evolution of NEAR wallets also showcases the substantial growth of the ecosystem, as NEAR now supports a diverse list of cross-chain wallets, as well as native wallets with innovative onboarding approaches such as <a href="/blog/get-to-know-the-bos-fastauth-for-easy-web2-style-onboarding-and-account-recovery/?_gl=1%2A1fvy7yq%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMjA1NTA3NTczNy4xNjg2NjY4NDc2%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY4NjY2ODQ3NC4xLjEuMTY4NjY2ODUxMC4wLjAuMA..">FastAuth</a>.</p>



<p>To celebrate these excellent contributions from across the NEAR community, and to reflect the priority of decentralization, over the next few months Pagoda will start migrating the domain <a href="https://wallet.near.org/">https://wallet.near.org/</a> from being a browser wallet to being a wallet hub. In this way, <a href="https://wallet.near.org/">https://wallet.near.org/</a> will become the reference place for all NEAR wallets, allowing users to discover and implement the right wallets for their specific needs.</p>



<p>If you currently use <a href="https://wallet.near.org/">https://wallet.near.org/</a> as your main wallet, you have nothing to worry about. The Pagoda team has been working hard to build a Wallet Transfer Wizard to help you transfer your accounts to a new wallet easily and smoothly, while keeping your funds and assets safe. The Transfer Wizard will allow you to choose between Browser and Extension-based wallets, so you will still have the same friendly wallet experience you are accustomed to after the Wizard is finished.</p>



<p>For more details, visit the <a href="https://wallet.near.org/transfer-wizard">Migrating from NEAR Wallet</a> page.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-timeline-for-transitioning-the-main-wallet-domain">Timeline for transitioning the main wallet domain&nbsp;</h3>



<p>The NEAR Wallet will remain a browser wallet until <strong>January 1st, 2024</strong>, during which time the wallet will encourage and help you to transfer your accounts to a new wallet. You can do this manually with your recovery phrase or use the Transfer Wizard to securely migrate your accounts to the wallet of your choice. </p>



<p>Do not worry if you have not transferred your accounts by <strong> <strong>January 1st, 2024</strong></strong> —<strong> </strong>the Transfer Wizard will still be available after the wallet functionality sunsets. Rest assured that your assets will remain secure until you import them to a new wallet.</p>



<p>The Transfer Wizard will remain available on the new wallet landing page at wallet.near.org indefinitely. This repurposed page will act as an introduction to the various options for wallets in the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-a-new-era-for-near-wallets">A new era for NEAR Wallets</h3>



<p>This new step moves NEAR closer to achieving a truly decentralized ecosystem driven by its own community. Thanks to the wallet hub and the wallet selector (which enables the use of any compatible NEAR wallet in web applications), users will now be able to use any wallet they like. This will not only improve their experience on NEAR, but also the full spectrum of available Web3 experiences thanks <a href="/blog/near-blockchain-operating-system-is-now-live-on-near-org/?_gl=1%2Ahbkih2%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMjAwNDA3NDY4Mi4xNjg2NjY5MjQx%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY4NjY2OTIzOS4xLjEuMTY4NjY2OTI0My4wLjAuMA..">to the BOS</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/embracing-decentralization-whats-next-for-the-near-wallet/">Embracing Decentralization: What’s Next for the NEAR Wallet</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
