<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>USDC Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/usdc/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/usdc/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 13:39:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.orghttps://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>USDC Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/usdc/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>USDC Launches Natively on the NEAR Protocol </title>
		<link>/blog/usdc-launches-natively-on-the-near-protocol/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Circle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>USDC, the open-source, permissionless protocol and stablecoin that enables any app to send and store digital dollars, is now native …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/usdc-launches-natively-on-the-near-protocol/">USDC Launches Natively on the NEAR Protocol </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.circle.com/en/usdc">USDC</a>, the open-source, permissionless protocol and stablecoin that enables any app to send and store digital dollars, is now native on the NEAR blockchain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The announcement opens the door for businesses built on NEAR to easily withdraw NEAR USDC and send it on-chain in seconds. Users can also swap USDC natively from Ethereum to NEAR and back — without incurring costs or delays from third-party bridges. MyNearWallet, Ledger, and wallet.near.org have all confirmed support allowing a user to hold USDC and interact with dapps on the B.O.S. Other wallets will follow over the coming days.</p>



<p>Before this, USDC was only available on NEAR as a bridged form of USDC, known as USDC.e from Ethereum. This announcement means users get all the benefits of a native stablecoin, empowering developers to integrate stablecoin payments flows into their Javascript and&nbsp; Rust-based decentralized applications.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This will unlock a new wave of accessibility for Web2 builders moving into Web3. It will also serve a vital role in NEAR’s mission of Web3 mass adoption, while helping developers build without limits on an open web.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-native-versus-bridged">Native versus Bridged</h2>



<p>Circle brings USDC natively to new blockchain networks to empower developers to build on a stable foundation they can trust. Native USDC is officially issued by Circle and is always redeemable 1:1 for US dollars.</p>



<p>In the case of NEAR, historically USDC was only available as a bridged version of USDC from Ethereum. USDC.e is not issued by Circle and is not compatible with Circle Account or Circle APIs. This brings a NEAR native version of USDC on chain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To facilitate this shift, the NEAR Foundation will be working with ecosystem partners to help facilitate the migration of liquidity from bridged USDC to native USDC.</p>



<p>Exchanges, digital wallets, institutional traders, and developers can now all access NEAR USDC via the Circle Account and Circle APIs. This unlocks a whole range of use cases including:&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Making low cost payments and remittances globally in seconds.</li>



<li>24/7 trading, borrowing, and lending on apps like <a href="http://burrow.cash/">Burrow</a>, <a href="https://orderly.network/">Orderly</a>, and <a href="http://ref.finance/">Ref Finance</a>.</li>



<li>Enable users to hold savings in digital dollars without needing a traditional bank account.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Allow for enhanced cross-chain interoperability with other blockchains via NEAR’s extensive range of bridges.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>In the DeFi realm, Ref Finance will also launch its stable 4-pool on September 14 onwards. Trisolaris, Burrow, Orderly, VEAX and others are all planning on bringing USDC to its platforms within the coming weeks.  </p>



<p>USDC.e will still be supported by the ecosystem during the transition.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-getting-started-with-usdc">Getting started with USDC&nbsp;</h2>



<p>If you’re a business or project working on NEAR, you can readily access on/off-ramps for converting fiat currency to NEAR USDC by <a href="https://www.circle.com/en/circle-account">applying for a Circle Account</a>.</p>



<p>If you’re new to NEAR, you can find free resources for building apps, deploying smart contracts, creating B.O.S components, and more on the <a href="https://docs.near.org/#">DevRel resources page.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>For developers looking for documentation on building with USDC, check out Circle’s <a href="http://developers.circle.com/">developer docs</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/usdc-launches-natively-on-the-near-protocol/">USDC Launches Natively on the NEAR Protocol </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
