<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NEARCON Early Bird Tickets Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/nearcon-early-bird-tickets/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/nearcon-early-bird-tickets/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 13:52:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.orghttps://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>NEARCON Early Bird Tickets Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/nearcon-early-bird-tickets/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>NEARCON Returns: Here’s Everything You Need to Know So Far</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-returns-heres-everything-you-need-to-know-so-far/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 19:56:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON Early Bird Tickets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20642</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last year’s NEARCON was epic. NEARCON 2023 will be iconic.&#160; While all of you have been diligently building NEAR into …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-returns-heres-everything-you-need-to-know-so-far/">NEARCON Returns: Here’s Everything You Need to Know So Far</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last year’s NEARCON was epic. NEARCON 2023 will be iconic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While all of you have been diligently building NEAR into one of the best ecosystems in the blockchain world, NEAR Foundation has been planning a 4-day journey into an open web.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s take a quick look at everything we have to share (so far).&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-to-expect-at-nearcon-2023">What to expect at NEARCON 2023</h2>



<p>For this year’s NEARCON, we’re expanding. There will be two venues —&nbsp;NEARCON HQ and Hack HQ.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Most of the action will happen at NEARCON HQ. But if you’re a hacker, or just like hanging with them, you can do that at Hack HQ.</p>



<p>At NEARCON, you can expect to:</p>



<ul>
<li>Join 5,000+ delegates as we explore the power and possibilities of an open web</li>



<li>Encounter a diverse melting pot of creators, builders, policy makers, and more — you’ll even find the rare thought leader in their natural environment</li>



<li>Get inspired by talks from renowned authors, economists, artists, politicians, VCS, developers, entrepreneurs, and more</li>



<li>Explore the Blockchain Operating System (BOS), try it for yourself, and find out why it&#8217;s the driving force behind an open web&nbsp;</li>



<li>Connect with projects, speakers, community members, builders, and multi-chain enthusiasts from around the world</li>



<li>Hack the days and nights away for a chance to build on the BOS and win $180+k&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>



<li>And experience so much more that you&#8217;ll be looking around and asking yourself, “What bear market?”&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-get-your-early-bird-tickets-now">Get your early bird tickets now!</h2>



<p>NEARCON 2023 tickets are $20 off until July 1. So, don’t wait — snag your ticket for $79 now because after July 1st they are $99. </p>



<p>NEAR Foundation is also offering another deal. If you refer 4 friends to NEARCON 2023, you will get a special gift upon check-in at the conference.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-become-a-speaker-or-sponsor">Become a Speaker or Sponsor</h2>



<p>Thinking about becoming a NEARCON speaker? We’d love to hear from you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Speaking spots always go fast, so make haste. Apply to speak at NEARCON <a href="https://airtable.com/shru9TnZ53F7qZT9C">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Psstt… we&#8217;re looking for technical applications that don&#8217;t just shill but highlight problems being solved — on the BOS and the wider open web.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-apply-for-the-hackathon-and-get-in-for-free">Apply for the Hackathon and get in for free</h2>



<p>NEAR and NEARCON loves its hackers. And to show it, we’ve made it so that any builder or developer who applies for the hackathon gets in for free.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Find more information about the NEARCON 2023 hackathon <a href="https://nearcon-hackathon.devpost.com/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-returns-heres-everything-you-need-to-know-so-far/">NEARCON Returns: Here’s Everything You Need to Know So Far</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
