<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Collision Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/collision/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/collision/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 18:24:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Collision Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/collision/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>NEAR at Collision Highlights</title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-collision-highlights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 13:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Collision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women in Web3 Changemakers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Missed NEAR’s booth at Collision? We’ve got you covered with content from NEAR talks and panels. There were also a …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-collision-highlights/">NEAR at Collision Highlights</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Missed NEAR’s booth at Collision? We’ve got you covered with content from NEAR talks and panels. There were also a number of awesome announcements, including the big news out of Collision: Alibaba Cloud.</p>



<p>From the winners of the Women in Web3 Changemakers awards being announced to exciting ecosystem developments, here’s a run down on all things NEAR from Collision 2023!! </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">ICYMI: Major Announcements @ Collision</h2>



<p>NEAR kicked off Collision with a roar, with two major news items rolling hot off the presses yesterday. Here’s the scoop:&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>NEAR Foundation and Alibaba Cloud Join Forces&nbsp;</strong></h3>



<p>First off, the NEAR Foundation announced a major partnership with <a href="https://near.org/blog/near-and-alibaba-cloud-team-up-to-grow-the-open-web/">Alibaba Cloud</a>, the digital technology and intelligence backbone of Alibaba Group. The two will collaborate to offer Remote Procedure Calls (RPC) as a service and multi-chain data indexing to NEAR developers, users, and the broader ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The goal is to make building decentralized applications on the BOS a breeze, and working with one of the world’s biggest tech infrastructure companies is a huge step in the right direction. Alibaba Cloud will also enhance plug-and-play capabilities for BOS builders everywhere, from China and APAC to Europe and the Americas.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Winners of the Women of Web3 Changemakers Awards</strong></h3>



<p>In other news, the ten winners of the <a href="https://near.org/blog/web3s-leading-ladies-near-foundation-honors-2023s-women-changemakers/">Women in Web3 Changemakers</a> initiative were just announced. These incredible women are leading the charge in the Web3 space, and NEAR Foundation is proud to recognize their outstanding contributions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Selected from over 200 nominations and voted for by the public, these were chosen based on their inclusive and innovative ideas, impact within the Web3 space, and their contributions to significant projects. Read the full announcement for <a href="https://near.org/blog/web3s-leading-ladies-near-foundation-honors-2023s-women-changemakers/">NEAR&#8217;s Women in Web3 Changemakers winners</a>. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Highlights from NEAR at Collision&nbsp;</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-geekpay-breaks-barriers-in-crypto-transactions-on-near">Geekpay breaks barriers in crypto transactions on NEAR</h3>



<p><a href="https://www.geekpay.co/">GeekPay,</a> a crypto payments platform for businesses and freelancers built on NEAR, surpassed $500,000 in total transactions during Collision. It also just hit 205 verified users, companies, and 120 transactions. GeekPay is transforming how companies handle digital currency payments to contractors, eliminating the need for lengthy wallet addresses and providing greater security for cross-border transactions.</p>



<p>&#8220;NEAR is a perfect ecosystem and technology for cross-border payments in digital currencies for remote workers and contractors,&#8221; said Veronica Korzh, CEO and co-founder of GeekPay.</p>



<p>GeekPay supports a range of digital currencies including NEAR and ETH, including functionality with tracking and analytics, secure payment processing, invoicing, and transaction categorization. GeekPay hurdling the $400,000 transaction mark shows that the future of crypto payments for work is being built on the BOS.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-tenamint-launches-toronto-regional-community-with-a-bang">Tenamint launches Toronto Regional Community with a bang</h3>



<p><a href="https://tenamint.com/">Tenamint</a>, a marketplace for fractionalized trading card collectibles built on the NEAR blockchain, christened the launch of the NEAR Toronto Regional Community during the NEAR Toronto Launch Party. The soiree was held on an iconic yacht, the Yankee Lady, during a sunset cruise for an epic post-event party to cap off Collision.</p>



<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re thrilled to announce the launch of the NEAR Toronto Regional Community, a vibrant community dedicated to fostering collaboration, innovation, and growth in the Toronto region’s blockchain ecosystem,&#8221; said Sal Chaudhry, Tenamint co-founder and Toronto local.</p>



<p>&#8220;At the NEAR Toronto Regional Community, we’re on a mission to foster collaboration, education, and entrepreneurial support within the blockchain community,&#8221; Sal added. &#8220;We aim to empower individuals and businesses in Toronto and beyond to explore, adopt, and thrive in the world of blockchain technology and beyond,&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-after-collision-onward-to-ethcc">NEAR after Collision: Onward to ETHCC</h2>



<p>Collision 2023 is only beginning, but the BOS momentum won’t stop in Toronto. NEAR will also be at the Ethereum Community Conference (ETHCC) in Paris, from July 19th to 23rd.</p>



<p>From exciting cross-chain discussions to insightful panels, interactive workshops, and pitch events, ETHCC promises to be another remarkable platform for BOS building and the wider NEAR community.</p>



<p>So after immersing yourself in Collision 2023, remember to mark your calendars for <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/near-ethcc-tickets-655229297467?aff=oddtdtcreator">NEAR’s presence at ETHCC</a> as well. Here&#8217;s to continuing to make waves in Web3 and expanding into the Open Web – with you as the BOS!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-collision-highlights/">NEAR at Collision Highlights</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR at Collision: Start Your BOS Journey and Expand into the Open Web</title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-collision-start-your-bos-journey-and-expand-into-the-open-web/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Collision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Horizon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Collision is here. Today, June 26th through the 29th in Toronto, Ontario, NEAR experts will be on hand at Collision …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-collision-start-your-bos-journey-and-expand-into-the-open-web/">NEAR at Collision: Start Your BOS Journey and Expand into the Open Web</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Collision is here. Today, June 26th through the 29th in Toronto, Ontario, NEAR experts will be on hand at Collision to showcase how brands and companies can make a move into the Open Web with NEAR’s Blockchain Operating System (BOS). The BOS redefines the Web2-to-Web3 experience. Now anyone can effortlessly create and distribute decentralized applications, using any blockchain — all in one browser.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Don’t miss <a href="https://near.org/horizon">NEAR Horizon</a>, NEAR Foundation’s new Web3 startup support platform, which will also be at Collision. If you’re a founder or developer, then you will definitely want to meet with the Horizon team to get started on the Web3 funding and building journey.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here is what to expect from <a href="https://near.org/Collision">NEAR at Collision 2023</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-speaker-sessions-you-won-t-want-to-miss">NEAR Speaker Sessions you won’t want to miss</h2>



<p><strong>Tuesday, Jun 27, 12:00 &#8211; 12:45 PM</strong></p>



<p>Location: Beanfield Centre, Masterclass 1</p>



<p>Masterclass: “The Fastest Way to Add Web3 to Your App”</p>



<p>NEAR is transforming Web3 for developers, enterprises, and users alike with the Blockchain Operating System (BOS) – a common layer for browsing and discovering open web experiences compatible with any blockchain. NEAR founder Illia Polosukhin shows how the fastest onboarding in Web3 combined with decentralized frontends and embedded social features can help Web2 brands and Web3 projects deliver new &amp; easy experiences and grow their communities.</p>



<p>Speaker: Illia Polosukhin, NEAR Protocol, Co-founder</p>



<p><strong>Tuesday, Jun 27, 2:10 &#8211; 2:35 PM</strong></p>



<p>Location: Enercare Centre, MoneyConf</p>



<p>Fireside Chat: “<a href="https://collisionconf.com/schedule/cc23/timeslot/at-the-intersection-of-ai-and-web3">At the intersection of AI and Web3</a>”</p>



<p>Speakers:</p>



<ul>
<li>lllia Polosukhin, Near Protocol, Co-founder</li>



<li>Elad Gil, Investor</li>
</ul>



<p>Moderator: Lucinda Shen, Axios, Fintech Reporter</p>



<p><strong>Wednesday, Jun 28, 01:30 &#8211; 02:15 PM</strong></p>



<p>Location: Beanfield Centre, Masterclass 4</p>



<p>Masterclass: “How to Decentralize Any Frontend Using BOS”</p>



<p>Learn how to store your frontend codebase entirely on-chain and make it more accessible to users with NEAR&#8217;s Blockchain Operating System (BOS).</p>



<p>Speaker: Miao Jiang, Head of Product, Proximity Labs</p>



<p><strong>Wednesday, Jun 28, 02:30 &#8211; 03:15 PM</strong></p>



<p>Location: Beanfield Centre, Masterclass 4<br>Panel: “Charting the Course for a Thriving Web3 Ecosystem”</p>



<p>Delve into the current state of web3 investing, identify the crucial elements for building a thriving web3 ecosystem, and explore innovative strategies for scaling startup support platforms.</p>



<p>Speakers:</p>



<ul>
<li>Joyce Yang, Founder, Global Coin Research</li>



<li>Steven Chien, Founder, Press Start Capital</li>



<li>Paul Hsu, Co-founder, Decasonic</li>



<li>Moderator: Laura Cunningham, General Manager, NEAR Foundation</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Thursday, Jun 29, 12:23 &#8211; 12:27 PM</strong></p>



<p>Location: Enercare Centre, Growth Summit</p>



<p>Keynote: “Solving the Blockchain Enterprise Dilemma”</p>



<p>Speaker: Sandi Fatic, Co-founder, CEO, Calimero Network</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Events from the NEAR Community</h2>



<p><strong>June 27, 6-9 PM &#8211; </strong><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/near-horizon-pitch-networking-collision-2023-tickets-637516598307"><strong>NEAR Horizon Pitch &amp; Networking</strong></a><strong> | Collision 2023</strong></p>



<p>The NEAR Horizon team is partnering with VCs and Funding Teams from around the world who are looking to back exceptional entrepreneurs for the long term to build the future of Web3.</p>



<p><strong>June 28, 10 AM-8 PM &#8211; <a href="https://rngtickets.com/ticket-tier/NI7PLeJZQuxILJZCcqVQ/GA">Web3 Day (&amp; Night)</a> | Collision Conference Toronto</strong></p>



<p>An invite-only event for the Web3 community &amp; Web3 curious during the Collision conference in Toronto. Panels, speakers, networking, art, music, food &amp; drinks, pitch opportunities, and more.</p>



<p><strong>June 29, 6-9 PM &#8211; <a href="https://partiful.com/e/WQTbDeFjQyMFjVW0XhAk">NEAR Toronto Launch Party</a></strong><a href="https://partiful.com/e/WQTbDeFjQyMFjVW0XhAk"><strong><br></strong></a>An exhilarating event that marks the launch of the NEAR Toronto Regional Community and concludes the three-day Collision Conference.</p>



<p>Stay tuned to <a href="https://near.org/Collision">Near.org/collision</a> for the latest event updates.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-collision-start-your-bos-journey-and-expand-into-the-open-web/">NEAR at Collision: Start Your BOS Journey and Expand into the Open Web</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR at Collision: Expand into the Open Web with the Blockchain Operating System</title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-collision-expand-into-the-open-web-with-the-blockchain-operating-system/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 07:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Collision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce that NEAR is heading to the 2023 edition of Collision from June 26-29 in …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-collision-expand-into-the-open-web-with-the-blockchain-operating-system/">NEAR at Collision: Expand into the Open Web with the Blockchain Operating System</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce that NEAR is heading to the 2023 edition of <a href="https://near.org/collision">Collision</a> from June 26-29 in Toronto, Ontario. </p>



<p>NEAR experts will be at Collision to demonstrate how brands and companies can expand into the open web using the Blockchain Operating System (BOS). The BOS is&nbsp; an industry-first category: a common layer for browsing and discovering open web experiences with any blockchain — all in one browser.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here is what to expect from NEAR at Collision 2023.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-bos-and-near-horizon-at-collision">The BOS and NEAR Horizon at Collision&nbsp;</h2>



<p>If you saw <a href="https://near.org/blog/near-announces-the-blockchain-operating-system/?_gl=1*1l4nodm*_up*MQ..*_ga*MTY2MDg5OTA4NC4xNjc5Njg5NTUw*_ga_9GWCXQJ62J*MTY3OTY4OTU0Ny4xLjAuMTY3OTY4OTU0Ny4wLjAuMA..">NEAR’s big announcement</a> out of ETHDenver and Collision, NEAR isn’t just a Layer 1 blockchain. It’s a Blockchain Operating System that makes it easy to use the tools you already know to build apps that engage users, while fostering an open web free from centralized platforms.</p>



<p>Also appearing at Collision will be NEAR Horizon — NEAR Foundation’s new Web3 startup support platform. Meet with the Horizon team and get started on the Web3 funding and building journey.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">NEAR speakers at Collision</h2>



<p>At Collision, catch a number of exciting NEAR speakers and sessions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Illia Polosukhin &#8211; Co-founder, NEAR Protocol; CEO, Pagoda</p>



<p>Elad Gil &#8211; Investor</p>



<p>Kendall Cole &#8211; Founder, Proximity</p>



<p>Laura Cunningham &#8211; General Manager, NEAR Horizon</p>



<p>Joyce Yang &#8211; Founder, Global Coin Research</p>



<p>Steven Chien &#8211;&nbsp; Founder, Press Start Capital</p>



<p>Paul Hsu &#8211; CEO &amp; Founder, Decasonic</p>



<p>Stay updated on the complete slate of confirmed speakers at <a href="https://near.org/collision">near.org/Collision</a>. </p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://near.org/collision"><strong>NEAR @ Collision</strong></a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">NEAR Horizon pitch and networking event</h2>



<p>NEAR Horizon will be hosting another Pitch and networking event with VC partners the evening of June 27th. <a href="https://airtable.com/shr0AmrMYNHnINZiK">Applications to pitch</a> are being accepted now through June 7th.&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/near-horizon-pitch-networking-collision-2023-tickets-637516598307"><strong>RSVP to Horizon Pitch and Networking Event</strong></a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-collision-expand-into-the-open-web-with-the-blockchain-operating-system/">NEAR at Collision: Expand into the Open Web with the Blockchain Operating System</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
