<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NEARCON Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/nearcon/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/nearcon/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 06:51:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>NEARCON Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/nearcon/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Welcome to NEARCON ‘23: Step Into the Open Web</title>
		<link>/blog/welcome-to-nearcon-23-step-into-the-open-web/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 14:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21050</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hello NEARians! Welcome to the 3rd annual NEARCON in the always lovely and scenic Lisbon, Portugal. The NEAR Community is …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/welcome-to-nearcon-23-step-into-the-open-web/">Welcome to NEARCON ‘23: Step Into the Open Web</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hello NEARians!</p>



<p>Welcome to the 3rd annual NEARCON in the always lovely and scenic Lisbon, Portugal. The NEAR Community is out in force for NEARCON ‘23, with around 3,000 delegates here to explore the power and possibilities of an open web.</p>



<p>A number of exciting protocol and ecosystem announcements are planned over from November 7-10th. We’re thrilled to have you all here to get inspired by talks from renowned authors, economists, artists, politicians, developers, entrepreneurs, and many others helping to build an open web.</p>



<p>NEARCON ‘23 is the perfect opportunity to meet and network with a wide variety of projects, speakers, community members, builders, and multi-chain enthusiasts from across the globe. And if you’re here to build, then we look forward to seeing what you put together for the NEAR IRL Hackathon, for which $140K+ in prizes are up for grabs!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-finding-the-nearcon-23-venues">Finding the NEARCON 23 venues&nbsp;</h2>



<p>NEARCON ‘23 will unfold across three different venues. NEAR Foundation designed and optimized each space for talks, demonstrations, hackathons, and more. You can find the three NEARCON venues here:</p>



<p>NEARCON HQ<br>Convento Do Beato<br>Alameda do Beato 40, 1950-042<br>Lisboa, Portugal</p>



<p>Hacker HQ<br>Armazem 16<br>R. Pereira Henriques nº1, 1950-242<br>Lisboa, Portugal</p>



<p>Community HQ<br>Rua Pereira Henriques<br>31950-242<br>Lisboa, Portugal</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ncon-what-it-is-and-how-to-use-it">NCON: What it is and how to use it</h2>



<p>For NEARCON ‘23, NEAR Foundation partnered with Jutsu, Keypom, and Veriken to create a novel conference experience — the NCON token, an event experience built on the Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S). In many ways, NCON is the embodiment of the open web, where users seamlessly transact with each other on a peer-to-peer network.</p>



<p>With NCON, you can attend content sessions, interact with sponsors, pay for your lunch, and more. You can even complete NCON Bounties, for which you’ll be rewarded NCON that can be redeemed for swag, lunches, and other goodies during NEARCON ‘23.</p>



<p><a href="/blog/introducing-ncon-and-how-to-use-it-at-nearcon-23/?_gl=1%2Ar05aze%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMzE5MjA3NjA1LjE2OTkzNjI3NzE.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5OTM2Mjc2OC4xLjEuMTY5OTM2NDA0OS4wLjAuMA..">More NCON details</a>. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-tracks-for-developers-entrepreneurs-creatives-and-regulators">Tracks for Developers, Entrepreneurs, Creatives, and Regulators</h2>



<p>To make this year’s NEARCON even more iconic than last year, we’ve created a diverse set of tracks for attendees. There is something for every type of open web enthusiast.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Developers </strong>— Devs should drop in on a number of hands-on workshops and coding sessions. These are the best sessions for getting first-hand looks at NEAR’s latest open web innovations.</li>



<li><strong>Entrepreneurs</strong> — A track designed for the open web entrepreneur. Web3 industry leaders will be on-site to share the best insights, strategies, and advice on turning an idea into the next best open web startup.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Creatives</strong> — Artists, musicians, marketers, and more are a major part of the NEAR community. The Creatives track is designed to deliver the latest insights into the creative process for NEARCON attendees.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Regulators</strong> — Top legal and regulatory talent will help open web developers and founders get the latest information on best practices, legal frameworks, and future regulatory development.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ai-is-near-the-future-of-ai-on-the-open-web">AI is NEAR: The Future of AI on the Open Web</h2>



<p>We’re all excited about AI and blockchain, and this is reflected in a special track for NEARCON ’23 — “AI is NEAR”. NEAR co-founder Illia Polosukhin, a pioneer in the world of AI, will be leading the charge. Check out the “AI is NEAR” track over at <a href="http://nearcon.org/">nearcon.org</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-get-your-badge-beat-the-lines-and-register-for-the-hackathon">Get your badge, beat the lines, and register for the hackathon</h2>



<p>November 7th is the perfect day to drop by to get your badge and register for the hackathon. Beat the lines and get settled in!</p>



<p>You can also drop by the Registration Party sponsored by Octopus Network, G20, and Glass at the Layer 1 Stage (Convento Do Beato). From 5-7pm, join the hackathon orientation and NDC’s Proof of Pizza at Hacker HQ from 5-7pm, then don your party hat for NEARWEEK’s evening party from 7-11pm! </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-a-look-ahead-to-nearcon-day-1-november-8th">A look ahead to NEARCON Day 1 — November 8th</h2>



<p>Doors open at 9:00am.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Join us bright and early for breakfast before a number of welcome sessions from various NEARCON stages, and earn some NCON for being an early riser!</p>



<p>NEARCON Day 1 will feature a variety of talks and panels, from NEAR UX and DeFi, to decentralized storage, Web3 community building, and much more.</p>



<p>Check out the <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1YazWMBGw8lEC3BHnmX2LJkV_2PgR2kJ6zAhN5eD4ucA/edit">full Day 1 schedule</a> now to plan for the day’s events!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/welcome-to-nearcon-23-step-into-the-open-web/">Welcome to NEARCON ‘23: Step Into the Open Web</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet the Builders of the Open Web: Top Speakers at NEARCON &#8217;23</title>
		<link>/blog/meet-the-builders-of-the-open-web-top-speakers-at-nearcon-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 18:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON ‘23]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON Speakers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you thought last year&#8217;s NEARCON was epic, then wait until you see what’s in store for NEARCON &#8217;23 in …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/meet-the-builders-of-the-open-web-top-speakers-at-nearcon-23/">Meet the Builders of the Open Web: Top Speakers at NEARCON &#8217;23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you thought last year&#8217;s NEARCON was epic, then wait until you see what’s in store for NEARCON &#8217;23 in Lisbon, kicking off on November 7th. From deep dives into the open web to insightful sessions featuring global leaders in blockchain and the open web, here’s the inside scoop on what to expect at this year’s iconic edition.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-awaits-you-at-nearcon-23">What awaits you at NEARCON &#8217;23</h2>



<p>NEARCON &#8217;23 is set to be a smorgasbord of innovation and collaboration. Taking place across three venues in Lisbon, including the historic Convento Do Beato, and spanning four days, NEARCON ‘23 attendees will have access to an array of exciting opportunities. From enlightening talks on AI and Web3&#8217;s future to hands-on developer hackathons, there’s something for everyone.</p>



<p>You also won’t want to miss exclusive networking sessions that connect you with NEAR and multi-chain enthusiasts and projects from around the globe. Attendees also get a firsthand experience with building on the Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S.).</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-meet-the-big-brains-of-nearcon-23">Meet the Big Brains of NEARCON &#8217;23</h2>



<p>There’s an incredible lineup of speakers and thought leaders scheduled for this year’s edition of NEARCON. Here’s a rundown of some of top names you’ll on various stages, panels and sessions:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Mitchell Amador: </strong>Founder and CEO of <a href="https://immunefi.com/">Immunefi</a>. Mitchell is a leading voice in blockchain security and will explore how incentivized bounties enhance security.</li>



<li><strong>James Young:</strong> The Co-founder and CCO of <a href="https://www.collab.land/">Collab.Land</a> will delve into the power of tokenized communities, from governance to engagement.</li>



<li><strong>Samantha Bohbot:</strong> Chief Growth Officer at <a href="https://rockawayx.com/">RockawayX</a>. An expert in strategic growth, Samantha will share essential tips for project scalability.</li>



<li><strong>Se Hyun Oh: </strong>SVP at <a href="https://www.sktelecom.com/index_en.html">SK Telecom</a>. Expect insights into the convergence of telecom, AI, and the open web.</li>



<li><strong>Michael Casey:</strong> Chief Content Officer at <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/">CoinDesk</a>. Michael will dissect the evolving narratives around cryptocurrency and its impact on the traditional financial sector.</li>



<li><strong>Richard Muirhead:</strong> Managing Partner at <a href="https://fabric.vc/">Fabric Ventures</a>. Hear a venture capitalist’s perspective on what makes a blockchain project investable.</li>



<li><strong>Oleg Fomenko:</strong> Co-founder of <a href="https://sweatco.in/">Sweat Economy</a>. Join the discussion on how blockchain is revolutionizing health and fitness via Move-to-Earn.</li>



<li><strong>Nicolai Reinbold:</strong> Global Head of Expansion and Innovation at <a href="https://www.cvlabs.com/">CV Labs</a>. Nicolai will cover blockchain innovation hubs and their role in nurturing early-stage startups.</li>



<li><strong>Teana Baker-Taylor</strong>: <a href="https://www.circle.com/en/">Circle’s</a> VP of Policy and Regulatory Strategy for the EU/UK. She’ll address the regulatory landscape surrounding blockchain and cryptocurrencies.</li>



<li><strong>Joy Macknight</strong>: The editor at <a href="https://www.thebanker.com/">The Banker</a> will offer an overview of how the open web and blockchain are disrupting traditional banking systems.<br>Check out the <a href="https://nearcon.app/speakers">complete list of NEARCON 23&#8242; Speakers</a>, full of founders, builders, VCs, and other open web innovators. </li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-maximizing-your-nearcon-23-experience">Maximizing your NEARCON &#8217;23 experience</h2>



<p>While the speakers are a definite draw, NEARCON &#8217;23 is more than just speaker sessions. You can also join the <a href="/blog/nearcon-irl-hackathon-2023-build-the-open-web/?_gl=1%2A41qcf0%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AOTY3ODAzMDQ2LjE2OTc2NDc0ODk.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5NzY0NzQ4Ny4xLjEuMTY5NzY0ODExNS4wLjAuMA..">NEARCON IRL Hackathon</a> where developers will have the chance to build directly on the B.O.S and compete for over $140,000 in prizes. In case you didn’t already know, NEARCON is free for hackers participating in the hackathon! At NEARCON ‘23, there’s something for just about everyone.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-four-distinct-paths-to-explore-at-nearcon-23">Four Distinct Paths to Explore at NEARCON &#8217;23</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Developers: </strong>Engage in technical workshops and learn from the best in the business. These sessions are designed to meet you at any point in your open web journey.</li>



<li><strong>Entrepreneurs</strong>: Explore how the open web can revolutionize the way businesses connect and engage with users through innovative products and solutions.</li>



<li><strong>Creators:</strong> Discover how the open web can disrupt traditional systems, offering more equitable platforms for creators to get discovered and fairly compensated.</li>



<li><strong>Regulators:</strong> Stay up-to-date with the evolving regulations and policies that are shaping the open web, keeping you ahead of the curve.</li>
</ul>



<p>And don&#8217;t forget the networking opportunities, where you’ll get a chance to collaborate and engage in exciting conversations with NEAR community members from around the world.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-don-t-miss-the-future-at-nearcon-23">Don&#8217;t miss the future at NEARCON &#8217;23</h2>



<p>Your chance to explore the entire NEAR ecosystem and the B.O.S is right around the corner. So, come play a part in driving the open web towards mass adoption. And with General Admission ticket prices still available, NEARCON ‘23 is still a steal for anyone interested in helping shape the future of blockchain and decentralization.</p>



<p>So what are you waiting for? <a href="https://tickets.nearcon.org/?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_campaign=google_events_nearcon_conversion_gl&amp;utm_content=nearcon_non-brand_blockchain-crypto-web3_gl______T1300&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwhL6pBhDjARIsAGx8D5-H2EpU3t-EF2qlg6YDwlzx5HgVqTUboWoe5nftEla82nDzSqVG1YUaAuJ9EALw_wcB">Register for NEARCON &#8217;23</a> to secure your spot today. And if you’re a <a href="/blog/%d1%83%d0%bd%d1%96%d0%ba%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bb%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2-%d0%b1/?_gl=1%2A41qcf0%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AOTY3ODAzMDQ2LjE2OTc2NDc0ODk.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5NzY0NzQ4Ny4xLjEuMTY5NzY0ODExNS4wLjAuMA..">Ukrainian</a> living in Portugal, or a student in <a href="/blog/estudantes-terao-ingressos-gratis-no-nearcon23/?_gl=1%2A1897020%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AOTY3ODAzMDQ2LjE2OTc2NDc0ODk.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5NzY0NzQ4Ny4xLjAuMTY5NzY0NzQ4Ny4wLjAuMA..">Portugal</a> or <a href="/blog/entradas-gratuitas-a-nearcon-23-para-estudiantes-en-espana/?_gl=1%2A41qcf0%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AOTY3ODAzMDQ2LjE2OTc2NDc0ODk.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5NzY0NzQ4Ny4xLjEuMTY5NzY0ODExNS4wLjAuMA..">Spain</a>, click those links for more information on how to register and attend NEARCON ‘23 in Lisbon for absolutely free!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/meet-the-builders-of-the-open-web-top-speakers-at-nearcon-23/">Meet the Builders of the Open Web: Top Speakers at NEARCON &#8217;23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Built on NEAR: Celebrating Partners and Innovators at NEARCON &#8217;23</title>
		<link>/blog/built-on-near-celebrating-partners-and-innovators-at-nearcon-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 15:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Partnerships are one of the biggest pillars to expanding NEAR’s footprint. They help drive the ecosystem toward fostering new and …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/built-on-near-celebrating-partners-and-innovators-at-nearcon-23/">Built on NEAR: Celebrating Partners and Innovators at NEARCON &#8217;23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Partnerships are one of the biggest pillars to expanding NEAR’s footprint. They help drive the ecosystem toward fostering new and innovative use cases that will bring the next billion users to the open web. And that&#8217;s exactly what&#8217;s happening on NEAR, with partnerships ranging from sports to social taking center stage. At NEARCON&nbsp;— <a href="https://near.org/blog/nearcon-the-ultimate-web3-education-for-only-99">the ultimate Web3 education</a> — a number of NEAR partners will be on-hand to talk about Web3 partnerships and innovation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Throughout the past few years, NEAR has engaged, collaborated, and built with partners who share the vision of a decentralized, user-centric open web. Each partnership is contributing their unique, innovative flair to the ecosystem, with a scalable, user-friendly blockchain helping to propel their efforts.</p>



<p>As NEARCON ‘23 approaches, let’s celebrate and explore how NEAR&#8217;s collaborations and partnerships are shaping the future of the open web. By registering for and attending NEARCON ‘23, you’ll be able to meet some of the following founders, entrepreneurs, and innovators below.</p>



<p>And these names are just the tip of the iceberg, so don’t forget to register for NEARCON ‘23 and let’s take part in learning, networking, and building an open web together.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://nearcon.app/">Register $99</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-creating-consumer-fun-and-engagement-in-the-open-web">Creating consumer fun and engagement in the open web</h2>



<p>An area where NEAR partnerships are thriving is making the blockchain more fun and engaging for the masses. NEAR’s partnership with NFT launchpad <a href="https://www.mintbase.xyz/">Mintbase</a> is a perfect illustration. Mintbase recently celebrated the traditional Indian festival, Raksha Bandhan, by seamlessly <a href="/blog/mintbase-brings-new-open-web-wallet-tech-to-families-celebrating-raksha-bandhan/">transforming photos into NFTs</a> on the NEAR blockchain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During Raksha Bandan, sisters tie a good-luck talisman around the wrists of their brothers, a special moment often photographed and cherished by families. With Mintbase’s open web wallet built on NEAR, users could easily create an account without seed phrases and seamlessly upload their photos, transforming them into NFTs in an instant.</p>



<p>Let’s also toast to&nbsp; <a href="http://www.glass.fun/">GLASS</a>, a one-of-a-kind Web3 platform that empowers alcohol brands to engage directly with consumers. Built on the NEAR blockchain, spirit brands can <a href="/blog/how-glass-is-uncorking-adult-beverage-loyalty-with-web3-and-near/">issue token rewards</a> and other blockchain perks to social drinkers who try new cocktail recipes, socialize with friends, and vote on brand decisions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gaming is also a key entry point into the open web, and NEAR&#8217;s partnership with <a href="https://playember.com/">PlayEmber</a> is kicking the door wide open. PlayEmber’s creative gaming studio is fusing AAA quality mobile games on the blockchain, with NEAR providing the backend foundation. Decentralized mobile gaming experiences are now becoming more accessible to a wider audience.</p>



<p>Then there’s <a href="https://cosmose.co/">Cosmose AI&#8217;s</a> KaiKai, a fusion of shopping, retail, and gamification dubbed&#8221;Shoppertainment.&#8221; Built on NEAR’s Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S), <a href="/blog/cosmose-and-near-foundation-set-to-revolutionize-retail-with-web3-and-ai/?_gl=1%2A1yt7etu%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2ANjE0MjI4NTkyLjE2OTcwMzUyNTQ.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5NzAzNTI1Mi4xLjAuMTY5NzAzNTI1Mi4wLjAuMA..">KaiKai offers a captivating brand discovery</a> avenue, with features like Augmented Reality (AR) product interactions, exclusive product drops, and celebrity live streams.&nbsp;</p>



<p>More than just a shopping app, KaiKai also uses a native cryptocurrency, Kai-Ching. Shoppers earn rewards with the help of Cosmose&#8217;s AI-powered personalization, all while transacting on the NEAR blockchain. It’s all about enhancing personalization, user empowerment, and engagements in the retail space with a unique, powerful blockchain twist.</p>



<p>And in a fusion of health and blockchain, <a href="https://sweatco.in/">Sweatcoin’s</a> partnership with NEAR helps people earn SWEAT tokens with literally every step towards better fitness. With a user base of over 63 million who&#8217;ve clocked in more than 19 trillion steps, Sweatcoin and NEAR are incentivizing&nbsp; healthier lifestyles.</p>



<p>Oleg Fomenko, co-founder of Sweatcoin, believes in the <a href="https://near.org/blog/sweatcoin-partners-with-near-foundation-to-create-a-new-movement-economy">potential of merging health and blockchain</a>, enabling users to “walk into the world of crypto.” This partnership, built on the NEAR blockchain, personifies the next level of open web adoption, encouraging physical wellness via crypto-based rewards.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-financial-empowerment-and-innovation-on-near">Financial empowerment and innovation on NEAR</h2>



<p>One of the biggest challenges that the open web is addressing is financial empowerment and inclusion. NEAR Foundation’s partnerships in this area are helping bring that vision to life. The Foundation’s collaboration with Proximity Labs is helping talented builders create innovative Web3 financial solutions, with substantial grants and support.</p>



<p>Calimero Network is another example of NEAR&#8217;s commitment to financial innovation. Calimero provides what’s called ‘private sharding’ infrastructure, a feature that ensures&nbsp; data privacy in Web3 finance without sacrificing the power of open-source platforms. With both <a href="https://www.theblock.co/post/204235/private-sharding-startup-calimero-network-raises-8-5-million">financial and technical support from NEAR</a>, more business can be safely conducted on the blockchain.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-building-the-technical-foundation-for-tomorrow-s-open-web">Building the technical foundation for tomorrow’s open web</h2>



<p>The ongoing partnership between NEAR Protocol and <a href="https://oct.network/">Octopus Network</a> signifies the ecosystem’s infrastructure strides. Early on, Octopus Network selected NEAR as its “mother-chain” protocol citing speed ability to accommodate a large user base. Octopus Network and NEAR are paving the way for developers aiming to launch tailored applications using their own dedicated blockchains —&nbsp;also known as “Appchains” —&nbsp;making deployment a breeze.</p>



<p>Partnering with a tech infrastructure behemoth like <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/startups/near-building-useable-web3-infrastructure-on-google-cloud">Google Cloud</a> is another way of giving Web3 startups pathways to world-class startup expertise. It’s all part of NEAR’s commitment to making blockchain solutions more accessible, robust, and primed for mainstream adoption.</p>



<p>In collaboration with <a href="https://urbit.org/">Urbit</a>, NEAR is also continuing to make the open web more user friendly. Urbit’s vision — shared and supported by the NEAR Foundation — is to improve the frontend experience of open web apps. Urbit allows developers to easily create sleek designs so that tomorrow’s decentralized applications are as seamless as the most popular ones in the App Store.</p>



<p>On another front, NEAR&#8217;s collaboration with <a href="https://sailgp.com/">SailGP</a> is bringing Decentralized Autonomous Organizations (DAOs) to professional sports, creating a bridge between leagues and fans. The introduction of a DAO-owned racing team on the NEAR Protocol gives fans a novel way to engage, interact with, and participate in active decision making along with teams and athletes.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-partnership-innovation-rolls-on-at-nearcon">Partnership innovation rolls on at NEARCON</h2>



<p>Past, current, and future partnership will take center stage at NEARCON 2023 — now less than a month away. It’ll be four full days of full immersion into the NEAR ecosystem —&nbsp;a place for you to truly step into the open web. Build on the B.O.S and network with thousands of other blockchain enthusiasts. Get the inside scoop on onboarding Web2 companies into Web3 with Google Cloud’s James Tromans, and get the low down on SWEAT with Oleg Fomenko.</p>



<p>From raising a glass to blockchain brand loyalty with GLASS and setting sail towards new DAO horizons with SailGP, each and every NEAR partner is playing its own pivotal role in crafting how tomorrow’s open web experiences will look, feel, and even taste. Better decentralized infrastructure, financial empowerment, and exciting consumer experiences are just the start.</p>



<p><em>Ready to dive into sessions, hackathons, and more in Lisbon at NEARCON 2023? Go ahead and </em><a href="https://tickets.nearcon.org/"><em>register now</em></a><em> to secure your spot.</em></p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://nearcon.app/">Register $99</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/built-on-near-celebrating-partners-and-innovators-at-nearcon-23/">Built on NEAR: Celebrating Partners and Innovators at NEARCON &#8217;23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Estudantes terão ingressos grátis no NEARCON’23</title>
		<link>/blog/estudantes-terao-ingressos-gratis-no-nearcon23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 17:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Estudantes do mundo inteiro estão interessados em Web3. Se você é um estudante em Portugal e quer aprender mais sobre …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/estudantes-terao-ingressos-gratis-no-nearcon23/">Estudantes terão ingressos grátis no NEARCON’23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Estudantes do mundo inteiro estão interessados em Web3. Se você é um estudante em Portugal e quer aprender mais sobre o mundo do Web3 não precisa procurar mais. NEARCON 2023 em Lisboa será o melhor lugar para aprender sobre a ‘open web’ (internet aberta).</p>



<p>Para começar sua jornada educacional na Web3, a Fundação NEAR tem uma excelente oferta para você! Estudantes registados em Portugal terão acesso a um número limitado de ingressos para o maior evento do ano, o NEARCON ‘23. O evento será em Lisboa, do dia 7 a 10 de Novembro (mais detalhes sobre como conseguir o ingresso abaixo).</p>



<p><strong>O que é o NEARCON?</strong></p>



<p>Para quem ainda não sabe, NEAR é uma blockchain, um ecossistema e uma comunidade internacional de desenvolvedores, criadores, fundadores e visionários da descentralização.</p>



<p>NEARCON será um evento de 4 dias celebrando a NEAR, o sistema operacional para blockchain na internet aberta (Blockchain Operating System &#8211; B.O.S). A internet aberta é como a internet deveria ser. Uma nova internet onde todos terão a chance de criar, participar e ganhar incentivos pelos seus dados, ideias e contribuições. NEAR é um dos únicos ecossistemas que podem trazer a internet aberta para todos.</p>



<p>Todos os anos a comunidade da NEAR se junta para ouvir, aprender, se conectar e desenvolver ideias inspiradoras para o futuro. NEARCON será o melhor lugar para aprender as últimas novidades da internet aberta!</p>



<p>Se você não tem certeza o que a Web3 é, ou como o crypto funciona, esse é o seu lugar. Um dos projetos mais descentralizados, a NEAR tem paixão em conectar e inspirar a próxima geração de talentos em tecnologia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEARCON 2023 vai ser o maior evento educacional de Web3 &#8211; e o número de ingressos gratuitos é limitado. Garanta o seu!</p>



<p><strong>O que você vai aprender no NEARCON ‘23</strong></p>



<p>O ecossistema em Web3 contém muitos setores, e nós temos a sorte de contar com muitas das mais brilhantes mentes no NEARCON esse ano. Palestras, painéis e conversas nos seguintes tópicos:</p>



<ul>
<li>Internet aberta &#8211; aprenda como a tecnologia aberta e seus ideais se juntam em blockchains como NEAR para a criação de uma internet onde todos podem aproveitar o controle dos seus dados, ideias e criações.</li>



<li>AI &amp; Blockchain &#8211; o co-fundador da NEAR, Illia Polosukhin, vai te ensinar como blockchain e inteligência artificial podem trabalhar juntos em 2023 e no futuro.</li>



<li>Descentralização &#8211; Veja como a NEAR Digital Collective (NDC) está contribuindo para a descentralização do ecossistema.</li>



<li>Leis e regulamentação &#8211; se informe sobre os últimos desenvolvimentos no setor.</li>
</ul>



<p>Garanta seu ingresso grátis para o NEARCON ‘23</p>



<p>É fácil garantir o seu ingresso grátis. Para conseguir o seu cupom de desconto, você precisa:</p>



<ul>
<li>Ser estudante registrado em Portugal</li>



<li>Ser maior de 18 anos</li>



<li>Estar disponível para ir ao evento entre 7 a 10 de Novembro em pessoa.</li>
</ul>



<p>Para acessar o cupom de desconto [DISCOUNT CODE], acesse a página do [NEARCON ‘23- add link]. Você vai precisar completar o formulário (preencha todas as informacoes). O site vai direcionar você à página de pagamento, mas não se preocupe, aqui você vai poder adicionar o cupom de desconto. O recibo com o ingresso será enviado para você.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/estudantes-terao-ingressos-gratis-no-nearcon23/">Estudantes terão ingressos grátis no NEARCON’23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Entradas Gratuitas a NEARCON ‘23 para Estudiantes en España</title>
		<link>/blog/entradas-gratuitas-a-nearcon-23-para-estudiantes-en-espana/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 17:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Si eres estudiante universitario en España y estás interesado en aprender sobre Web3, la Fundación NEAR tiene una gran noticia …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/entradas-gratuitas-a-nearcon-23-para-estudiantes-en-espana/">Entradas Gratuitas a NEARCON ‘23 para Estudiantes en España</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Si eres estudiante universitario en España y estás interesado en aprender sobre Web3, la Fundación NEAR tiene una gran noticia para ti. ¡Estamos ofreciendo un número limitado de entradas gratuitas a universitarios para NEARCON ‘23!, nuestro evento insignia en Lisboa, del 7 al 10 de noviembre (más detalles sobre elegibilidad debajo).&nbsp;</p>



<p>No importa si nunca usaste una blockchain, o si eres nuevo en el mundo del Web3. NEARCON es el mejor lugar para aprender sobre Web3 y cómo ésta contribuye a la Web Abierta.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-que-es-nearcon">¿Qué es NEARCON?</h3>



<p>Si nunca escuchaste hablar de NEAR, NEAR es a la vez una blockchain, un ecosistema, y una comunidad internacional de desarrolladores, emprendedores, y visionarios de la descentralización.</p>



<p>Una de las principales misiones de NEAR es hacer realidad la visión de una web abierta. Esto es, una web donde todo el mundo puede crear, participar y ser recompensado por sus datos, ideas y esfuerzo.</p>



<p>NEARCON es el evento insignia de 4 días destinado a NEAR, donde todos los años la comunidad se junta a debatir, conectar y colaborar en ideas que contribuyan a desarrollar una web abierta.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index">NEARCON 2023</a> ofrece lo mejor en educación Web3, y hay entradas gratuitas disponibles para un número limitado de universitarios.</p>



<p>No importa si eres nuevo en el universo Blockchain, NEAR tiene una pasión por involucrar e inspirar a la próxima generación de talentos Web3, ¡y NEARCON es el lugar donde aprender lo último en tecnología Web3 y la web abierta!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/entradas-gratuitas-a-nearcon-23-para-estudiantes-en-espana/">Entradas Gratuitas a NEARCON ‘23 para Estudiantes en España</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Унікальна можливість для українців: Безкоштовні квитки на NEARCON ‘23</title>
		<link>/blog/%d1%83%d0%bd%d1%96%d0%ba%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bb%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2-%d0%b1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 18:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON ‘23]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEARCON &#8217;23 &#8211; це багатоденна конференція, яка збирає найяскравіших представників блокчейн-індустрії з усього світу. Це місце, де ви зможете почути …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/%d1%83%d0%bd%d1%96%d0%ba%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bb%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2-%d0%b1/">Унікальна можливість для українців: Безкоштовні квитки на NEARCON ‘23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEARCON &#8217;23 &#8211; це багатоденна конференція, яка збирає найяскравіших представників блокчейн-індустрії з усього світу. Це місце, де ви зможете почути найсвіжіші ідеї, познайомитися зі світовими експертами та знайти натхнення для вашої майбутньої кар&#8217;єри. NEARCON &#8217;23 пропонує широкий спектр тематик, включаючи штучний інтелект, кібербезпеку, блокчейн, веб-розробку та багато іншого.</p>



<p>Як невеликий акт солідарності, NEAR Foundation пропонує обмежену кількість БЕЗКОШТОВНИХ квитків для українців, які живуть у Португалії чи Іспанії, на NEARCON ‘23, що відбудеться в Лісабоні з 7 по 10 листопада.</p>



<p>Це неймовірна можливість познайомитися зі світом Web3, розширити свої знання та знайти нові можливості для кар&#8217;єрного зростання. Не пропустіть цю унікальну можливість та отримайте безкоштовний квиток на NEARCON &#8217;23 вже сьогодні!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-що-таке-nearcon">Що таке NEARCON?</h3>



<p>Ті, хто не знайомі з Web3, можуть не бути обізнані, що NEAR &#8211; це блокчейн, екосистема та міжнародна спільнота розробників, підприємців, фаундерів і провідних фігур у сфері децентралізації.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="http://nearcon.org/">NEARCON</a> &#8211; це основна щорічна подія для NEAR. Кожного року спільнота NEAR збирається, щоб слухати, навчатися, спілкуватися та розробляти надихаючі ідеї для майбутнього.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEARCON &#8211; це найкраща освіта в галузі Web3! Як провідний децентралізований проект у світі, NEAR прагне привернути та надихати наступне покоління талантів Web3 з обмеженою кількістю безкоштовних місць.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-що-ви-дізнаєтесь-на-nearcon-2023">Що ви дізнаєтесь на NEARCON 2023</h3>



<p>Web3 складається з кількох ключових ролей і секторів, і на NEARCON ‘23 ми матимемо можливість почути виступи та взяти участь у панельних дискусіях із провідними фігурами в галузі Web3.&nbsp;</p>



<p>На NEARCON будуть обговорюватися такі теми як Open Web, де використовуються технології з відкритим кодом, включаючи NEAR. Також буде розглядатися взаємодія блокчейну та штучного інтелекту сьогодні та їхні перспективи в майбутньому, а також роль <a href="https://www.neardc.org/">NEAR Digital Collective</a> у децентралізації управління NEAR. Крім того, будуть поширені оновлення щодо регулювання та політики в сфері Web3.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-як-отримати-безкоштовний-квиток-на-nearcon-23">Як отримати безкоштовний квиток на NEARCON ‘23</h3>



<p>Отримати безкоштовні квиток на NEARCON ‘23 просто!&nbsp;</p>



<p>Основні вимоги включають:</p>



<ul>
<li>Ви є українцем, що тимчасово проживає в Іспанії/Португалії</li>



<li>Ваш вік більше за 18 років</li>



<li>Ви можете відвідати подію особисто в Лісабоні з 7 по 10 листопада</li>
</ul>



<p>Щоб отримати безкоштовний квиток на NEARCON &#8217;23, переходьте за <a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index?tab=register">посиланням</a>, заповніть форму аплікації. Вас буде перенаправлено до завершення оплати, де ви введете код знижки <strong>«UKFRENSNCON»</strong>. Ви отримаєте квитанцію на ваш імейл, і квиток буде надіслано вам пізніше перед NEARCON ‘23.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/%d1%83%d0%bd%d1%96%d0%ba%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bb%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2-%d0%b1/">Унікальна можливість для українців: Безкоштовні квитки на NEARCON ‘23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON: The Ultimate Web3 Education for Only $99!</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-the-ultimate-web3-education-for-only-99/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As NEAR’s flagship conference, NEARCON is the place to learn all of the latest on Web3 technologies and the open …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-the-ultimate-web3-education-for-only-99/">NEARCON: The Ultimate Web3 Education for Only $99!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As NEAR’s flagship conference, <a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index">NEARCON</a> is the place to learn all of the latest on Web3 technologies and the open web. <a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index">NEARCON 2023</a> will be the ultimate Web3 education — and for only $99.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s explore what you can expect from the NEARCON crash course — from recent Web3 developments in venture capital, decentralization, and AI to NEAR technologies like the Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S), and much more.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-you-ll-learn-at-nearcon-2023">What you’ll learn at NEARCON 2023</h2>



<p>The Web3 ecosystem consists of several key roles and sectors, and we’re lucky to have some of the biggest names attending NEARCON. Over 4 days, you will hear from venture capital figures like Samantha Bohbot (RockawayX) and Nathalie Oestmann (Outlier Ventures) as well as accelerator leaders like Nicolai Reinbold (CV Labs). There will also be a number of entrepreneurs and founders, including Michael Casey (CoinDesk), Alexander Skidanov (NEAR Protocol), Rebecca Allen (Contented), Dave Balter (Flipside Crypto), Aurelie Boiteux (Nansen), Mitchell Amador (Immunefi), Marc Goldich (Proximity Labs), and many others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Featured talks, panels, and discussions will include learnings on:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Open Web </strong>— Learn how open source technologies and ideals are colliding with blockchain technologies like NEAR to create an open web where everyone can be fairly rewarded for their data, ideas, and effort.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>AI &amp; Blockchain</strong> — Learn from the OG of AI himself, NEAR co-founder Illia Polosukhin, on how Blockchain and Artificial Intelligence are intersecting in 2023, and how they will develop in the near future.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Decentralization</strong> — See how the NDC (NEAR Digital Collective) is helping to decentralize governance to the NEAR community.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Regulation &amp; Policy</strong> — Get updated on the latest Web3 regulatory developments.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-your-web3-education-doesn-t-stop-at-nearcon-take-the-next-step">Your Web3 education doesn’t stop at NEARCON — take the next step</h2>



<p>If you love what you learn at NEARCON, you can keep going with your NEAR and open web education. The NEAR ecosystem offers a number of resources to help you find success in Web3.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks to the <a href="https://near.org/horizon">NEAR Horizon</a> team — who will be on hand at NEARCON — you can get help in your journey of building, getting funding, and networking as a Web3 builder, founder, and entrepreneur.&nbsp;</p>



<p>See you in Lisbon!</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index">Register</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-the-ultimate-web3-education-for-only-99/">NEARCON: The Ultimate Web3 Education for Only $99!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON 2023: Get Tickets, Get Involved, Join the Hackathon!</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-2023-get-tickets-get-involved-join-the-hackathon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20880</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEARCON 2023 “Step into the Open Web” may be a few months away but it’s fast approaching. Since kicking off …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-2023-get-tickets-get-involved-join-the-hackathon/">NEARCON 2023: Get Tickets, Get Involved, Join the Hackathon!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEARCON 2023 “Step into the Open Web” may be a few months away but it’s fast approaching. Since kicking off this year’s edition of NEARCON, the NEAR Foundation has been hard at work building an iconic experience for the NEAR ecosystem and community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This year, NEARCON has three venues, designed to optimize spaces for the hackathon and the talks and demos.  While we are still working out the details of the third venue, here are two confirmed venues:  </p>



<p><strong>NEARCON HQ<br></strong>Convento Do Beato<br>Alameda do Beato 40, 1950-042<br>Lisboa, Portugal</p>



<p><strong>Hacker HQ</strong><br>Armazem 16<br>R. Pereira Henriques nº1, 1950-242<br>Lisboa, Portugal</p>



<p>We’ve got some exciting updates on NEARCON tickets, speakers and sessions, the hackathon, and ways of getting involved in the conference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s take a look at all of the latest from NEARCON.<br><em>To stay tuned for all of the latest updates over the next few months, join the official </em><a href="https://t.me/nearcon"><em>NEARCON 2023 Telegram channel</em></a><em>, and drop into the spirit before the event.</em></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="NEARCON 2023: The Official Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qMrJheF0ZdE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-you-get-at-nearcon">What you get at NEARCON</h2>



<ul>
<li>Join 5,000+ delegates as the NEAR community explores the power and possibilities of an open web</li>



<li>Get inspired by talks from renowned authors, economists, artists, politicians, developers, entrepreneurs, and more</li>



<li>Explore the Blockchain Operating System (BOS), try it for yourself, and find out why it&#8217;s the driving force behind an open web</li>



<li>Connect with projects, speakers, community members, builders, and multi-chain enthusiasts from around the world</li>



<li>Hack the days and nights away for a chance to build on the BOS and win $180k</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-tickets-info-update">Tickets info update</h2>



<p>If you missed our early bird NEARCON 2023 tickets a few months ago, don’t worry! While your chance at free tickets has passed, you can still receive a special prize.<br>If you refer 4 friends when you <a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index?tab=register">register for NEARCON</a>, you will get a special prize at the conference. When your friends register for NEARCON, they must name you in the referral field. Friends can refer you all the way up to the first day of the conference. </p>



<p>Stay tuned to the Near.org/blog and NEAR Protocol Twitter account for updates on the prize.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-speakers-sessions">Speakers &amp; Sessions</h2>



<p>NEARCON will host a wide array of exciting speakers, including VCs, founders, developers, and many other notable ecosystem players. Here is a sneak peak at some of the 70+ confirmed speakers:&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Michael Casey — CoinDesk</li>



<li>Samantha Bohbot — RockawayX</li>



<li>Nicolai Reinbold — CV Labs</li>



<li>Nathalie Oestmann — Outlier Ventures</li>



<li>Alexander Skidanov — NEAR Protocol</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-nearcon-hackathon-build-a-multi-chain-open-web-future">NEARCON Hackathon: Build a multi-chain, open web future.</h2>



<p>Hackers know that NEAR and NEARCON love them. This year, any builder or developer who applies for the hackathon gets in for free.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The NEARCON hackathon is a 48-hour IRL hacking session for those looking to team up, familiarize themselves with NEAR, prototype their project, and pitch it —&nbsp;all for a chance to win.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The hackathon can be the start of something amazing —&nbsp;or a way to fail fast, learn, and adapt. We appreciate both, because we know that to build the next big thing you often have to fail enough times to find just the right idea.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-if-accepted-to-the-hackathon-hackers-will-receive">If accepted to the hackathon, hackers will receive:</h2>



<ul>
<li>FREE access to NEARCON</li>



<li>24/7 access to hack at the venue</li>



<li>Hands on mentoring</li>



<li>Participation stipend in NEAR</li>



<li>Chances to win amazing prizes!</li>
</ul>



<p>For consideration to hack and get a free NEARCON pass, please complete the <a href="https://nearcon-hackathon.devpost.com/">application form</a>. We’re working on the full list of bounties, partners, and opportunities, so stay tuned to the NEARCON hackathon page.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdncTzQkavACE1dmTJTZqWB1iOSpfYzGnof9pdNYjbmBhmgbQ/viewform">Request a visa letter</a> to support hackers’ visa applications.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-get-involved-with-nearcon">Get involved with NEARCON</h2>



<p>Last year, a number of partners helped support NEARCON, including TAP Air Portugal, Business Insider, Circle, The Graph, and others. There are various ways of getting involved, from digital marketing exposure and exclusive access to side events to major visibility at the conferences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Find what’s right for you. Take a look at how you can <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1P5q35REgAn7jnm61c25dLMuEynl4oI8N/view">get involved</a> at NEARCON 2023. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-step-into-the-open-web-and-register-for-nearcon">Step into the Open Web and register for NEARCON</h2>



<p>Join the NEAR ecosystem and community and step into the open web. Let’s build a new web together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;<a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index?tab=register">Register for NEARCON</a>.<br><br></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-2023-get-tickets-get-involved-join-the-hackathon/">NEARCON 2023: Get Tickets, Get Involved, Join the Hackathon!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR After NEARCON In Numbers</title>
		<link>/blog/near-after-nearcon-in-numbers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statistics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Anyone who made the trip to Lisbon for NEARCON 2022, or tuned in via the YouTube livestream or Twitter, knew …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-after-nearcon-in-numbers/">NEAR After NEARCON In Numbers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Anyone who made the trip to Lisbon for NEARCON 2022, or tuned in via the YouTube livestream or Twitter, knew NEARCON was a smashing success. The vibe was something to behold. From devs and builders to other visionaries and champions of NEAR, NEARCON showcased the ecosystem and community at its very best—with boundless energy for creating without limits.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is an energy that was also palpable to the press. Everything came together to produce&nbsp; awe-inspiring momentum that is being sustained well beyond NEARCON’s aftermath.</p>



<p>Let’s take a look at NEAR by the numbers in the wake of NEARCON to see just how the NEAR community is building without limits.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-20m-accounts-and-200m-transactions">20M Accounts and 200M Transactions&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Coming out of NEARCON, the total amount of NEAR accounts hit a new high of 20 million. To be sure, this was an ecosystem and community effort. But Sweat Economy, who presented at NEARCON, is responsible for onboarding 14 million new users into the NEAR ecosystem with their move-to-earn app. That’s 20x growth since this time last year!&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks to NEAR’s Nightshade sharding—Phase 1 of which was announced at NEARCON—this onboarding of the masses unfolded without a hitch. This example of NEAR’s infinite capacity is proof that it can welcome millions more users across the 800+ apps running on the protocol.</p>



<p>Earlier this month, NEAR also hit a new milestone of 200 million on-chain transactions. Next up? 250 million. The ecosystem is growing by leaps and bounds, and doing so in a crypto winter.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-21-global-media-partners">21 Global Media Partners</h2>



<p>NEARCON was a major hit this year with members of the international press.&nbsp; All told, the conference attracted 21 global media partners, with <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/">CoinDesk</a> leading the pack as NEAR’s top tier sponsor.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Other major media outlets joined NEAR from around the world, including Cointelegraph, the Defiant, Coinpost Japan, W3volution Spain, and Business Insider Africa.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-over-250-pieces-of-media-coverage">Over 250 Pieces of Media Coverage</h2>



<p>Naturally, with so many global media partners, there is quite a lot of great news to share. Seven NEAR announcements and five partnership stories were pushed out to the global media.&nbsp; All together these ecosystem stories attracted 256+ pieces of coverage including a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qgQF-g-S0NY">fantastic show roundup video by CryptoBanter</a>, a hugely influential crypto YouTube channel that has over half a million subscribers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While US media outlets led with most of the NEARCON coverage, NEAR’s flagship conference also saw consistent reporting from media in India, Korea, Vietnam and beyond.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-media-coverage-breakdown-by-country">Media Coverage Breakdown by Country</h3>



<ol><li>Africa &#8211; 5 pieces of coverage</li><li>Brazil &#8211; 5 pieces of coverage</li><li>China &#8211; 5 pieces of coverage</li><li>French &#8211; 8 pieces of coverage</li><li>German &#8211; 2 pieces of coverage</li><li>Italy &#8211; 4 pieces of coverage</li><li>India &#8211; 18 pieces of coverage</li><li>Japan &#8211; 2 pieces of coverage</li><li>Korea &#8211; 11 pieces of coverage</li><li>Spain &#8211; 5 pieces of coverage </li><li>UK &#8211; 12 pieces of coverage</li><li>US &#8211; 25 pieces of coverage</li><li>Vietnam &#8211; 5 pieces of coverage</li><li>Global &#8211; 150+pieces of coverage</li></ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-100m-entertainment-fund">$100M Entertainment Fund</h2>



<p>Perhaps the biggest story to come out of NEARCON was the launch of NEAR’s $100 million entertainment fund. It captivated the press, appearing in coverage from international news outlets such as <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/business/2022/09/12/layer1-blockchain-protocol-near-launches-100m-vc-fund-targetingweb3-culture-and-entertainment/">CoinDesk</a>, <a href="https://www.ibtimes.com/swiss-based-near-foundation-announces-100m-fund-focused-web3-developers-3612182">International Business Times</a>, <a href="https://journalducoin.com/defi/defi-near-100-millions-dollars-ethereum/">Journal Du Coin</a> France, China’s leading crypto title <a href="https://www.panewslab.com/zh/sqarticledetails/354nv0vl.html">Panony </a>, <a href="https://coinpost.jp/?p=386703">CoinPost Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.coinpress.co.kr/2022/09/13/38193/">Coin Press Korea</a>.</p>



<p>And rightly so. By partnering with Caerus for this new $100 VC Fund and Lab, NEAR will help push new Web3 innovation in culture, media, and entertainment. This fund now places NEAR at the forefront of changing how creative projects are financed, produced, and distributed, as well as how it’s consumed, owned, and monetized.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-11-visionary-women-of-web3-changemakers">11 Visionary ‘Women of Web3 Changemakers’</h2>



<p>Another big campaign launched at NEARCON—the <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1K2ZNKEKNNYMNWmDVOTdc2eLX8SZxEtaeCSc8I34-MUg/edit#">Women of Web3 Changemakers</a>. A partnership with <a href="https://forkast.news/why-crypto-needs-more-women/">Forkast News</a>, thisinitiative celebrated 11 exceptional women shaping the future of Web3.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The campaign attracted a great deal of interest from a global audience, with mentions in <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/video/recent-videos/nft-double-disruption-web3-women-celebrated/">CoinDesk</a>, <a href="https://ffnews.com/newsarticle/near-foundation-and-forkast-unveil-winners-of-women-in-web3-changemakers-2022/">Fintech Finance</a>, and <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/video/nft-double-disruption-web3-women-123000320.html">Yahoo Finance</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-digital-collective-ndc-and-phase-1-sharding-announcements">NEAR Digital Collective (NDC) and Phase 1 Sharding announcements</h2>



<p>NEAR Co-founder Illia Polosukhin gave an exclusive interview with <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2022/09/12/near-protocol-forms-working-group-to-promote-defi-governance/">CoinDesk</a> about the <a href="https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/currencies/near-blockchain-moves-ahead-with-phase-one-of-sharding-upgrade-1031736729">NEAR Digital Collective (NDC)</a>. This interview was syndicated in various media outlets across <a href="https://cryptotvplus.com/2022/09/nearcon-2022-near-launches-near-digital-collective-ndc/">Africa</a>, <a href="https://www.infomoney.com.br/mercados/near-protocol-forma-grupo-de-trabalho-para-promover-governanca-em-defi/">Brazil</a>, and <a href="https://www.panewslab.com/zh/sqarticledetails/o5w25c94.html">China</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>CoinDesk also covered NEAR’s <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/business/2022/09/12/near-blockchain-moves-ahead-with-phase-one-of-sharding-upgrade/">Phase 1 Sharding news</a>, which made significant waves in the developer community as well as international headlines. Meanwhile, <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1dy4_JjcTqxhJddWQjo3qsKT3vPW7f8inGJwhYLO_K80/edit">Pagoda </a>announced their Pagoda Console—a ‘one stop’ tool shop that gives devs all the kit they need to build Web3 apps.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-hubs-launch-in-india-and-vietnam">NEAR hubs launch in India and Vietnam</h2>



<p>NEARCON also witnessed the launch of two major regional hubs—<a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1_bfTVUW9LitXNRlD7OyT5MiMZRP75Mzj0LToeLkWdJ4/edit#heading=h.ze51feky5sjx">Vietnam</a> and <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/130LEgPu22sBiA1Q8RPviRhM9McVGvoSr6OUZiirD0Ig/edit#">India</a>.&nbsp; NEAR Foundation worked closely with the Vietnamese press to amplify the story locally, and with great success. Vietnam’s major tech titles covered the announcement, including <a href="https://zingnews.vn/near-ra-mat-trung-tam-khu-vuc-web3-tai-viet-nam-post1355031.html">Zing news</a>.</p>



<p>NEAR Foundation replicated this approach with India’s media outlets, garnering coverage in major titles such as <a href="https://yourstory.com/the-decrypting-story/near-protocol-foundation-web3-hub-india">YourStory</a>, the local equivalent of TechCrunch. Interviews were also secured with Reuters, Bloomberg and Times of India.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-other-stories-from-the-near-ecosystem">Other stories from the NEAR ecosystem</h2>



<p>NEAR Foundation pushed out announcements on <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/16FDNncIttWPeZVOgYu5cbpmG71R8Ban6/edit">Tether</a> (USDT) going live on NEAR, <a href="https://www.theblock.co/post/169139/pantera-capital-leads-wallet-sender">Sender Wallet’s</a> $3.5 million funding round, and Few and Far’s ambition to grow the NEAR NFT ecosystem. There were also announcements for NEAR’s partnership with<a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1nRRPrSfa8gHdfpiOjyRVeUfHYAX_-RaP/edit"> Fireblocks</a>, which will bring innovative crypto technologies to new global institutional investors, and <a href="https://www.altfi.com/article/9826_the-tokenomics-behind-sweatcoin">SWEAT Economy’s tokenomics</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As with many of the other stories and announcements from NEARCON, these stories had mass global appeal. Coverage could be found in <a href="https://www.theblock.co/post/169182/tethers-usdt-stablecoin-launches-on-near-blockchain">The Block</a>, <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/tether-usdt-stablecoin-goes-live-on-near-protocol-to-boost-defi-presence">Cointelegraph</a>,&nbsp; <a href="https://www.forbesindia.com/article/crypto-made-easy/usdt-goes-live-on-near-protocol-making-it-the-14th-blockchain-network-to-support-tether/79771/1">Forbes India</a>, and&nbsp; <a href="https://cryptotvplus.com/2022/09/how-the-sweatcoin-economy-works/">CryptoTVPlus Africa</a>.</p>



<p>The sheer amount of positive press comes at a critical time for NEAR. The entire ecosystem and the wider Web3 world are building through a crypto winter but also battling other macroeconomic forces, post-Covid trauma, and climate change. It’s a time for resilience and creativity in how the NEAR and Web3 communities rethink and refashion the internet, and more importantly, the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEARCON demonstrated to the people across the globe that the protocol, ecosystem, and community will not be deterred. Builders and investors are still flocking to NEAR to build the next generation of decentralized apps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is what creating without limits looks like. And it’s just the beginning!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-after-nearcon-in-numbers/">NEAR After NEARCON In Numbers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON 2022: Highlights, Talks and Videos</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-2022-highlights-talks-and-videos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 21:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Missed NEARCON 2022? We’ve got you covered with content from the four conference stages, as well as a dizzying host …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-2022-highlights-talks-and-videos/">NEARCON 2022: Highlights, Talks and Videos</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Missed NEARCON 2022? We’ve got you covered with content from the four conference stages, as well as a dizzying host of awesome announcements.</p>



<p>Here’s a <a href="https://youtu.be/vjXyKn9zAzk?t=21059">sizzle</a> to get you primed for all that happened at this year’s NEARCON. A <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/sh/i90u0wtce9pd8m9/AABVE7vsvCD5n2kfVlrGHgmXa?dl=0">NEARCON 2022 Dropbox folder</a> has also been set up so everyone can peruse, download, and share all of the photos from the conference. There is also a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?app=desktop&amp;list=PL9tzQn_TEuFWIUkJASran12IB5DPOvZmL">NEARCON 2022 YouTube video playlist</a> worth checking out.  </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-nearcon-day-1-year-in-review-regulatory-frameworks-brave-fireside-chat-and-more">NEARCON Day 1:&nbsp; Year in Review, Regulatory Frameworks, Brave Fireside Chat, and More</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/IbfJxn0mYvxHcukGpj5iLb0Mu5DnQUL_VkllwA5MaWvN8OEopMP95SJ6_592H4wGv0ihReY55snbGxu1t98j_cqHCsSJ3O99m6aBcHY4NcD3izOchpSuqqIPoWW1DRJZe9caBxWYloozAcxS07g53nCBrz0xzGsJUr1ztbzmWNEzK04aL-TgStU3Fg" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Day One kicked off with a slew of exciting speakers, sessions, and announcements. It was headlined by notable names from an array of industries and backgrounds, from JavaScript inventor Brandon Eiche to renowned crypto legal expert Sheila Warren.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From NEAR’s first ever transparency report to the announcement of a new Sports and Entertainment fund, here’s all the big news from Day One of NEARCON.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ecosystem-announcements">Ecosystem Announcements</h3>



<ul><li>Few and Far, a next-generation NFT marketplace built on NEAR, won a grant&nbsp; to advance NFTs across the ecosystem.</li><li>NEAR unveiled the eleven winners of the Women in Web3 Changemakers competition to spotlight the achievement of women in Web3 and to showcase female role models in the ecosystem.</li><li>Tether, the first and most widely used stablecoin (“USDT”), launched on NEAR.</li><li>Sender Wallet raised US$4.5 Million in a private round led by Pantera&nbsp; Capital.</li><li>NEAR Digital Collective (NDC) will help decentralize NEAR’s ecosystem governance and move decision-making on-chain to make community more resilient, transparent, and fair.</li><li>Phase 1 of NEAR’s Nightshade sharding was unveiled, making NEAR even more decentralized and scalable.</li><li>In a new Entertainment Fund, NEAR is backing a new $100m VC Fund and Lab focused on Web3’s evolution of culture, media, and entertainment&nbsp;</li><li>The Fireblocks integration on NEAR went live.</li></ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-day-1-videos">Day 1 Videos</h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://youtu.be/YtQnabo7EeE">Layer 1 Stage</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5SPUtzpbIIo">Nightshade Stage</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ggpw1yklsAs">Doomslug Stage</a></li></ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-year-in-review-and-transparency-report">NEAR Year in Review and Transparency Report</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/HaNiZm2rThGuXi2DQpp-lfkSFniOlHUYRo4snZNmUxZvRzNlN-1N9b1x_AHn1WpDq0BMXY3UQ9pTcaR_g4C9z9X6VNwfRd1rQdTyXMvT7PtF3VMH4VzB__gEj_9N2nwpq4lFw9E3nGq70om-hNG_nzcaOMlFY0fsERovuG4kzjP4FI0_a8W9Pc2EtQ" alt=""/></figure>



<p>NEAR Foundation CEO Marieke Flament and NEAR Co-founder Illia Polosukhin began the day by welcoming attendees on the Layer 1 Stage and delving into how NEAR is building beyond the hype through 2022 and beyond.</p>



<p>“We’re extremely excited about the diversity of attendees and over 220 speakers from so many different verticals and industries,” said Flament. “And we’ll continue to build upon our core vision of onboarding the next one billion users onto Web3 by helping the ecosystem build things that people can use.”</p>



<p>Flament returned solo to the stage for the “NEAR Year in Review,” recapping key milestones in the ecosystem over the last 12 months and unveiling NEAR’s first ever <a href="/blog/near-foundation-transparency-report/">Transparency Report</a>. Flament communicated top data from the report, including how the NEAR Grants fund had reached over $800 million in capital with over $540 million deployed within the ecosystem. Among the key sectors of grant recipients were Startup Funds, Regional Hubs, NFTs, Gaming and &amp; Entertainment and DAOs.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/YtQnabo7EeE?t=5069">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-bridging-the-gap-between-web2-and-web3">Bridging the Gap Between Web2 and Web3</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/o7APk_axbvoXxYGrdkBGvE0v1uJTV-vFtOuDBFV2sP3TKDAzkVawoRTaDRhxncU2KIKxp9Dt88ERsEWTzcS2gvcvbF6M52JQAID8CQSykI22dUot76ABMEaychY2o75bUvbhEXiQLXHA2lqNB80c9HMkKLGynr4zamgIQkVsI0zibC2IydBBoT3KXA" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Onboarding the next billion users onto Web3 requires an efficient tech stack and rich ecosystem of useful decentralized apps (dApps) and services, a topic that James Tromans from <a href="https://cloud.google.com/">Google Cloud</a> took to the Layer 1 Stage to address. While Tromans championed Web3, he also pointed out the Web2 services can play a role in easing the transition for developers.</p>



<p>“We need to make building in Web3 faster, better, and easier,” Tromans said. “For now, we can bring the best of Web2 services like Google Cloud to Web3 so that not everything has to be built from scratch.”</p>



<p>Tromans was then joined by a panel moderated by Emily Parker from <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/">Coindesk</a> entitled “Bridge Builders, Why We Need Web 2.5.” In addition to Parker and Tromans, Susie Batt from <a href="http://www.opera.com/">Opera Browser</a> and Satish Ramakrishan of <a href="http://www.bitgo.com/">BitGo</a> contributed their opinions on the concept of a “Web 2.5” that could enable a more seamless transition to Web3.</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/YtQnabo7EeE?t=2418">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-shelia-warren-discusses-web3-regulatory-frameworks">Shelia Warren discusses Web3 regulatory frameworks</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/Q--FD1m0NxFqyJw4RXzOCuBd7bhdeUWQ40whyHSXPZnipE5yTxYeXbAPW4909p_q6_tZp_syiof7Mu4XctfLXcvNKhwySZgyyFIIWv-MKObJinglaI5gI8GeZR41DYbtI6p18iDFMylxyAoWr9RYQMUlWMjH_PsYggiMmgQ3qoh0kiQKyi0nVCIjUg" alt=""/></figure>



<p>One of the biggest names headlining day one was Sheila Warren, crypto legal expert and CEO of the <a href="https://cryptoforinnovation.org/">Crypto Council for Innovation</a>. Warren took the Layer One stage during the afternoon to help attendees wade through the complex and controversial topics of regulation, governance, and legal frameworks in crypto and Web3.</p>



<p>“Who regulates crypto?” Warren posited to begin. “There is no definitive answer other than it’s complicated. It depends how projects are classified and certain power dynamics between the industry and regulators. What we need is a regulatory policy framework that addresses multiple aspects of decentralization.”</p>



<p>Warren added that regulation is not all bad and could have a beneficial effect on the space if done in an intelligent and collaborative manner.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/YtQnabo7EeE?t=10830">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-next-year-on-near-and-brave-fireside-chat">The next year on NEAR and Brave Fireside Chat</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/fVVIqFDvT-Dw4vqLB5Uq4-fzPwFQM0TUbRwqVzorK0mcGg9CWM-_zRdRrBHHW7B782aPpox6QTZwqN5a4uba2MJNjeOx3KYPaVmLuF8vEqBkiDefEzOi7cNNimNLYYiDx1bvJlYxiNe-2evm3kmV472B2cC1rhMqHet4Xff4oSAFDqVdtwId5tjfWw" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Looking ahead, NEAR Co-founder Illia Polosukhin took the Layer 1 stage to offer his sentiments on the year ahead for the NEAR Foundation, protocol, and ecosystem. Polosukhin predicted a steady increase in both ecosystem funding and projects, with over 800 projects and growing, according to <a href="https://awesomenear.com/">AwesomeNEAR</a>.</p>



<p>“I’m very excited about next year as we’ll continue to build out a wide range of developer tooling that will facilitate the next generation of NEAR apps,” said Polosukhin. “We now have all the necessary primitives – like <a href="https://paras.id/">Paras</a> for NFTs and <a href="https://astrodao.com/">AstroDAO</a> for DAOs – that the NEAR ecosystem can now become more composable with richer experiences.”</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/YtQnabo7EeE?t=14809">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Polosukhin then welcomed Brave founder Brandon Eiche to the stage for a fireside chat. Eiche is also the inventor of the JavaScript programming language, and the two discussed a wide array of topics including <a href="/blog/near-releases-javascript-sdk-bringing-web3-to-20-million-developers/">NEAR’s recently launched JavaScript SDK</a>.</p>



<p>“Everything NEAR is doing feels like one of my children,” Eiche said. “On-chain JavaScript is simply a dream, and now so many developers can build on-chain without learning another language.”</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/YtQnabo7EeE?t=16176">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-nearcon-day-2-headlined-by-messari-armored-kingdom-and-sailgp">NEARCON Day 2: Headlined by Messari, Armored Kingdom, and SailGP</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/dYPb_CoN3adCIgIw9nsfAFiZTbKlcjQfJasaJRj1S_GrrBkFqoWo5n2ZJcrKFPDbNuiQvAGNltiC7xlqwfQpp4mQkMDjt3Gbq5o6P7jMP8qUCWR3Bi0hIj5BGI-NZcd617crhHB6x7VX62m2XNZURP8jEeInc-VMEYc4H4ioqK3yNWtfInisQL-G6w" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Most anyone at Day Two of NEARCON could attest to the level of excitement and momentum for the entire NEAR ecosystem. And if there’s one thing that Day Two showcased, it’s that Web3 and NEAR are well along the path of mass adoption. From sports to social media and entertainment, real-world projects building on NEAR stepped forward in a big way on Day Two.</p>



<p>Session attendees came away with big updates and predictions for NEAR ecosystem partners like <a href="http://www.sweatco.in/">Sweatcoin</a> and <a href="http://www.sailgp.com/">SailGP</a>, not to mention a special appearance and workshop for the creators of <a href="https://armoredkingdom.com/">Armored Kingdom</a>. Everyone in the building also saw that the Hackathon was in full swing, with presentations and judging right around the corner.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ecosystem-announcements-1">Ecosystem Announcements&nbsp;</h3>



<ul><li>New NEAR Regional Hubs launched in India and Vietnam to support Web3 innovation, education, and talent.&nbsp;</li><li>Pagoda Console lets devs create without limits from an ad hoc toolkit, a one-stop tool shop that gives devs all they need to build Web3 apps.</li><li>Switchboard goes multichain with NEAR to give developers the best tools and data to build their apps.</li><li>Fayyr launched first NFT Marketplace for Social Impact Organizations on NEAR.</li><li>Chainstack, a leading blockchain managed services provider, launched support for NEAR on its platform.</li><li>Contented Media Group (CMG) received a Near Foundation grant to launch a Web3 platform where brands can interact with content creators.&nbsp;</li><li>Bitstamp listed NEAR token on its exchange.</li></ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-day-2-videos">Day 2 Videos</h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2duD7rSX0U8">Layer 1 Stage</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VrK46yUEh9s">Nightshade Stage</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7eGctqz44RU">Doomslug Stage</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Khn7zX7ZtqI">Proof of Sound Stage</a></li></ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ryan-selkis-of-messari-on-navigating-crypto-cycles">Ryan Selkis of Messari on navigating crypto cycles</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/XznJw3vNYRO0AuLnpVHsfy02iJ6zQjpQNpanlkXcIVR91OagFWu9vCNv7hDp8qrwMqoyMrCKX2raxhVLehsw5VRf1T_HwsAZQ-EnweXf-hYRQ2gkq5WSb27NHDEPcRn06jiaOHvcYaUjBF4hIee46su2yiEp7j5cYIiywvxPIrJ47MAdDz_nTCqwzg" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Things started off with one of the biggest names at NEARCON, as <a href="https://messari.io/">Messari</a> co-founder Ryan Selkis joined NEAR CEO Marieke Flament to discuss where we are in the current crypto cycle, building in a downturn, and how to navigate the future. Selkis was well-positioned to speak on the subject, having lived through multiple peaks and valleys of blockchain markets and adoption.</p>



<p>“We’re in the early innings of a long-term game,” Selkis told Flament. “Centralized institutions are weaker than ever and there’s transformational potential in a user-owned economy, empowering individuals and building more resilient systems.”</p>



<p>“This is the part of the cycle where protocols will begin to cross the chasm from MVP to mass adoption,” posited Selkis. “And now is the time to think long term about things like how the Web3 tech stack will develop and what a potential cross-chain future looks like.”</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/2duD7rSX0U8?t=377">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-sweat-economy-gets-nearcon-moving">The SWEAT Economy gets NEARCON moving</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/lM8FUtasFzctXU3UpELAYYIw5mfkHkhnO4UGdQAOzTHAH3tHyJJ7G3VtQHAk12-roshonbjYSZyXPlguzQMp1ObOX6jqIEsgoiybxcZKGYIrI647cI4gSbtOiwlM4kb1Cg51LAHULxotcthWUBcUE3zsrx6Km3vwwdHrJlQnokp6JY7cDxLZyNqq2A" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Another major highlight of Day Two took place on the Layer One stage as Oleg Fomenko, co-founder of Sweatcoin, explained how the SWEAT economy was born, why the <a href="/blog/sweatcoin-partners-with-near-foundation-to-create-a-new-movement-economy/">NEAR blockchain is playing a critical role</a>, and where the move-to-earn economy is heading.</p>



<p>“We are literally witnessing the birth of the movement economy,” Fomenko exclaimed. “We created Sweatcoin in 2016 with that name because we assumed it would be on the blockchain. Now we’re number one on the App Store in over 66 countries with over 120 million users.”</p>



<p>Fomenko also recalled that in the early days of Sweatcoin, the Ethereum network simply couldn’t handle the number of transactions with adequate speed to truly bring his vision of move-to-earn to life.</p>



<p>“But when we found NEAR, it was a perfect match in terms of both vision and mission,” said Fomenko. “A fast, low-cost blockchain along with an incredible team is helping us push the movement economy forward and help users live healthier lifestyles.”</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/2duD7rSX0U8?t=10207">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sailgp-near-have-the-wind-at-their-backs">SailGP + NEAR Have the wind at their backs</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/cU1YF7uGDf8Y7gpMuBifP7UsUaw67mKYLUypOYmjgIc7YXtkfl2e4cU6jc5lfWHobre3cP6SfRRcwbhCQs2qgYMS7NKyd_9gCV7KIGK1vkcJlBDNP1p_QRIKxwWtAboFXkRjQzJn91ktW1pZSM3cbvu-BtvDOEL38wwOlyTsFC0ujOFbRkvA-IKHuA" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Piggybacking on Day One’s announcement of the NEAR Foundation’s new Sports and Entertainment fund, NEAR CEO Marieke Flament returned to the stage to welcome SailGP’s CEO Russell Coutts and CTO Warren Jones.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“SailGP as a brand and product is built on both being exciting and data driven,” said Coutts. “Our boats generate billions of data points per day that we use to improve the fan experience. We’ve always been technology focused, which is why working with NEAR to integrate Web3 and the blockchain makes so much sense.”</p>



<p>Flament added that one of the most exciting aspects to the partnership is how <a href="/blog/near-and-sailgp-partner-on-ground-breaking-new-sports-dao/">NEAR is currently helping SailGP</a> facilitate a racing team being owned and operated by a DAO. Coutts also expressed this excitement, painting a picture of endless possibilities with how the DAO might choose to operate and increase fan engagement.</p>



<p>“The DAO might decide that certain token holders or the most engaged members can actually talk to athletes in the midst of a competition,” said Coutts. “Other things like special rewards for members or participating in team selection can also potentially be implemented. It’s all up to the DAO, which is what makes this initiative so special.”</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/2duD7rSX0U8?t=11230">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-armored-kingdom-gives-a-lesson-in-storytelling">Armored Kingdom gives a lesson in storytelling</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/tyJJkh03KKZzz7sUNLEREunUTVAcZLCMNbfFEbmR8AbGn_37oEd1UIDMS_Oeeq96LxsA9G3SubJYti_zpPxQLL50PLVTfMk7MqIBPQn6pnyeggI8bE-Zmsr3mXubM9A-ainqNuyQj3IFzTEyCLNw43hItW8FJa2OdMGCpCYrQp7nNSiyStrZzV4tbg" alt=""/></figure>



<p>One of the most anticipated gaming and metaverse projects finally touched down on Day Two of NEARCON. Armored Kingdom creators Lisa and Hugh Sterbakov were joined by writer Brian Turner to deconstruct the process of building a story arc, core elements to great storytelling, and what to expect from <a href="/blog/armored-kingdom-launches-new-scifi-fantasy-media-platform-on-near/">Armored Kingdom on NEAR</a>.</p>



<p>“Armored Kingdom is not just a comic book or metaverse game,” said Lisa. “It’s an entire multimedia platform built where fans can participate and co-create. And we’ll be rolling out an animated series to go along with it.”</p>



<p>“Armored Kingdom is our playground,” Turner said. “The world is based on an endless conflict between four major tribes on an alien planet. There are religious undertones as well as a battle for a scarce resource – Armorite – with which very powerful weapons are made from.”</p>



<p>Lisa capped off the session by mentioning that building Armored Kingdom on NEAR is allowing the team to build features and functions into the game easily due to the tech stack, and in the end, fans can put as much or as little time in as they want.</p>



<p>“Web3 is allowing us to create communities and encourage participation that Web2 never has,” she said. “We’re currently receiving fan art submissions through our Discord community that have already made their way into the comic book.”</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/2duD7rSX0U8?t=13201">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-nearcon-day-3-circle-astrodao-and-near-digital-collective">NEARCON Day 3: Circle, AstroDAO, and NEAR Digital Collective</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/tvoa1GI1lXJMLzlKuTrxKA-FZ1UlKE5UP8MjwO4wcHT4Hh8pGYklaVSanh2FB2z0nByk1s36HyIu9NoNpAJRq53XyvIiI0rAeeS5x3Oll6bXwlwsv7pCrWKP1qkGiJi2k9Fp7lU-Lhxl9KPrtJ6vm9Krlbn25Jnc2BtNS3Le8XngZLwKlOQA0nel5Q" alt=""/></figure>



<p>The biggest NEARCON to date came to a close on Day Three with a slew of insightful speakers, interactive panels, and an unexpected announcement. Big names from organizations and projects like <a href="https://www.circle.com/en/">Circle</a>, <a href="https://www.nearpay.io/">NearPay</a>, and <a href="https://a16z.com/">A16z</a> helped make the conclusion of NEARCON 2022 feel extremely meaningful&nbsp; and memorable.</p>



<p>Attendees got a glimpse at how DAOs work under the hood, where NEAR fits in with the ever-evolving fintech and payments space, and how builders should approach governance in a crypto winter. And then there was the unveiling of the NEAR Digital Collective, an ambitious leap in decentralizing and enhancing governance on the NEAR network.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ecosystem-announcements-2">Ecosystem Announcements&nbsp;</h3>



<ul><li>SWEAT and NEAR partner to enable the masses to ‘walk into crypto.’</li><li>OnMachina to provide native large-scale storage system to dApps and services building on NEAR, creating capacity to support billions of users.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-day-3-videos">Day 3 Videos</h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2duD7rSX0U8">Layer 1 Stage</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VrK46yUEh9s">Nightshade Stage</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7eGctqz44RU">Doomslug Stage</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Khn7zX7ZtqI">Proof of Sound Stage</a></li></ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-spotlight-on-crypto-payments-and-fintech">Spotlight on Crypto Payments and Fintech</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/eAxq55SX3tRyM40-47Odec0qVxgJ7RgjQ5uhYk-E52XEDmARwHtg7RHGamJbGU7FM_s733zHw1j0d97EIDKtu7hZp4GfO1lesWVjhqjK-WqGczam4H1DQ99LnFBDpwpJJgZabzZyNhgsM4d_QP49R7RiEkMzAv4j5qR16sAaN2M9veOHok4yqx8n8A" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Day Three began with a meeting of the minds between NEAR CEO Marieke Flament and Jeremy Allaire, CEO of Circle. The pair started a morning of talks and discussions around crypto innovation, payments, and broader implications for governments and fintech.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“You couldn’t have predicted the amount of innovation that’s taken place over the past decade and the millions of developers now on the blockchain,” Allaire from Circle said. “And now that we have the base layer technology in place for programmable money, along with decreasing costs of transactions, the stage is really set for exponential growth.”</p>



<p>Flament then asked Allaire about his perspective on the role that stablecoins and central bank digital currencies (CBDC) could play in the future of a blockchain and crypto-powered global financial ecosystem.</p>



<p>“What we really want to see is a composable system that resembles the software-powered internet,” Allair continued. “There’s certainly room for various stablecoins and CBDCs, as long as they continue the inertia towards self-sovereign commerce.”</p>



<p>The duo was followed by a panel entitled “Crypto Natives vs. Fintechs for the Future of Payments,” including notable names from <a href="https://www.checkout.com/">Checkout.com</a>, <a href="https://roke.to/">Roketo</a>, and NearPay. The group discussed a range of topics, from making crypto payments more seamless for individuals and onboarding small businesses to the blockchain.</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/vjXyKn9zAzk?t=668">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-deep-dive-into-daos-and-governance">Deep Dive into DAOs and Governance</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/EkJtydT--yprsvORmTb5i91AUf9LEBybVGN6TMnvdo_en1JOyv_YdjNgELd_TUc_rPcGDjDvEI0styZNrgZtoMzmqXkirii0_NUjrJd8eHVvinKkEfNKghSjpAgbkpV2vylH_8MllKdw6lJH-29-dwtR1a5U8VFUNkwGgUhBkJZeNhUYBb2vis1Gnw" alt=""/></figure>



<p>The afternoon on the Layer 1 Stage was filled with opinions and insights about Decentralized Autonomous Organizations (DAOs), how they function, and the role of DAOs in the future of Web3 and society at large. In a panel about How DAOs Get Work Done, founders and leaders from <a href="https://astrodao.com/">AstroDAO</a>, <a href="https://www.thekindao.com/">The Kin DAO</a>, and <a href="https://corndao.org/">CornerstoneDAO</a> all offered unique perspectives.</p>



<p>“We created Kin DAO for the purposes of collaboratively owning physical land to create self-sustaining food systems and micro economies,” said Adrian Bello, founder of Kin DAO and Primordia DAO. “We’re practicing this decentralized governance in person and rehabilitating our relationship with Earth.”</p>



<p>Bello went on to explain that her new project, <a href="https://www.thekindao.com/primordia">Primorida DAO</a>, has the goal of onboarding as many DAOs as possible from excluded communities onto NEAR. That’s in large part because of the NEAR ecosystem’s focus on user-friendly DAO tooling and community building through AstroDAO.</p>



<p>“AstroDAO is our home for everything,” Bello continued. “Other chains can be somewhat hard to get into. But AstroDAO is accessible and has a low barrier to entry. We can reference decisions made on-chain and governance is therefore always transparent.”</p>



<p>Jordan Gray, the founder of <a href="/blog/a-deep-dive-into-daos-exploring-astro-dao/">AstroDAO</a>, also explained how his project is focused on letting everyday users harness the power of DAOs. Smart contracts, APIs, and governance protocols all exist “under the hood” of AstroDAO, making it easier for both users and developers to create, engage with, and operate DAOs.</p>



<p>“DAOs are going to rock the business world in a way that we haven’t seen since the spreadsheet,” Gray predicts. “We’re on the cusp of a work revolution. And if we figure out new ways to incentivize voting, we might even fix democracy.”</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/vjXyKn9zAzk?t=12032=">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-introducing-the-near-digital-collective-for-governance">Introducing the NEAR Digital Collective for Governance</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/8YclXysuX-c3Tc1uxqTSpFzMDap4opxjS4TSipthqFO589Y6vLLJSPsF1uidI8EpX0rYy3F0xRTx7mEkqeWAKdSj4PRomrRaF9xxBF48KrUureJqMl1XdFGw-eVfiDNHVpzAyc5-vo9RvmC-kvbXolRm2TdkYt8cXjmzLoGrzgFifII0N6AEFD33MQ" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Day Three of NEARCON concluded with one of the most exciting announcements of the entire conference. NEAR co-founder Illia Polosukhin and Harry Tafolla of <a href="https://twitter.com/CheddarFi?s=20&amp;t=gz8AMkSEzLMs2polLasmiw">Cheddar</a> announced the creation of the <a href="https://cryptotvplus.com/2022/09/nearcon-2022-near-launches-near-digital-collective-ndc/">NEAR Digital Collective (NDC)</a>, an ambitious initiative to further decentralize NEAR governance and create a more robust, resilient network.</p>



<p>“With the NEAR Digital Collective, we’re striving for a truly autonomous ecosystem,” Polosukhin said. “We need to do this on the people&#8217;s level, where we’re all accountable and responsible and systems are not chaotic or toxic.”</p>



<p>Polosukhin went on to explain that the NDC governance framework is akin to drafting the constitution of a newly formed nation, with core community members like Tafolla leading the charge to formulate, define, and implement NEAR governance from here on out.</p>



<p>Polosukhin said&nbsp; that the NDC is a major step in addressing the needs of all stakeholders within the NEAR ecosystem, from users and DAOs to node validators and wallet developers. The NDC will also be dynamic and allow for constant updates and upgrades in governance frameworks and processes.</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/vjXyKn9zAzk?t=19635">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-hackathon-winner-and-wrapping-up-nearcon">Hackathon winner and wrapping up NEARCON</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/lBjqzpXPU-Vufj7yJ5b3yHW3WdS0OD8u4_I8QpL1mrfy6FbxNdMtZII1pNRmceCIVkh_lhvEY027B0FADJ6ybA69LWuxR-W1EgZvH0kyqH7iw5llQ7C7iAulqSZnEfzhIJz3vpEkqRJi3EvJWnQXacheFqxfCEM3hsm9RNoo_07idC_0qvO_Qcrx3g" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Flament then took the stage along with Polosukhin to wrap up NEARCON 2022, highlighting that almost 3,000 attendees from 176 countries contributed to making this year’s gathering such a rousing success. In addition, 38% of all attendees were women, and NEAR handed out the first-ever <a href="https://cryptotvplus.com/2022/09/nearcon-celebrates-women-in-web3/">Women in Web3 Changemakers awards</a> for female role models in the space.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Polosukhin also thanked the 500+ hackers who participated in the <a href="https://nearcon-irl-hackathon.devpost.com/">NEARCON 2022 Hackathon</a>. Out of the 98 submissions, the winner chosen was <a href="https://devpost.com/software/pomegrant">Pomegrant</a>, a browser plugin that allows users to eliminate ads and donate directly to content creators using crypto.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“If there’s something that we hope you’re taking away from these past three days, it’s <em>without limits</em>,” Flament concluded. “We hope with NEAR you see that you can truly create without limits and realize whatever dreams and visions that you have for both your project and society. So let’s continue to create without limits, build beyond the hype, and get to one billion users!”</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/vjXyKn9zAzk?t=21122">Watch the full talk</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks again to all who attended, contributed to, and engaged with NEARCON 2022. A big round of applause for the entire NEAR ecosystem and we’ll see you again at NEARCON 2023!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-2022-highlights-talks-and-videos/">NEARCON 2022: Highlights, Talks and Videos</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
