<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Web3 Onboarding Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/web3-onboarding/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/web3-onboarding/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 15:43:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Web3 Onboarding Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/web3-onboarding/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Rownd and NEAR Foundation are Cracking the Code of Web3 Onboarding</title>
		<link>/blog/rownd-and-near-foundation-are-cracking-the-code-of-web3-onboarding/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rownd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3 Onboarding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the main reasons that the NEAR ecosystem exists is to onboard the next billion users to Web3 — …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/rownd-and-near-foundation-are-cracking-the-code-of-web3-onboarding/">Rownd and NEAR Foundation are Cracking the Code of Web3 Onboarding</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>One of the main reasons that the NEAR ecosystem exists is to onboard the next billion users to Web3 — and that mission has just made significant strides by partnering with <a href="https://rownd.io/">Rownd</a>. An industry leader in digital onboarding and identity, Rownd’s passwordless authentication tech will utilize NEAR for more seamless interaction and onboarding for both Web3 and Web2.</p>



<p>Brands and businesses use Rownd to take users from landing pages to downloading apps while ensuring a streamlined registration process across platforms, websites, and mobile apps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, companies that use Rownd can integrate NEAR apps into their mobile and desktop experiences, while still maintaining privacy and security via passwordless authentication.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-addressing-the-persistent-digital-onboarding-problem">Addressing the persistent digital onboarding problem</h2>



<p>Engaging and retaining users is still a major challenge. A clear symptom of this problem is that only 2% of site visitors complete sign-up processes of all sorts. A whopping 60% leave during the sign-up stage itself. This high attrition rate can have a severe impact on customer acquisition and revenue generation efforts.</p>



<p>Rownd directly confronts this problem, bringing to the table its innovative onboarding and authentication solutions. These are far from one-size-fits-all solutions. Rownd dynamically allows platforms to tailor the authentication and profile creation process to meet the specific needs and preferences of their users.</p>



<p>This customization reduces friction and drop-off rates, improving user experience and making the process more appealing. When onboarding is user-centric and straightforward, it leads to higher conversion rates, ultimately benefiting both the user and the platform. Rownd doesn’t just address not a functional need but also builds trust and credibility amongst users.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-rownd-s-digital-onboarding-solution-on-near">Rownd&#8217;s digital onboarding solution on NEAR</h2>



<p>Rownd&#8217;s solution is both elegant and robust. It employs compact code snippets and software development kits (SDKs) to create a network of interconnected digital platforms — from websites and blogs to landing pages and apps. This strategic platform unification consolidates user data into a single, comprehensive profile, which translates into a smooth cross-platform experience.</p>



<p>Rownd goes a step further with adaptive sign-up. Rownd’s SDKs do not require hard coding design and authentication methods for apps and websites.&nbsp; Rather, they are set in the platform. This allows developers and non-developers alike to dynamically change sign-in methods, branding, and where authentication occurs without editing code.</p>



<p>Rownd also has a Web3 integration strategy, making it easier for users to navigate the often complex and intimidating world of crypto and Web3. They offer user-friendly custodial wallets for those new to the crypto space, while simultaneously allowing crypto-savvy users to link their existing wallets with minimal hassle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This balanced approach ensures that Rownd&#8217;s onboarding solution is inclusive, comprehensive, and future-ready.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-foundation-and-rownd-the-future-of-web3-onboarding">NEAR Foundation and Rownd: the future of Web3 onboarding</h2>



<p>NEAR Foundation’s partnership with Rownd greatly expands the potential of the company</p>



<p>‘s advanced authentication and onboarding solutions. Rownd’s NEAR integration allows app developers to add a NEAR account/wallet to a new user in seconds.&nbsp; This collaboration paves the way for faster adoption of Web3 technology in a secure, scalable, and decentralized environment. Brands and businesses will benefit from increased conversions and engagement of Web3 veterans and novices alike.</p>



<p>Together, Rownd and the NEAR Foundation demonstrate the transformative potential of integrating state-of-the-art onboarding and passwordless authentication with the revolutionary Web3. By crafting a user-centric onboarding experience, they are making significant strides toward broadening the use of Web3 applications, marking a new era for digital experiences.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/rownd-and-near-foundation-are-cracking-the-code-of-web3-onboarding/">Rownd and NEAR Foundation are Cracking the Code of Web3 Onboarding</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
