<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Web3 Accelerator Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/web3-accelerator/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/web3-accelerator/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 15:11:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.orghttps://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Web3 Accelerator Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/web3-accelerator/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Case Study: NEAR Foundation&#8217;s Laura Cunningham on the NEAR Horizon Startup Accelerator</title>
		<link>/blog/case-study-near-foundations-laura-cunningham-on-the-near-horizon-startup-accelerator/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Horizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3 Accelerator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20758</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-near-foundations-laura-cunningham-on-the-near-horizon-startup-accelerator/">Case Study: NEAR Foundation&#8217;s Laura Cunningham on the NEAR Horizon Startup Accelerator</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR to effortlessly create and distribute innovative decentralized apps, while helping build a more open web — free from centralized platforms. In these Case Study videos, NEAR Foundation showcases some of these projects.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>In the latest NEAR Foundation Case Study video, viewers hear from Laura Cunningham, Team Lead at NEAR Horizon and General Manager at NEAR Foundation. NEAR Horizon is a Web3 accelerator program revolutionizing how founders and builders receive support in the open web. Laura takes viewers on a deep dive into Horizon’s startup accelerator marketplace, which the Horizon team built on the Blockchain Operating System (BOS). </p>



<p>“The BOS was our platform of choice for building NEAR Horizon because it makes Horizon much more accessible to founders and projects that are already in the ecosystem. And then ones coming in new, you can be building on another chain as long as you have some component of your stack on NEAR then you can apply and be part of NEAR Horizon,  ” she adds. “It is also incredibly composable, so we were able to fork different attributes that were already available on BOS and make use of them in our front end, so it made it a lot quicker to actually develop.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Case Study: NEAR Foundation&#039;s Laura Cunningham on the NEAR Horizon Startup Accelerator" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8R9rtRuk5Vw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-near-foundations-laura-cunningham-on-the-near-horizon-startup-accelerator/">Case Study: NEAR Foundation&#8217;s Laura Cunningham on the NEAR Horizon Startup Accelerator</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Horizon and Encode Club: Accelerating Blockchain Mastery for Builders</title>
		<link>/blog/near-horizon-and-encode-club-accelerating-blockchain-mastery-for-builders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Encode Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Horizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3 Accelerator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Horizon and Encode Club have joined forces with a singular mission: to simplify the entry into the Web3 sphere. …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-horizon-and-encode-club-accelerating-blockchain-mastery-for-builders/">NEAR Horizon and Encode Club: Accelerating Blockchain Mastery for Builders</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Horizon and Encode Club have joined forces with a singular mission: to simplify the entry into the Web3 sphere. This partnership forms a structured pathway, offering builders and founders a seamless transition into the blockchain world. Anchoring their efforts on practical solutions, NEAR Horizon and Encode Club aim to foster an inclusive and accessible future in the ever-evolving decentralized landscape.</p>



<p>Uniting Encode&#8217;s developer training expertise with NEAR&#8217;s advanced tech, the partnership goes beyond facilitation. It directly trains builders, fueling growth and actively shaping an open Web3.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-encode-x-near-horizon-four-steps-to-blockchain-expertise">Encode x NEAR Horizon: Four steps to blockchain expertise</h2>



<p>This inclusive program is meticulously designed to accommodate everyone from those new to blockchain to well-versed industry professionals, promoting skill development and exploration in Web3.</p>



<p>Here’s what to expect:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Encode x NEAR Horizon Educational Series:</strong> The journey commences with a four-week program of building awareness of Web3 and NEAR Technology. These sessions aim to demystify blockchain technology, making it approachable for newcomers while offering valuable insights for seasoned professionals. From introductory presentations to in-depth technical demos, the educational series lays a solid foundation for all participants.</li>
</ol>



<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Encode x NEAR Horizon Bootcamp: </strong>An intense eight-week program offers a deep dive into the world of blockchain development. Participants engage in live classes, practical assignments, and collaborative group projects — all under the expert guidance of seasoned instructors. The bootcamp offers a hands-on learning experience, accelerating the participants&#8217; transition from theory to practice.</li>
</ol>



<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Encode x NEAR Horizon Hackathon:</strong> A four-week hackathon that supports builders in launching high-quality projects. This event is designed to challenge participants and allow them to apply their newfound skills. With technical workshops, mentorship, and continual support, the hackathon provides an excellent platform for budding developers to build, learn, and innovate.</li>
</ol>



<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Encode x NEAR Horizon Accelerator Program: </strong>This eight-week program focuses on nurturing the most promising hackathon projects and ecosystem builders. By offering mentorship and weekly workshops, the accelerator program aims to transform innovative ideas into operational startups, contributing to the growth and diversity of the NEAR ecosystem.</li>
</ol>



<p>In essence, this partnership between NEAR Foundation and Encode Club is more than just an event — it&#8217;s a comprehensive roadmap to blockchain mastery, designed to educate, engage, challenge, and inspire all who embark on the journey.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-cultivating-talent-encode-x-near-horizon-growth-strategy">Cultivating talent: Encode x NEAR Horizon growth strategy</h2>



<p>The program offers a well-structured process for developers to learn, practice and build startups while receiving mentorship support from Encode and NEAR Horizon. The program’s impact extends beyond individual growth, as it also fosters a thriving environment for the NEAR ecosystem and Web3 developers.</p>



<p>Don&#8217;t miss the chance to be part of this enriching experience — an opportunity that promises to strengthen the NEAR ecosystem while nurturing the next generation of Web3 developers. Embark on a rewarding blockchain journey with the NEAR Horizon and Encode Club partnership. Whether it&#8217;s the educational series, hackathon, bootcamp, or accelerator program, NEAR Horizon and Encode provide the resources and opportunities you need to succeed in the world of blockchain. Your blockchain adventure starts here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To start,&nbsp; create a <a href="http://near.org/horizon">NEAR Horizon project profile</a> and register to the Encode x NEAR Horizon program <a href="https://www.encode.club/near2023">here</a>. Stay updated on Encode Club&#8217;s programs via their <a href="https://www.encode.club/">website</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/encodeclub">Twitter</a>, and <a href="https://discord.gg/encodeclub">Discord</a>, and join a community that shares your passion for Web3 innovation and growth. NEAR Horizon was recently launched, read the press release <a href="/blog/near-foundation-launches-near-horizon/">here</a>, and register in the NEAR Horizon platform <a href="http://near.org/horizon">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-horizon-and-encode-club-accelerating-blockchain-mastery-for-builders/">NEAR Horizon and Encode Club: Accelerating Blockchain Mastery for Builders</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Update on Near Decentralized Funding, DAOs, and Accelerator</title>
		<link>/blog/update-on-near-decentralized-funding-daos-and-accelerator/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DAOs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3 Accelerator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=19785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hello Nearians, We are more than halfway through the first quarter of 2023 and wanted to share a quick update …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/update-on-near-decentralized-funding-daos-and-accelerator/">Update on Near Decentralized Funding, DAOs, and Accelerator</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hello Nearians,</p>



<p>We are more than halfway through the first quarter of 2023 and wanted to share a quick update on the progress NEAR Foundation has made on community funding and accelerator strategies.</p>



<p>First, if you are a project building on NEAR or interested in building on NEAR and need some immediate support, please fill out this <a href="https://airtable.com/shrQk2yWacIj2QA3E">Project Support Form</a>. NEAR Foundation will connect you with the appropriate person or organization who can assist.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-decentralizing-funding">Decentralizing Funding</h2>



<p>Important <a href="/blog/refining-near-foundations-grant-approach/">changes in the grant program</a> were announced at the start of January, highlighting the Foundation’s goal for a more decentralized funding process by handing over decision making to community DAOs. What follows is the status of the initial DAOs.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>MarketingDAO</strong> is actively reviewing proposals related to amplification and marketing via the <a href="https://gov.nearpages.wpengine.com/c/marketing/marketingdao">MarketingDAO forum channel</a>. At the moment, the core focus of applications is around content and social media, with an exciting <a href="https://gov.nearpages.wpengine.com/t/introducing-the-near-day-community-content-bounty-program-for-eth-denver-2023/32935/9">ETHDenver bounties</a> initiative having just recently been announced.
<ul>
<li><a href="https://gov.nearpages.wpengine.com/t/the-marketing-dao-vertical/3554">What is the Marketing DAO</a></li>



<li><a href="https://gov.nearpages.wpengine.com/t/guide-how-to-submit-a-funding-proposal-to-the-marketing-dao/4603">How to submit a proposal</a></li>



<li><a href="https://gov.nearpages.wpengine.com/t/guidelines-for-assessment-marketing-dao-proposals/31645">Marketing DAO Guidelines </a>&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>DevGov</strong> is ramping up and reviewing proposals supporting technical ecosystem projects via their <a href="https://near.social/#/mob.near/widget/MyPage?accountId=devgovgigs.near">NEAR.social gig board</a>.
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.neardevgov.org/">What is the Developer Governance DAO</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.neardevgov.org/blog/near-developer-governance-funding-guidelines">How to submit a proposal</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>Creatives DAO</strong> is on track for accepting proposals for funding before the end of March.
<ul>
<li><a href="https://creativesdao.org/">What is the Creatives DAO</a></li>



<li><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1CVfx6go2EjEh3ygvvEDlKUAtj2sZ_i9KH-DWfxDpPnE/edit">How to submit a proposal</a></li>



<li><a href="https://gov.nearpages.wpengine.com/t/guide-creativesdao-guidelines-and-procedures/32878">Creatives DAO Guidelines</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>NEAR Digital Collective (NDC)</strong> is a grassroots movement by the NEAR Community to decentralize. NDC V0 Governance is coming soon! The initial milestone is for the Community Treasury to come online, and it is actively being finalized. V0 focuses on funding the GrassrootsDAOs listed above: Marketing, Developer, and Creatives.
<ul>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/near-digital-collective/a-beginners-guide-to-v0-of-the-ndc-governance-structure-39f977d91b3e">A beginner’s guide to V0 of the NDC governance structure</a></li>



<li><a href="https://medium.com/near-digital-collective/what-is-the-near-digital-collective-36151cab2b73">What is the NDC?&nbsp;</a></li>



<li>How to Get Involved:
<ul>
<li>Join the NDC movement on <a href="https://t.me/+SkmIlkkXB9UzYjM0">Telegram</a>:
<ul>
<li>Join the Movement</li>



<li>Start a conversation</li>



<li>Join or form a Workgroup to contribute to governance and decentralization on NEAR&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-accelerator">The Accelerator</h2>



<p>From the accelerator side, NEAR Foundation’s past experience with the grants program showed us that founders and teams are in need of a variety of support in order to be successful and take their project to the next level.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To that end, the Foundation’s strategy consists of <strong>three elements</strong>:&nbsp;</p>



<ol>
<li>We are building a product on NEAR Discovery that will allow founders to connect with a range of contributors (e.g., investors, subject matter experts in areas like legal and finance) who can support them in their journey. We are launching an MVP in early March.
<ol>
<li>If you are a founder, investor, mentor, or subject matter expert interested in being a beta tester, please fill out this <a href="https://airtable.com/shrALYWH9TBQr8jxh">form</a>.&nbsp;</li>



<li>If you are a founder interested in participating in paid user research, please fill out this <a href="https://survey.alchemer.eu/s3/90526683/Research-Plan-NEAR-Foundation-Project-Journey">form</a>.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>



<ol start="2">
<li>We recently made <a href="/blog/open-call-for-near-accelerator-partners/">an open call to partner with accelerator programs</a> that can help us fast track support needs for projects. We will be releasing additional open calls in the coming weeks as we continue building out the support network available for founders. These open calls will be for:
<ol>
<li>Engineering support resources</li>



<li>Talent / Recruitment platforms and services</li>



<li>Legal platforms and services</li>



<li>Back office accounting platforms and services</li>



<li>Marketing services</li>



<li>Product management services</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>



<ol start="3">
<li>We are continuously developing and identifying learning content and tooling that are most helpful for early stage founders (e.g., accounting software geared towards Web3 teams, Go To Market exemplars, etc.). These resources will be available within the product.</li>
</ol>



<p><em>Take 1 minute to help us pick a name for the Accelerator </em><a href="https://airtable.com/shrN84QjGEOTqTCKL"><em>here</em></a><em> (survey closes on March 1, 2023)!</em></p>



<p>If you have any questions on decentralized funding, the DAOs, and Accelerator program, please reach out to the Community Team on <a href="https://t.me/cryptonear">Telegram</a>, <a href="https://discord.com/invite/UY9Xf2k">Discord</a>, and other social media channels used by the NEAR community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, if your project is building on NEAR or interested in doing so and you are in need of some immediate support, fill out this <a href="https://airtable.com/shrQk2yWacIj2QA3E">Project Support Form</a>. NEAR Foundation will connect you with the appropriate person or organization who can assist.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/update-on-near-decentralized-funding-daos-and-accelerator/">Update on Near Decentralized Funding, DAOs, and Accelerator</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
