<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NEARCON ‘23 Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/nearcon-23/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/nearcon-23/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:51:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>NEARCON ‘23 Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/nearcon-23/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>NEARCON &#8217;23 Unwrapped: Lisbon Steps into the Open Web in Iconic Fashion</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-23-unwrapped-lisbon-steps-into-the-open-web-in-iconic-fashion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI is NEAR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EigenLayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR DA Layer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON ‘23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21092</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the course of three epic days, the NEAR ecosystem showed up and showed out to make NEARCON ‘23 the …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-unwrapped-lisbon-steps-into-the-open-web-in-iconic-fashion/">NEARCON &#8217;23 Unwrapped: Lisbon Steps into the Open Web in Iconic Fashion</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Over the course of three epic days, the NEAR ecosystem showed up and showed out to make NEARCON ‘23 the most iconic edition yet. Groundbreaking partnerships were announced, new bonds forged, and a new vision for AI and the open web was unveiled by some of the brightest minds in the blockchain business.</p>



<p>“The open web is an internet where all people control their own assets, data, and power of governance,” remarked NEAR co-founder and newly minted CEO of NEAR Foundation, Illia Polosukhin, on Day One of NEARCON ‘23. “And that vision extends beyond NEAR to the entire space, with the B.O.S. acting as the single entry point to an open web.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Illia’s remarks truly encapsulated the spirit of NEARCON ‘23, as innovative collaborations with the likes of Polygon and <a href="https://near.org/blog/near-foundation-and-eigen-labs-partner-to-enable-faster-cheaper-web3-transactions-for-ethereum-rollups-via-eigenlayer/">EigenLayer</a> highlighted a cross-chain, multi-ecosystem future with NEAR enabling multiple key facets of tomorrow’s truly open web.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So ICYMI, here’s all the key happenings, hubbub, and highpoints of an iconic NEARCON ‘23.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-partnerships-irl-hackathon-and-ncon-make-a-splash">Partnerships, IRL Hackathon, and NCON make a splash</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/jog58Foi9eK8yb0kt8LNLgFBKjQo_cXMxmxeUn3ZDPFEgvNaQ3RjVnw-i9AOrKpa3Q3sv70HDA9Lzn2vAUWN6A-tq6S3obNwg_Z9f2B1VciUCWNlOXK3rCbWJWWvJ34ZYED5WJoRY0-jqiwdYVoFvw4TqHGsmsGHgU_7zO3Z0mLfjeS8dQmWII645drzXw" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Things started off with a bang before the doors of the Convento Do Beato in Lisbon even opened, with the debut of the NCON token. The first ever native NEARCON token, attendees could download the NEARCON app and collect NCON tokens by completing tasks, bounties, and viewing sessions throughout the event.</p>



<p>NEARCON-goers could then redeem NCON tokens for swag or a bite from the various food trucks, or even send NCON to other attendees via a slick native wallet on the NEARCON app. All told, <a href="https://twitter.com/openwebdata/status/1723463055542300696">over 110,000 NCON tokens</a> were distributed during the event, making it a smash hit amongst attendees.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/WvxgD6nadaErgWpYzZLpHKMJmLXrxWA9r4riyOV_wywtPrBLCKEjhiCASWjAGFVk2C0twfjs8macMcr029Hawm0N7ftUrsbkZdJVC6QGF5L-IIottIQlp3Bcgtmrbkk5LBknm0cqxwUVfkhSA-sG8D5ptvFsZWqC-tC8Ava6daCzCYDQdhS1X3JdniIBCA" alt=""/></figure>



<p>This year’s NEARCON also took place across three cool and contrasting venues: NEARCON HQ, Hacker HQ, and Community HQ, each providing a unique experience for those of varying interests. HackerHQ was popping in particular due to the three day IRL Hackathon. Held in a stunning seaview venue, the winners will be announced next week, so stay tuned.</p>



<p>Once everyone settled in for Day One, the ecosystem was treated to a few major game-changing partnership announcements. Here’s a roundup of the major collabs that are already making an impact for NEAR builders, developers, and the community at large:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-releases-the-data-availability-layer-for-eth-rollups-and-ethereum-developers">NEAR releases the Data Availability Layer for ETH Rollups and Ethereum developers</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Introducing the NEAR Data Availability Layer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U1IfP435Aow?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>By far the biggest news of Day One was NEAR <a href="/blog/near-foundation-launches-near-da-to-offer-secure-cost-effective-data-availability-for-eth-rollups-and-ethereum-developers/?_gl=1%2Ak9zc45%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTA3NDE2NTgxOS4xNzAwMDM4OTU2%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTcwMDAzODk1Mi4xLjAuMTcwMDAzODk1Mi4wLjAuMA..">unveiling the NEAR Data Availability Layer (NEAR DA)</a>, offering robust, low-cost blockchain data to developers for modular open web development. NEAR DA will help developers reduce costs and enhance the reliability of rollups, while keeping the security of Ethereum. NEAR DA is a key part of tomorrow&#8217;s open web development stack, with early users including StarkNet, Caldera, Movement Labs, and others.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-x-eigenlayer-streamline-ethereum">NEAR x EigenLayer streamline Ethereum</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/4Ir5U6Ej7UgAKATGtl2k3GEBZxcx9Ijetal173PU1eM2MQpV9C_wCj5DBt6rhWx_rSg4JqZiTXTnQq2RiEECZ8USbNkOtFoHifoVPn4xB6_-71Mb5mALQD6BXhP30NLTWR6hEBziROAg3v8hNnAU_1-Hpfk5TSJZz2kqhxDgMJLq2uYTOVDzML8G5MIKzQ" alt=""/></figure>



<p>NEAR Foundation announced its <a href="/blog/near-foundation-and-eigen-labs-partner-to-enable-faster-cheaper-web3-transactions-for-ethereum-rollups-via-eigenlayer/?_gl=1%2Abb1vlz%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTA3NDE2NTgxOS4xNzAwMDM4OTU2%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTcwMDAzODk1Mi4xLjAuMTcwMDAzODk1Mi4wLjAuMA..">partnership with EigenLayer</a>, which will speed&nbsp; up transaction times and slashing costs on the Ethereum blockchain. The collaboration will introduce a fast finality layer to Ethereum rollups, boosting their efficiency and scalability. The fast finality layer showcases the strengths of NEAR’s technology while making the open web more usable.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-layerzero-brings-interoperability-to-near">LayerZero brings interoperability to NEAR</h3>



<p>In other big news, <a href="https://x.com/NEARProtocol/status/1722936951358034312?s=20">LayerZero integrated with NEAR</a>, bringing over 40 blockchain networks into the open web. Layer brings trustless cross-chain messaging into the fold, making NEAR a more versatile ecosystem. The announcement highlighted NEAR&#8217;s commitment to seamless communication across various blockchain networks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-day-one-highlights-bringing-the-open-web-vision-to-life">Day One highlights: bringing the open web vision to life</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/5fAa-iF11u_bBT0EJBugPswSRTK_DHm7ECm7cLCVfEtmDtoBIKN52uxtmdhoe_GQWmkP_-C--T3SEtp73OayIz1dZSIvSDAxHDNc7A0K7dDW4PgJvug3KvDxbqfJYvTig2bTg8vOTiEQPClSJnYvUzBugacwlUJR3dqVTxWSNeymjYjJORlvPHGfL7s1ZA" alt=""/></figure>



<p>While there were a ton of amazing sessions and panels on the first day — from open web gaming and sports to crypto economics — one of the major themes was how Illia would realize his vision for a truly open internet in his new role as CEO of the NEAR Foundation. With a renewed focus on developers in the ecosystem, it only makes sense for him to steer the ship.</p>



<p>Piggybacking on Illia’s “NEAR: The Open Web Vision” keynote, new NEAR COO Chris Donovan made a case for the open web, while also sitting down to discuss Web3 regulatory issues with Coindesk’s Michael Casey. And in other developer tooling news, NEAR Data Availability (DA) was announced, giving developers low-cost access to modular, scalable blockchain data.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-day-two-highlights-the-ai-is-near-track-takes-flight">Day Two highlights: the AI is NEAR track takes flight</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/Fliv3gNu9eojFeS2QCYlbxHaSRLWEofADptXojnQOVMHb-JBTXZ1Euxfz-QByKYir75UtWSqIzzfAmYBVCz8SJzl1r4_iZIjsbIyKdlMAayDnzJeRmDv9_8vSDsp7oEdKXy81iSLX9w60C_9o6dPWOz7barT9gxfu1I1w5_tGkAJz-kHi132RK710vzz-w" alt=""/></figure>



<p>The second day of NEARCON ‘23 was perhaps the boldest to date, with an epic “AI is NEAR” speaker and programming track that was simply mind blowing. Things kicked off with sessions featuring thought leaders from the likes of Pantera Capital and NEAR Tasks, and heated up even more with NEAR co-founder Alex Skidanov’s talk on generative AI and the open web.</p>



<p>Illia returned in the afternoon to discuss “AI on NEAR: The Future of Work and Governance,” painting a picture of how AI will impact the future of governance, work, asset ownership, and beyond. He was then joined by Mike Butcher of TechCrunch, with the two unpacking the intersection of AI, blockchain, and global policy.</p>



<p>“AI has the potential to be a huge driver for productivity,” Illia explained. “AI agents, for example,&nbsp; are redefining the future of work. They have the unique ability to manage transactions and resources on blockchain platforms, communicate with secure cryptographic verification, and act as autonomous entities on people’s behalf — and directly for their benefit.”</p>



<p>The AI is NEAR track was capped off when Illia then joined Michael Casey for a Coindesk podcast, where the two dove as deep as one can imagine down the AI rabbit hole. In particular, Illia shared his experience, views, and predictions regarding AI, blockchain, and the open web – simply a must listen. (Stay tuned for the release of this Coindesk podcast with Illia and Michael.)</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-day-three-highlights-governance-and-hackathon-on-stage">Day Three highlights: governance and hackathon on stage</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/YMVF0QoG2ZetU2RDLt_nolNdY7zpPh8xeNNvkvPtQ6I1Nzu_H2G_d0Chx1KTM0lcq2jMJZ3QFkLJDtQccpLP63nyyQBSKBhZ-WX-eED61NbYupTHjHQLk-CxriCdqBFG-cznfPVFtr48Avga7qSbfUgup1_CnSW5EWGSwldn59un6pvdD3rsLgwZv1SnsQ" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Governance and current happenings with the NEAR Digital Collective (NDC) were front and center in a spirited Day Three. One of the most unique panels was the NEAR Governance Forum, featuring AVB from the Transparency Committee, Cameron Dennis from Banyan, and Blaze of Cheddar.</p>



<p>All three gave their takes on what’s gone right — and wrong — with the NDC since its inception at last year’s NEARCON. And in a “Round Robin” format, the three fielded a variety of questions from the audience, some of whom were NDC members themselves. Blaze and AVB then joined NEAR’s Yadira Blocker in an afternoon session discussing Decentralized Democracy in 2024.</p>



<p>The final season of NEARCON ‘23 featured presentations from the IRL Hackathon, where builders unveiled their work and ideas. Judges and panelists included Oleg Fomenko, CEO of Sweat Economy, with talented NEAR builders putting their best foot forward. They showcased some truly amazing ideas and tech, so you’ll want to keep your eyes peeled for the winners.</p>



<p>And what’s Day Three of any NEARCON without a party? This year’s bash was held at the LX Factory, an enormous space where all attendees got their final chance to network, share ideas, and have a blast. The Littles sponsored the party, bringing an added element of excitement by setting up carnival games at the venue along with The Fun Pass to reward anyone who played.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-nearcon-23-as-iconic-as-it-gets">NEARCON ‘23: as iconic as it gets</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/yYY2_yr7Zg7pzkHX3fpfsykRtcnXSlKZR-RcTXw4pTzfPnkfR2PH3_xaIqGFPjDkpcm3bN5fG4LVBV9qP20QVuu63SlCyQnZynqNuCq8uNwY7CNGhb4d8bld1DPMvw6XibIBsHe0dYz9MuQSj7_m5ZEmgAPe_Wu5hWpGxg5M2j0ohXt96G9c-j2smCf55w" alt=""/></figure>



<p>If you joined us in Lisbon, a huge thanks for making this year’s edition so fun, spectacular, and rewarding. If you weren’t able to attend, we sincerely hope to see you next year. From transformative partnerships to leading the Web3 pack in AI, NEARCON ‘23 showcased the passion, momentum, and ingenuity of the entire NEAR ecosystem.<br><br>If you weren’t able to make it to Lisbon for NEARCON, don’t worry —&nbsp;you can still check out all of the talks. Visit <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@NEARProtocol/videos">NEAR Protocol’s YouTube page</a> for the full livestreams from the Layer 1 and Layer 2 stages, or click the links below.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>NEARCON Day One Livestream</strong>&nbsp; – <a href="https://youtu.be/Cj2PpoZW47g?feature=shared">Layer 1 Stage</a>, <a href="https://youtu.be/6vMidjsnXjM?feature=shared">Layer 2 Stage</a></li>



<li><strong>NEARCON Day Two Livestream</strong> – <a href="https://youtu.be/gYhNjSQ1uVs?feature=shared">Layer 1 Stage</a>, <a href="https://youtu.be/uIMWHcMuzj8?feature=shared">Layer 2 Stage</a></li>



<li><strong>NEARCON Day Three Livestream</strong>&nbsp; – <a href="https://youtu.be/nsnit6wKIUU?feature=shared">Layer 1 Stage</a>, <a href="https://youtu.be/ghb5mxFQoOs?feature=shared">Layer 2 Stage</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Anyone who built furiously at the HackerHQ or clinked a cocktail at the Glass Movers &amp; Shakers Happy Hour will likely tell you something similar: that NEARCON ‘23 showed the importance of a truly open web — and how together we can all achieve it.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-unwrapped-lisbon-steps-into-the-open-web-in-iconic-fashion/">NEARCON &#8217;23 Unwrapped: Lisbon Steps into the Open Web in Iconic Fashion</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON ‘23 Day One: Major Announcements and Insightful Panels in Focus</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-23-day-one-major-announcements-and-insightful-panels-in-focus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 17:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON ‘23]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON Highlights]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21061</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As the sun set on Lisbon, the first day of an already iconic NEARCON ‘23 drew to a close, the …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-one-major-announcements-and-insightful-panels-in-focus/">NEARCON ‘23 Day One: Major Announcements and Insightful Panels in Focus</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As the sun set on Lisbon, the first day of an already iconic NEARCON ‘23 drew to a close, the excitement and momentum of the entire ecosystem was on full display. The morning kicked off with insightful sessions on open web interoperability and AI, all leading up to NEAR co-founder and newly announced NEAR Foundation CEO Illia Polosukhin unveiling some exciting announcements.</p>



<p>From regulatory talks to marketing in the open web, here’s everything that went down at Day One of NEARCON ‘23.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-talks-panels-and-sessions-highlight-day-one">Talks, panels and sessions highlight day one</h2>



<p><strong>NEAR: The Open Web Vision</strong><br>Illia Polosukhin, NEAR co-founder, delivered an inspiring session on his vision for the open web, sharing NEAR&#8217;s strategic direction and upcoming enhancements. His talk illuminated the path forward for the ecosystem, including new initiatives and partnerships in areas like account abstraction and NEAR’s role as the main portal to the open web.</p>



<p><strong>Regulating the Open Web: Chris Donovan and Michael Casey</strong><br>Chris Donovan, COO of NEAR Foundation, and Michael Casey, Chief Content Officer at CoinDesk, engaged in a riveting dialogue about the intersection of open web philosophies and regulation. They unpacked the complexities of fostering innovation within a framework that ensures inclusivity, transparency, and community governance.</p>



<p><strong>Innovations in AI, Account Abstraction, and NFTs Today</strong><br>Nate Geier, CEO of Mintbase, took attendees on a deep dive into the evolving realms of AI, account abstraction, and the burgeoning NFT landscape. His insights provided a closer look at how these technologies interplay to shape a user-centric NFT ecosystem and finding product market fit for NFT projects.</p>



<p><strong>Marketing Through Web3 Mechanisms at DevHub and Beyond</strong><br>Joe Spano of ShardDog highlighted the transformative power of open web mechanisms in the marketing domain. He discussed how decentralized approaches are reshaping brand strategies, offering businesses a novel way to engage with their audiences while retaining user privacy and control.</p>



<p><strong>Open Brand: Unlocking the Power of Brand to Accelerate Growth</strong></p>



<p>One of the biggest challenges for decentralized projects and founders is developing a powerful, cohesive brand. Tom Munckton, head of design at well-known branding agency Fold7, joined NEAR Foundation CMO Jack Collier in a fireside chat, where the two dove into NEAR’s rebrand as a case study for any open web project.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-recap-of-major-announcements">Recap of major announcements</h2>



<p>The crowd at NEARCON ‘23 was buzzing with anticipation as Illia took the stage to kick off the afternoon sessions, and he didn’t disappoint, unveiling a number of key announcements that will drive NEAR’s vision of the open web into the future.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-data-availability-da">NEAR Data Availability (DA)</h3>



<p>Perhaps the biggest announcement of the day was Illia lifting the curtain on <a href="/blog/near-foundation-launches-near-da-to-offer-secure-cost-effective-data-availability-for-eth-rollups-and-ethereum-developers/">NEAR DA</a>, offering Ethereum developers a low-cost, secure data availability layer. NEAR DA opens the door for enhanced modular blockchain solutions, ensuring scalability and cost-efficiency for developers in the NEAR ecosystem and beyond.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-polygon-zkwasm">Polygon zkWASM</h3>



<p>Illia also spotlighted a new NEAR and Polygon Labs partnership, zkWASM, which fuses zero-knowledge proofs with Web Assembly (WASM) for enhanced blockchain scalability and decentralization. This exciting research initiative will pave the way for greater trustless interoperability across the open web, including between NEAR and the Ethereum ecosystem.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-coin98-decentralized-dapp-store">Coin98 Decentralized Dapp Store&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Coin98&#8217;s new decentralized app store, leveraging NEAR’s Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S), will empower its 7 million users to access diverse apps across key Ethereum Layer-2 ecosystems. The user-friendly platform will enhance dApp discoverability, streamlining the open web experience within a single, decentralized interface.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ecosystem-announcements">Ecosystem announcements</h2>



<p>And the momentum didn’t stop there, with a couple of key ecosystem announcements coming to the forefront during Day One.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-tekuno-spurs-open-web-adoption">Tekuno spurs open web adoption</h3>



<p>Tekuno has sparked a surge in NEAR&#8217;s ecosystem by activating over 27,000 new wallets since March 2023. This NEAR BAAS platform, leveraging NFTs to gamify real-world experiences, has garnered attention with collaborations like Mastercard, showcasing NEAR&#8217;s growing appeal and Tekuno&#8217;s innovative impact.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-mintbase-empowers-near-builders">Mintbase empowers NEAR builders</h3>



<p>Mintbase, in partnership with NEAR, has launched its 2023 cohort to propel the NEAR ecosystem. The initiative aims to empower developers with essential open web development tools and has earmarked funding for innovative projects that contribute open-source solutions, driving forward the creation and adoption of decentralized applications.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-side-events-and-networking-success">Side events and networking success&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The day concluded with a couple of amazing side events where networking, brainstorming, and fun all came together. The final speaker session led right into the SailGP Happy Hour at the SailGP Lounge directly at the venue, giving NEARCON-goers a chance to unwind and socialize right away.</p>



<p>From there, things lead into the Opening Night Party, Sponsored by Cosmose and BitGo, at the Pavilhão Carlos Lopes. It’ll be a great chance to party until midnight with fellow builders, founders, and open web enthusiasts. Between the Opening Night party and SailGP Happy Hour, Day One’s social activities showcase the energy and enthusiasm of the entire ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-a-stellar-nearcon-day-two-agenda-around-the-corner">A stellar NEARCON Day Two agenda around the corner</h2>



<p>As NEARCON &#8217;23&#8217;s Day Two swiftly approaches, attendees can look forward to a plethora of enriching talks and panels, including deep dives into blockchain&#8217;s societal impacts and the latest in open web advancements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, the Women of Web3 Brunch and Founders Forum Programming kick off at 8:30 AM, offering insights on diversity, equity, and open web building success. And if you’re participating in the Hackathon, make sure your project is submitted by the deadline.</p>



<p>Thanks to everyone who attended Day One, and if you weren’t able to attend, rest assured that it’s just the beginning of a NEARCON ‘23 that will only grow to be more iconic over the next few days.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-one-major-announcements-and-insightful-panels-in-focus/">NEARCON ‘23 Day One: Major Announcements and Insightful Panels in Focus</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON ‘23 Lifts Off: Start Your Journey into the Open Web</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-23-lifts-off-start-your-journey-into-the-open-web/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON ‘23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21052</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Lisbon is about to light up as NEARCON ‘23 kicks off in the heart of the city. The stars are …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-lifts-off-start-your-journey-into-the-open-web/">NEARCON ‘23 Lifts Off: Start Your Journey into the Open Web</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Lisbon is about to light up as NEARCON ‘23 kicks off in the heart of the city. The stars are aligned for Day One to kick things off in spectacular fashion with a wide array of sessions, speakers, and activities you won’t want to miss.</p>



<p>Doors open at 9:00 AM for breakfast, so make sure to head on over bright an early, grab a bite with your fellow NEARCON-goers. And stay connected throughout the conference with Calimero Chat for private, decentralized comms on the NEAR blockchain.</p>



<p>So start off the most iconic NEARCON yet and catch some of the most intriguing and impactful happenings on what promises to be an epic first day of NEARCON ‘23.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-can-t-miss-speaker-sessions">Can’t miss speaker sessions&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Speaker stages ramp up at 10:45 AM until 5:30 PM, so set your alarms for an invigorating start to NEARCON ‘23 with sessions that promise to shape your understanding of the open web and the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>NEAR: The Open Web Stack </strong>(2:00 PM &#8211; 2:30 PM at Layer 1 Stage). Join Illia Polosukhin, CEO of NEAR Foundation and NEAR co-founder, as he shares his strategic vision on what’s next for the NEAR ecosystem.</li>



<li><strong>Regulating the Open Web</strong> (1:40 PM &#8211; 2:00 PM, Layer 1 Stage). Michael Casey from CoinDesk and NEAR Foundation COO Chris Donovan take a forward-thinking look at regulatory headwinds and regional approaches to open web regulations.</li>



<li><strong>Innovations in AI, Account Abstraction, and NFTs Today</strong> (3:00PM &#8211; 3:15 PM, Layer 2 stage). If you’re into the intersection of AI and NFTs, Nate Grier of Mintbase’s talk is one you won’t want to miss.</li>



<li><strong>Marketing Through Web3 Mechanisms at DevHub and Beyond </strong>(4:15 PM &#8211; 4:30 PM,</li>
</ul>



<p>Block Zero Stage). Shardog’s Joe Spano shares how the open web provides unique opportunities to create relationships while allowing users to retain control and privacy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-more-speaker-highlights">More speaker highlights</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>The Interop Future</strong> (11:30 AM &#8211; 12:00PM at Layer 1 Stage). An in-depth panel including Aurora founder Alex Shevchenko, and Mariano Sorgente of a16z will dive into&nbsp; NEAR&#8217;s critical role in driving open web interoperability.</li>



<li><strong>Unstore Your Data for the AI Revolution </strong>(11:20 AM &#8211; 11:40AM at Block Zero Stage). Don&#8217;t miss Jonathan Bryce and Polina Aladina from OnMachina as they delve into the future of data and AI, exploring new ways of working with unstructured data.</li>



<li><strong>Anjali Young&#8217;s Web3 Advertising Revolution </strong>(1:15 PM &#8211; 1:30 PM, Layer 2 Stage). Dive into the world of advertising and the open web with Anjali Young from Collab.Land. She’ll illustrate how Web3 is redefining brand-customer relationships through community engagement, NFTs, and token-gated communities.</li>



<li><strong>Richard Muirhead&#8217;s Vision of the Open Economy </strong>(4:30PM &#8211; 4:45 PM, Layer 1 Stage). Fabric Ventures&#8217; Richard Muirhead presents a compelling vision of 2023&#8217;s open economy, discussing the profound impact of token economics and the massive impact of AI on decentralized economies.</li>
</ul>



<p>Conclude your day enriched with insights from these thought leaders of the open web, and get revved up for the evening networking and festivities.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-hackathon-and-hzn1-in-full-force">Hackathon and HZN1 in full force</h2>



<p>There’s also tons of activity for builders, founders, and developers during Day One. Things kick off at 9:00AM with the all day HZ1 Retreat for Founders. It’s an invite-only event so if you’re on the list, get ready for a full day of jumpstarting your vision supported by the best open web experts until 5:00PM.</p>



<p>And then there’s what promises to be an epic Hackathon. Make sure you’re registered, submit your projects, and join your fellow builders over at the Hacker HQ. Get the full low-down over at the official <a href="https://nearcon.app/hackathon">NEARCON ‘23 Hackathon webpage</a>, and kick things off with a full day of hacking and B.O.S building.</p>



<p>Finally, there’s the invite-only Validator Session at Hacker HQ from 1:00-4:00PM, so if you’re registered for that don’t forget to check it out and participate.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-must-attend-side-events">Must attend side events</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>SailGP Happy Hour</strong> (5:45 &#8211; 7:00 PM, SailGP Lounge, Layer 2 Stage): Wind down from a dynamic day of sessions and celebrate the community spirit of NEARCON ‘23 with one of the pioneers of Web3 and fan engagement..</li>



<li><strong>Opening Night Party</strong> (8:00 PM, Pavilhão Carlos Lopes): Don&#8217;t miss Day One’s biggest networking event, sponsored by Cosmose AI and BitGo, where the energy of NEARCON ‘23 will be on full display under the Lisbon stars.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-shout-out-to-the-day-one-sponsors">Shout out to the Day One sponsors</h2>



<p>A heartfelt thanks to our sponsors that highlighted Day One of NEARCON ‘23:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>SailGP</strong></li>



<li><strong>BitGo</strong></li>



<li><strong>Cosmose AI</strong></li>



<li><strong>PlayEmber</strong></li>



<li><strong>Aurora Labs</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Day One of NEARCON promises to be an amazing kick off to an iconic gathering of minds, builders, and creators in the open web. From interoperability and cryptonomics to drinks and brainstorming well into the night, make sure to mark your calendars for all of the notable speakers and sessions that will make Day One a simply can’t miss.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-lifts-off-start-your-journey-into-the-open-web/">NEARCON ‘23 Lifts Off: Start Your Journey into the Open Web</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing NCON and How to Use It at NEARCON ‘23</title>
		<link>/blog/introducing-ncon-and-how-to-use-it-at-nearcon-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 22:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON ‘23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hello NEARians, By now many of you are in or are en route to the magical city of Lisbon for …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-ncon-and-how-to-use-it-at-nearcon-23/">Introducing NCON and How to Use It at NEARCON ‘23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hello NEARians,</p>



<p>By now many of you are in or are en route to the magical city of Lisbon for NEARCON23! The amount of alpha dropping this week will have you weak in your knees. It’s been our mission to bring you an event that puts Web3 experiences at the forefront of NEARCON. Even better when we partner with our Community to bring you a truly social experience elevating your journeys throughout NEARCON. This year NCON makes its big debut!&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-is-ncon">What is NCON?&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The NEAR Foundation has partnered with Jutsu, Keypom, and Veriken to create an exciting experience for you: the NCON token —&nbsp;an event experience built on B.O.S. NCON embodies the essence of the open web. An open web where we transact with each other on a peer to peer network.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Interacting with sponsors, attending content sessions, paying for your lunch, will be part of the NCON experience. As you complete NCON Bounties (see the full list below), you’ll be rewarded NCON which can be redeemed for swag, lunches, and other goodies during NEARCON.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When you check in at registration you will automatically receive 100 NCON — enough to buy lunch for 3 days and 1 piece of swag. Complete Bounties to earn more NCON and maximize your NEARCON experience. At the end of NEARCON, the top 3 NCON redeemers will receive a free trip to NEARCON24. Visit the helpdesk to verify your Bounty completions and get dropped NCON.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Good luck and “happy bounting”!</p>



<p><em>*</em>NCON<em> exists for the purposes of NEARCON and NCON holds no real financial value beyond the event. </em><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1nUvEXwUfzkZcLXNr5muRZ1hAQjDeNY8R/view"><em>Terms and conditions apply</em></a><em>.&nbsp;</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">NCON Bounties to complete</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>BOUNTY</strong></td><td><strong>NCON REWARD</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Ticket Claim (done at registration)</td><td>100.00</td></tr><tr><td>We’re dropping various amounts of NCON during sessions, roundtables, firesides, panels and keynotes. The more sessions you join, the higher chance for more NCON!</td><td>1.00 &#8211; 10.00</td></tr><tr><td>Take a picture with the Opening Ceremony special guest and tweet “FOUNDERS, DEVELOPERS, BUILDERS #NEARCON2023”</td><td>20.00</td></tr><tr><td>Early Bird Drops (arrive to NEARCON or Hacker HQs between 9am and 10:30am)</td><td>5.00</td></tr><tr><td>Visit all three venues (tweet pictures of each venue and #NEARCON2023)</td><td>5.00</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://near.org/blog/call-for-founders-and-developers-to-qualify-your-b-o-s-apps-before-nearcon-23">Upvote apps in the B.O.S. App Library&nbsp;</a></td><td>5.00</td></tr><tr><td>Attend one of the Founders Forum sessions&nbsp;</td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td>Complete the Shard Dog Engage-a-thon</td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://nearprotocol1001.typeform.com/ResearchIntake?typeform-source=qrcode-button">Submit Pagoda User Research Survey</a></td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td>Shoutout your favorite thing on NEARCON Twitter #NEARCON2023</td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td>Submit a Hackathon Project</td><td>40.00</td></tr><tr><td>Visit the B.O.S. Booth</td><td>5.00</td></tr><tr><td>Visit the hacker help desk and get help on your project (or just get your NCON Drop)</td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Sponsor Bounties</strong></td><td>Varies</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Glass</strong> &#8211; Sign up for GLASS at www.glass.fun/signup, and tag us (@glassdotfun) in a tweet about your favorite thing you&#8217;ve eaten or drank so far at NEARCON!</td><td>5.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Aurora</strong> &#8211; Visit Aurora booth, talk to Armand or Slava, tweet “Big Alpha coming soon on @auroraisnear” without a spoiler.</td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Proximity</strong> &#8211; Attend a talk featuring a Proximity team member. Post on X and tag @proximityfi</td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Proximity </strong>&#8211; Try out these B.O.S.-powered gateways for L2s and share your thoughts on X: Polygon zkEVM Interactive App Dashboard, Mantle Ecosystem Gateway, &#8220;B.O.S.&#8221; Store on the Coin98 Super App.</td><td>20.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Mintbase </strong>&#8211; Minsta your NEARCON moments and earn NCON 🤳🏻<br>▾ Go to https://minsta.mintbase.xyz/<br>▾ Take a photo and mint it as a NFT</td><td>8.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Octopus </strong>&#8211; Visit us at the Octopus Network booth and tweet a picture at the booth with &#8220;Otto&#8221; tagging @oct_network and #NEARCON.&nbsp;</td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Octopus </strong>&#8211; Interact with Octopus Network on mainnet.oct.network, in forum at forum.oct.network or at Octopus DAO on AstroDAO for a 5x multiplier bonus!</td><td>10.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Calimero</strong> &#8211; Log in to Calimero Chat, the official chat of NEARCON, and send an epic meme! The funnier your meme, the more NCON you score! Claim them at the Calimero booth.</td><td>2.00 &#8211; 5.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>The Littles </strong>-1. Visit TheFunPass booth2. Participate in their Stick Catcher experience.</td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>NEAR Mobile</strong> &#8211; Publish a tweet describing what you like more about @NEARMobile_app- Download NEAR Mobile (https://nearmobile.app/) and give us a review on Google Play or App Store- Follow us on Twitter (@NEARMobile_app), join our Telegram (https://t.me/NEARMobile) and subscribe to YT (@NEARMobileWallet).</td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>NEAR Balkans</strong> &#8211; NEAR Lisbon Adventure: Collect all flags at the NEACON booths!</td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>NEAR Balkans</strong> &#8211; POAP: Find the POAP QR code and prove your attendance at NEARCON with the Tekuno PODs!</td><td>2.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>SailGP</strong> &#8211; SailGP&#8217;s NEARcon Scavenger Hunt: Download the SailGP app and join our fan loyalty program, The Dock. Then, set off to explore NEARcon&#8217;s three venues, hunting down not one, not two, but SEVEN SailGP QR codes. Scan all seven codes using the SailGP app to snag your exclusive SailGP x NEARcon NFT. Once you&#8217;ve got your hands on it, head over to the SailGP booth, present your collectible, and get in on the action to win daily prizes on top of NCON!</td><td>5.00</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to redeem your NCON</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Redeemable</strong></td><td><strong>NCON PRICE</strong></td></tr><tr><td>LUNCH (NEARCON and HACKER HQs)</td><td>15 per visit</td></tr><tr><td>White t-shirt</td><td>20.00</td></tr><tr><td>Black t-shirt</td><td>20.00</td></tr><tr><td>Green t-shirt</td><td>20.00</td></tr><tr><td>Cream hoodie</td><td>50.00</td></tr><tr><td>Black hoodie</td><td>50.00</td></tr><tr><td>Windbreaker</td><td>50.00</td></tr><tr><td>Cream hat</td><td>15.00</td></tr><tr><td>Black hat</td><td>15.00</td></tr><tr><td>Water bottle</td><td>10.00</td></tr><tr><td>Duffle bag</td><td>50.00</td></tr><tr><td>Tangem Wallet V1</td><td>40</td></tr><tr><td>Tangem Wallet V2</td><td>40</td></tr><tr><td>Bottle Openers</td><td>5</td></tr><tr><td>Early Closing Party Access</td><td>50</td></tr><tr><td>Horizon Credits for Founders</td><td>30</td></tr><tr><td>Top 3 NCON Redeemers will receive a free trip to NEARCNO24!</td><td>—&#8211;</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-ncon-and-how-to-use-it-at-nearcon-23/">Introducing NCON and How to Use It at NEARCON ‘23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why NEARCON is the Must-See Global Web3 Event of 2023</title>
		<link>/blog/why-nearcon-is-the-must-see-global-web3-event-of-2023/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON ‘23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Just less than a week until Lisbon rumbles as the epicenter of the NEAR ecosystem. Step into the open web …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/why-nearcon-is-the-must-see-global-web3-event-of-2023/">Why NEARCON is the Must-See Global Web3 Event of 2023</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Just less than a week until Lisbon rumbles as the epicenter of the NEAR ecosystem. Step into the open web at NEARCON ‘23 across three different stunning venues, with the Convento Do Beato being the main hub for things like&nbsp; founder and builder talks. Rua Pereira will pop off with creative and community action, and hardcore dev building will be going down at the Hacker HQ.</p>



<p>Don’t miss what’s next in NEAR’s vision for an open web that’s scalable, user-friendly, and secure. NEAR has grown to over 30 million active accounts and over 1,000 projects, and NEARCON ‘23 will showcase all these ecosystem successes, along with a slate of brand new product and ecosystem announcements.</p>



<p>Here’s exactly why you’ll want to be in Lisbon starting on November 7th.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-a-track-for-everyone-at-nearcon-23">A track for everyone at NEARCON ‘23</h2>



<p>This year’s edition promises to be even more iconic then the last, with diverse tracks for any open web enthusiast, along with a melting pot of cultural and social activities to spice up the nights — Portuguese style.</p>



<p>No matter who you are, one of these tracks is likely tailor made for your interests:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Developers: </strong>Sharpen your skills in open web technology with hands-on workshops and coding sessions. This is your chance to get a first-hand look at the newest innovations in the blockchain space.</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>Entrepreneurs</strong>: Listen to industry leaders as they offer game-changing insights, actionable strategies, and practical advice you need to transform your vision into the next unicorn startup.</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>Creatives: </strong>Explore how blockchain technology can revolutionize art, marketing, and beyond. You&#8217;ll walk away with new perspectives on how to infuse blockchain into your creative process.</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>Regulators</strong>: Blockchain regulations can seem like a daunting maze of laws and policies. Get the low-down on best practices, legal frameworks, and the future of blockchain regulation from experts in the field.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-hackathons-bounty-rewards-and-ai-at-the-bleeding-edge">Hackathons, bounty rewards, and AI at the bleeding edge</h2>



<p>If you’re a developer, fling yourself into an intense 48-hour <a href="https://nearcon.app/hackathon">NEARCON hackathon</a> where you’ll get the chance to build next-level apps for NEAR and potentially see your project in the spotlight. Developers can also <a href="https://near.org/blog/call-for-founders-and-developers-to-qualify-your-b-o-s-apps-before-nearcon-23/">earn NCON tokens</a> through bounties, redeemable for perks from food to merch. Also, don&#8217;t miss the much anticipated &#8220;<a href="/blog/ai-is-near-the-future-of-ai-on-the-open-web-at-nearcon-23/">AI is NEAR</a>&#8221; track led by AI and machine learning OGs Illia Polosukhin and Alex Skidanov, exploring where AI meets the Open Web.</p>



<p>So whether you&#8217;re an AI head who craves the latest insights from the baddest machine learning experts or a curious founder who delights in brainstorming over a local merlot at one of the many super cool side events, NEARCON ‘23 is sure to be memorable and valuable.</p>



<p>With tracks tailored to suit every interest, ecosystem milestones to celebrate, and a hackathon that brings the brightest minds together, NEARCON ‘23 is the can’t miss event of the year for anyone curious, passionate (or both) about what’s next for the&nbsp; open web.</p>



<p>So what are you waiting for? <a href="https://nearcon.app/nearpad.testnet/widget/Index?tab=register">Sign up for NEARCON &#8217;23 now</a> to secure your spot!<br><em>And let’s not forget some special treatment is in store for </em><a href="/blog/%d1%83%d0%bd%d1%96%d0%ba%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bb%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2-%d0%b1/?_gl=1%2A1deejbu%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTY4MTY0NTc0NS4xNjk4MTUxODc4%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5ODE1MTg3NC4xLjEuMTY5ODE1MjI2NC4wLjAuMA.."><em>Ukrainians</em></a><em>, students in </em><a href="/blog/entradas-gratuitas-a-nearcon-23-para-estudiantes-en-espana/?_gl=1%2A1deejbu%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTY4MTY0NTc0NS4xNjk4MTUxODc4%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5ODE1MTg3NC4xLjEuMTY5ODE1MjI2NC4wLjAuMA.."><em>Spain</em></a><em> and </em><a href="/blog/estudantes-terao-ingressos-gratis-no-nearcon23/?_gl=1%2A1clz06g%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTY4MTY0NTc0NS4xNjk4MTUxODc4%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5ODE1MTg3NC4xLjEuMTY5ODE1MjI2NC4wLjAuMA.."><em>Portugal</em></a><em>, and </em><a href="/blog/nearcon-irl-hackathon-2023-build-the-open-web/?_gl=1%2A1fu2kk1%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTY4MTY0NTc0NS4xNjk4MTUxODc4%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5ODE1MTg3NC4xLjEuMTY5ODE1MjI2NC4wLjAuMA.."><em>hackathon registrants</em></a><em>. All of the above can head over to those pages and register for a totally free NEARCON ‘23 pass!</em></p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/why-nearcon-is-the-must-see-global-web3-event-of-2023/">Why NEARCON is the Must-See Global Web3 Event of 2023</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Call for Founders and Developers to Qualify Your B.O.S Apps Before NEARCON ‘23 </title>
		<link>/blog/call-for-founders-and-developers-to-qualify-your-b-o-s-apps-before-nearcon-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NCON Bounties]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON ‘23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21013</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Dear NEAR B.O.S Developer Community,&#160; This week, the Pagoda product team launched the App Library to help B.O.S founders and …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/call-for-founders-and-developers-to-qualify-your-b-o-s-apps-before-nearcon-23/">Call for Founders and Developers to Qualify Your B.O.S Apps Before NEARCON ‘23 </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Dear NEAR B.O.S Developer Community,&nbsp;</p>



<p>This week, the Pagoda product team launched the App Library to help B.O.S founders and developers showcase and promote their apps. With over 200 applications powered by B.O.S and more than 11,000 components now in the ecosystem, the App Library is a page on near.org designed to help users and community members find your applications and promote greater usage across the NEAR ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-app-upvoting-event-ncon-bounty">The App Upvoting Event: NCON Bounty</h2>



<p>To find the first group of featured apps on App Library, we are launching the <a href="https://near.org/near/widget/AppLibrary.Nearcon.IndexPage">App Upvoting Event as a NCON Bounty</a> to invite all NEARCON attendees to upvote and decide who gets featured!&nbsp;</p>



<p>“NCON Bounties” is a Web3 gamified event experience for attendees to engage throughout the event. Attendees will earn NCON by completing Bounties and have the option to redeem NCON for food, merchandise, and more. Participants who decide to complete this special NCON Bounties experience will also help select the first group of featured apps in the B.O.S. App Library.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-to-qualify-and-get-your-app-featured">How to Qualify and Get Your App Featured?</h3>



<p>To ensure your dApp shines during this event, here&#8217;s what you need to do. The following steps can be be found in the B.O.S interface for those who want to participate — simply go to the Metadata page of your app and follow the instructions below:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Create a Captivating Description</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Craft a compelling introduction to your dApp. Highlight its unique features and value proposition. Pro tip: Add <em>screenshots</em> to make your dApp visually appealing and easy to understand. (Description is <strong>required</strong>!)</p>



<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Tag Your App</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>First, make sure to tag the component that holds the entry to your project experience as <strong>App</strong>. Then, choose the category that best represents your dApp—<strong>Earn, Play, Develop, Engage</strong>. (Choosing <strong>one of these four</strong> categories is <strong>required</strong>! If you applied more than one of these four tags, then we will only use the latest one you applied.) Add additional tags for improved discoverability. Make it easy for users to find and appreciate your work.</p>



<p>(<em>These categories are suggested from research around users’ needs, broken down by categories and industry app store benchmarks. Check near.org/applications on how these categories are currently being used)</em></p>



<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Spread the Word</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>It&#8217;s time to promote! Rally your community, spread the news across your networks, and encourage users to like and engage with your dApp. The more upvotes your app gets, the greater your chances of securing a top spot.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-why-participate">Why Participate?</h3>



<p>The App Library isn&#8217;t just a catalog — it&#8217;s an interactive platform that spotlights the capabilities of the NEAR B.O.S. It will become the most visited page on near.org and serves as a gateway to the NEAR Ecosystem. By participating, you have the chance to feature prominently on the App Library and the NEAR homepage for the next three months, gaining exposure and recognition across the NEAR ecosystem and beyond.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-s-the-payoff">What’s the Payoff?&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Your active participation can lead to significant rewards:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Top 8 Featured dApps</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>The dApps with the highest number of upvotes from this event will be showcased prominently on the landing page of the App Library for the next three months, putting your creation on the most visited page on near.org.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Category Leaders&nbsp;</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>The top 4 dApps in each category will be prominently featured on category pages, such as Earn, Play, Develop, and Engage. This targeted exposure aligns with the core needs and use cases of the diverse NEAR user base.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-s-next">What’s Next?&nbsp;</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Upvote Button Enabled 2 days Before NEARCON</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>2 days before NEARCON, you will see an <em>upvote</em> button appear on the details pages of your qualified Apps. Any users who have an account on near.org can now send their support by hitting that upvote button. This upvote button will be disabled two days after NEARCON, and the total number of upvotes you received in the event will be displayed for 6 months on your details page as your participation badge.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>NEARCON attendees will be incentivized to engage with App Upvoting by earning NCON</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>QR code and event posters will be promoted at the NEARCON venues to encourage them to complete this Bounty. In addition, this Bounty will be part of the NCON product for NEARCON participants to earn more NCON, so we will make sure your dApps get plenty of exposure.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-event-timeline-summary">Event Timeline Summary</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>October 27th</strong> — Submit your App for Qualification. <a href="https://near.org/near/widget/AppLibrary.Nearcon.IndexPage">App Upvoting Bounty Event Page</a> made available on near.org. Qualified Apps will be Fetched (Qualified Apps will be fetched continuously on one-hour intervals throughout the NEARCON event through November 13th).</li>



<li><strong>November 3rd</strong> — Upvote button enabled + counters started.</li>



<li><strong>November 13th</strong> — Upvote disabled + results calculated.</li>



<li><strong>November 17th</strong> — Results display + feature apps updated on main App Library page.</li>
</ul>



<p>The primary goal of the App Library is to celebrate the creativity and efforts of NEAR developers and founders. To increase visibility, boost engagement, and get valuable feedback from the whole NEAR community on your app, make sure to register your apps as qualified and participate in the <a href="https://near.org/near/widget/AppLibrary.Nearcon.IndexPage">App Upvoting NCON Bounty</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/call-for-founders-and-developers-to-qualify-your-b-o-s-apps-before-nearcon-23/">Call for Founders and Developers to Qualify Your B.O.S Apps Before NEARCON ‘23 </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet the Builders of the Open Web: Top Speakers at NEARCON &#8217;23</title>
		<link>/blog/meet-the-builders-of-the-open-web-top-speakers-at-nearcon-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 18:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON ‘23]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON Speakers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you thought last year&#8217;s NEARCON was epic, then wait until you see what’s in store for NEARCON &#8217;23 in …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/meet-the-builders-of-the-open-web-top-speakers-at-nearcon-23/">Meet the Builders of the Open Web: Top Speakers at NEARCON &#8217;23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you thought last year&#8217;s NEARCON was epic, then wait until you see what’s in store for NEARCON &#8217;23 in Lisbon, kicking off on November 7th. From deep dives into the open web to insightful sessions featuring global leaders in blockchain and the open web, here’s the inside scoop on what to expect at this year’s iconic edition.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-awaits-you-at-nearcon-23">What awaits you at NEARCON &#8217;23</h2>



<p>NEARCON &#8217;23 is set to be a smorgasbord of innovation and collaboration. Taking place across three venues in Lisbon, including the historic Convento Do Beato, and spanning four days, NEARCON ‘23 attendees will have access to an array of exciting opportunities. From enlightening talks on AI and Web3&#8217;s future to hands-on developer hackathons, there’s something for everyone.</p>



<p>You also won’t want to miss exclusive networking sessions that connect you with NEAR and multi-chain enthusiasts and projects from around the globe. Attendees also get a firsthand experience with building on the Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S.).</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-meet-the-big-brains-of-nearcon-23">Meet the Big Brains of NEARCON &#8217;23</h2>



<p>There’s an incredible lineup of speakers and thought leaders scheduled for this year’s edition of NEARCON. Here’s a rundown of some of top names you’ll on various stages, panels and sessions:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Mitchell Amador: </strong>Founder and CEO of <a href="https://immunefi.com/">Immunefi</a>. Mitchell is a leading voice in blockchain security and will explore how incentivized bounties enhance security.</li>



<li><strong>James Young:</strong> The Co-founder and CCO of <a href="https://www.collab.land/">Collab.Land</a> will delve into the power of tokenized communities, from governance to engagement.</li>



<li><strong>Samantha Bohbot:</strong> Chief Growth Officer at <a href="https://rockawayx.com/">RockawayX</a>. An expert in strategic growth, Samantha will share essential tips for project scalability.</li>



<li><strong>Se Hyun Oh: </strong>SVP at <a href="https://www.sktelecom.com/index_en.html">SK Telecom</a>. Expect insights into the convergence of telecom, AI, and the open web.</li>



<li><strong>Michael Casey:</strong> Chief Content Officer at <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/">CoinDesk</a>. Michael will dissect the evolving narratives around cryptocurrency and its impact on the traditional financial sector.</li>



<li><strong>Richard Muirhead:</strong> Managing Partner at <a href="https://fabric.vc/">Fabric Ventures</a>. Hear a venture capitalist’s perspective on what makes a blockchain project investable.</li>



<li><strong>Oleg Fomenko:</strong> Co-founder of <a href="https://sweatco.in/">Sweat Economy</a>. Join the discussion on how blockchain is revolutionizing health and fitness via Move-to-Earn.</li>



<li><strong>Nicolai Reinbold:</strong> Global Head of Expansion and Innovation at <a href="https://www.cvlabs.com/">CV Labs</a>. Nicolai will cover blockchain innovation hubs and their role in nurturing early-stage startups.</li>



<li><strong>Teana Baker-Taylor</strong>: <a href="https://www.circle.com/en/">Circle’s</a> VP of Policy and Regulatory Strategy for the EU/UK. She’ll address the regulatory landscape surrounding blockchain and cryptocurrencies.</li>



<li><strong>Joy Macknight</strong>: The editor at <a href="https://www.thebanker.com/">The Banker</a> will offer an overview of how the open web and blockchain are disrupting traditional banking systems.<br>Check out the <a href="https://nearcon.app/speakers">complete list of NEARCON 23&#8242; Speakers</a>, full of founders, builders, VCs, and other open web innovators. </li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-maximizing-your-nearcon-23-experience">Maximizing your NEARCON &#8217;23 experience</h2>



<p>While the speakers are a definite draw, NEARCON &#8217;23 is more than just speaker sessions. You can also join the <a href="/blog/nearcon-irl-hackathon-2023-build-the-open-web/?_gl=1%2A41qcf0%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AOTY3ODAzMDQ2LjE2OTc2NDc0ODk.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5NzY0NzQ4Ny4xLjEuMTY5NzY0ODExNS4wLjAuMA..">NEARCON IRL Hackathon</a> where developers will have the chance to build directly on the B.O.S and compete for over $140,000 in prizes. In case you didn’t already know, NEARCON is free for hackers participating in the hackathon! At NEARCON ‘23, there’s something for just about everyone.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-four-distinct-paths-to-explore-at-nearcon-23">Four Distinct Paths to Explore at NEARCON &#8217;23</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Developers: </strong>Engage in technical workshops and learn from the best in the business. These sessions are designed to meet you at any point in your open web journey.</li>



<li><strong>Entrepreneurs</strong>: Explore how the open web can revolutionize the way businesses connect and engage with users through innovative products and solutions.</li>



<li><strong>Creators:</strong> Discover how the open web can disrupt traditional systems, offering more equitable platforms for creators to get discovered and fairly compensated.</li>



<li><strong>Regulators:</strong> Stay up-to-date with the evolving regulations and policies that are shaping the open web, keeping you ahead of the curve.</li>
</ul>



<p>And don&#8217;t forget the networking opportunities, where you’ll get a chance to collaborate and engage in exciting conversations with NEAR community members from around the world.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-don-t-miss-the-future-at-nearcon-23">Don&#8217;t miss the future at NEARCON &#8217;23</h2>



<p>Your chance to explore the entire NEAR ecosystem and the B.O.S is right around the corner. So, come play a part in driving the open web towards mass adoption. And with General Admission ticket prices still available, NEARCON ‘23 is still a steal for anyone interested in helping shape the future of blockchain and decentralization.</p>



<p>So what are you waiting for? <a href="https://tickets.nearcon.org/?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_campaign=google_events_nearcon_conversion_gl&amp;utm_content=nearcon_non-brand_blockchain-crypto-web3_gl______T1300&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwhL6pBhDjARIsAGx8D5-H2EpU3t-EF2qlg6YDwlzx5HgVqTUboWoe5nftEla82nDzSqVG1YUaAuJ9EALw_wcB">Register for NEARCON &#8217;23</a> to secure your spot today. And if you’re a <a href="/blog/%d1%83%d0%bd%d1%96%d0%ba%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bb%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2-%d0%b1/?_gl=1%2A41qcf0%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AOTY3ODAzMDQ2LjE2OTc2NDc0ODk.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5NzY0NzQ4Ny4xLjEuMTY5NzY0ODExNS4wLjAuMA..">Ukrainian</a> living in Portugal, or a student in <a href="/blog/estudantes-terao-ingressos-gratis-no-nearcon23/?_gl=1%2A1897020%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AOTY3ODAzMDQ2LjE2OTc2NDc0ODk.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5NzY0NzQ4Ny4xLjAuMTY5NzY0NzQ4Ny4wLjAuMA..">Portugal</a> or <a href="/blog/entradas-gratuitas-a-nearcon-23-para-estudiantes-en-espana/?_gl=1%2A41qcf0%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AOTY3ODAzMDQ2LjE2OTc2NDc0ODk.%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5NzY0NzQ4Ny4xLjEuMTY5NzY0ODExNS4wLjAuMA..">Spain</a>, click those links for more information on how to register and attend NEARCON ‘23 in Lisbon for absolutely free!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/meet-the-builders-of-the-open-web-top-speakers-at-nearcon-23/">Meet the Builders of the Open Web: Top Speakers at NEARCON &#8217;23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Унікальна можливість для українців: Безкоштовні квитки на NEARCON ‘23</title>
		<link>/blog/%d1%83%d0%bd%d1%96%d0%ba%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bb%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2-%d0%b1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 18:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON ‘23]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEARCON &#8217;23 &#8211; це багатоденна конференція, яка збирає найяскравіших представників блокчейн-індустрії з усього світу. Це місце, де ви зможете почути …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/%d1%83%d0%bd%d1%96%d0%ba%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bb%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2-%d0%b1/">Унікальна можливість для українців: Безкоштовні квитки на NEARCON ‘23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEARCON &#8217;23 &#8211; це багатоденна конференція, яка збирає найяскравіших представників блокчейн-індустрії з усього світу. Це місце, де ви зможете почути найсвіжіші ідеї, познайомитися зі світовими експертами та знайти натхнення для вашої майбутньої кар&#8217;єри. NEARCON &#8217;23 пропонує широкий спектр тематик, включаючи штучний інтелект, кібербезпеку, блокчейн, веб-розробку та багато іншого.</p>



<p>Як невеликий акт солідарності, NEAR Foundation пропонує обмежену кількість БЕЗКОШТОВНИХ квитків для українців, які живуть у Португалії чи Іспанії, на NEARCON ‘23, що відбудеться в Лісабоні з 7 по 10 листопада.</p>



<p>Це неймовірна можливість познайомитися зі світом Web3, розширити свої знання та знайти нові можливості для кар&#8217;єрного зростання. Не пропустіть цю унікальну можливість та отримайте безкоштовний квиток на NEARCON &#8217;23 вже сьогодні!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-що-таке-nearcon">Що таке NEARCON?</h3>



<p>Ті, хто не знайомі з Web3, можуть не бути обізнані, що NEAR &#8211; це блокчейн, екосистема та міжнародна спільнота розробників, підприємців, фаундерів і провідних фігур у сфері децентралізації.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="http://nearcon.org/">NEARCON</a> &#8211; це основна щорічна подія для NEAR. Кожного року спільнота NEAR збирається, щоб слухати, навчатися, спілкуватися та розробляти надихаючі ідеї для майбутнього.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEARCON &#8211; це найкраща освіта в галузі Web3! Як провідний децентралізований проект у світі, NEAR прагне привернути та надихати наступне покоління талантів Web3 з обмеженою кількістю безкоштовних місць.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-що-ви-дізнаєтесь-на-nearcon-2023">Що ви дізнаєтесь на NEARCON 2023</h3>



<p>Web3 складається з кількох ключових ролей і секторів, і на NEARCON ‘23 ми матимемо можливість почути виступи та взяти участь у панельних дискусіях із провідними фігурами в галузі Web3.&nbsp;</p>



<p>На NEARCON будуть обговорюватися такі теми як Open Web, де використовуються технології з відкритим кодом, включаючи NEAR. Також буде розглядатися взаємодія блокчейну та штучного інтелекту сьогодні та їхні перспективи в майбутньому, а також роль <a href="https://www.neardc.org/">NEAR Digital Collective</a> у децентралізації управління NEAR. Крім того, будуть поширені оновлення щодо регулювання та політики в сфері Web3.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-як-отримати-безкоштовний-квиток-на-nearcon-23">Як отримати безкоштовний квиток на NEARCON ‘23</h3>



<p>Отримати безкоштовні квиток на NEARCON ‘23 просто!&nbsp;</p>



<p>Основні вимоги включають:</p>



<ul>
<li>Ви є українцем, що тимчасово проживає в Іспанії/Португалії</li>



<li>Ваш вік більше за 18 років</li>



<li>Ви можете відвідати подію особисто в Лісабоні з 7 по 10 листопада</li>
</ul>



<p>Щоб отримати безкоштовний квиток на NEARCON &#8217;23, переходьте за <a href="https://near.org/nearcon23.near/widget/Index?tab=register">посиланням</a>, заповніть форму аплікації. Вас буде перенаправлено до завершення оплати, де ви введете код знижки <strong>«UKFRENSNCON»</strong>. Ви отримаєте квитанцію на ваш імейл, і квиток буде надіслано вам пізніше перед NEARCON ‘23.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/%d1%83%d0%bd%d1%96%d0%ba%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bb%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2-%d0%b1/">Унікальна можливість для українців: Безкоштовні квитки на NEARCON ‘23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
