<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NEARCON 23 Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/nearcon-23-3/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/nearcon-23-3/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 10:42:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>NEARCON 23 Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/nearcon-23-3/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>NEARCON ‘23 Day Three: Shaping the Future of Decentralized Governance </title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-23-day-three-shaping-the-future-of-decentralized-governance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 08:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21078</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEARCON &#8217;23&#8217;s grand finale is here, packed with groundbreaking sessions you won&#8217;t want to miss. It&#8217;s been a great ride …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-three-shaping-the-future-of-decentralized-governance/">NEARCON ‘23 Day Three: Shaping the Future of Decentralized Governance </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEARCON &#8217;23&#8217;s grand finale is here, packed with groundbreaking sessions you won&#8217;t want to miss. It&#8217;s been a great ride so far, with engaging sessions, a mind-blowing hackathon, and the chance to network in person with open web experts from all over the globe. Today’s agenda has some of the most impactful talks yet, so get ready to send NEARCON ‘23 out with a bang!</p>



<p>Start with a coffee at 9:00 AM and enjoy breakfast at the venue with other attendees before diving into our final day of immersive sessions. By 10:45 AM, the curtain will lift on the main stage for NEARCON 23’s final foray into Web3 — including a special, surprise announcement from NEAR CEO Illia Polosukhin.<br>Remember, you can stay connected throughout the day on Calimero Chat  — a private, decentralized comms built on the NEAR blockchain.<br><em>*Note: There is no bag check or cloak room at any NEARCON venue</em>. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-can-t-miss-sessions-on-day-three">Can’t miss sessions on Day Three</h2>



<p><strong>What 2024 Looks Like for Decentralized Democracy</strong> (1:00 PM &#8211; 1:30 PM, Layer 1 Stage).</p>



<p>Join us for a deep dive into the future of governance on NEAR, where the visionaries behind NEAR&#8217;s political framework dissect past triumphs and unfold the master plan for 2024. Hear from our panelists, including Joe Spano of ShardDog and Blaze from Cheddar.</p>



<p><strong>Special Announcement </strong>(12:00 PM &#8211; 12:30 PM, Layer 1 Stage). Don’t miss NEAR Co-founder and NEAR Foundation CEO Illia Polosukhin’s major announcement. When Illia speaks, the entire Web3 world listens, so grab a quick bite and head on over to the main stage for what’s sure to be Illia’s mic-drop moment of NEARCON ‘23.</p>



<p><strong>NEAR Governance Forum</strong> (11:05 AM &#8211; 12:00 PM, Layer 2 Stage). Curious about NEAR’s decentralized governance model? Get your questions answered by Alejandro Betancourt of the Transparency Commission and Cameron Dennis of Banyan Collective, with the conversation facilitated by Gus Friis of NEARWEEK.</p>



<p><strong>NEAR Campus: Unleashing the Potential of University Partnerships for DevHub </strong>(11:00 AM &#8211; 11:20 AM). NEAR DevHub’s Boris Polania will showcase the NEAR Campus&#8217;s role in revolutionizing developer engagement. Explore the relationship between NEAR and academia, and how NEAR Campus will serve as a touchpoint for global campuses in the future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sensational-speaker-highlights">Sensational speaker highlights</h2>



<p><strong>Unveiling the Web3 BUILD Incubator Fellowship</strong> (11:20 AM &#8211; 11:30 AM, Block Zero Stage)</p>



<p>Max Mizzi from Major League Hacking will introduce the BUILD Incubator Fellowship, an innovative collaboration with NEAR Horizon. Discover the inception, operation, and success stories of the program&#8217;s trailblazing summer cohort.</p>



<p><strong>It&#8217;s Honest Work: How DeFi Is Growing Up </strong>(11:30 AM &#8211; 12:00 PM, Layer 1 Stage),</p>



<p>From ‘DeFi Summer’ to today, decentralized finance remains one of the most promising areas of crypto — and it’s inevitably maturing. Drop by as an incredible panel included Arjun Arora from Orderly Network, Mike Cahill of Douro Labs, and more chart recent developments that are reshaping DeFi&#8217;s landscape on NEAR and beyond.</p>



<p><strong>Aurora Unleashed: Igniting NEAR&#8217;s Potential </strong>(11:15 AM &#8211; 11:30 AM, Layer 1 Stage).</p>



<p>Alex Shevchenko of Aurora Labs takes the spotlight to discuss Aurora&#8217;s impactful innovations within the NEAR ecosystem. Expect insights into Aurora’s network developments, Borealis infrastructure, and their cross-contract call SDK, all of which amplify NEAR&#8217;s technological prowess.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-irl-hackathon-grand-finale-and-lx-factory-party">IRL Hackathon grand finale and LX Factory party</h2>



<p>Judgment day is finally here, as winners of the IRL Hackathon will claim their awards on the Main Stage from 2:35 PM &#8211; 3:50 PM. Huge thanks to all who participated and submitted projects. Every hacker, coder, builder, and developer is what makes the NEAR ecosystem special and the NEAR Foundation looks forward to engaging each and every one in the future.</p>



<p>Finally, NEARCON ‘23 is going out with a major bang at one of the most iconic Lisbon party venues — LX Factory. An epic bash brought to you by The Littles, it’s a going away soiree that every NEARCON ‘23 attendee simply can’t miss. Grab a drink, do some networking, and groove your night away as NEARCON ‘23 sails off into the Portuguese sunset. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A few important reminders </h2>



<p>Here are today&#8217;s venue hours:</p>



<ul>
<li>Armazem (Hacker HQ) closes at 12:30 PM. </li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>Garagem (Community HQ) closes at 5:30 immediately after the happy hour. </li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>Convento Do Beato Layer 2 Stage closes at 12:00 PM. The Layer 1 Stage and venue closes at 4:00 PM. </li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>Closing party at LX Factory (Fábrica) from 9:00 PM &#8211; 4:00 AM. Open to badge holders. </li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-shoutout-to-day-three-sponsors">Shoutout to Day Three sponsors</h2>



<p>Of course, this epic Day Three wouldn’t be possible without the support of todays’ generous and amazing sponsors:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>The Littles</strong></li>



<li><strong>SailGP</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Day Three will be all about forging connections, gaining insights, and celebrating all that you and the collective NEAR ecosystem has accomplished not only over the past three days – but the entirety of 2023. So grab a coffee, head on over to the venue, and let’s make the final day of NEARCON ‘23 count towards making this the most iconic edition ever.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-three-shaping-the-future-of-decentralized-governance/">NEARCON ‘23 Day Three: Shaping the Future of Decentralized Governance </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON ‘23 Day 2 Roundup: Web3&#8217;s Women Shine and Innovations Unfold</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-23-day-2-roundup-web3s-women-shine-and-innovations-unfold/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 17:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21075</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As the Lisbon sun dipped below the horizon, NEARCON ‘23&#8217;s second day came to a vibrant conclusion. The day was …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-2-roundup-web3s-women-shine-and-innovations-unfold/">NEARCON ‘23 Day 2 Roundup: Web3&#8217;s Women Shine and Innovations Unfold</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As the Lisbon sun dipped below the horizon, NEARCON ‘23&#8217;s second day came to a vibrant conclusion. The day was marked by a rich tapestry of dialogue and discovery, highlighting the profound impact of women in Web3 and the AI is NEAR track. The energy was palpable as attendees navigated through a day steeped in collaborative exploration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Key announcements from Pyth Network and breakthroughs in identity solutions with idOS and Tangem Wallet underscored a day where the future of blockchain was not just imagined, but actively constructed.</p>



<p>Remember, you can stay connected with other attendees through Calimero Chat — a private, decentralized comms built on the NEAR blockchain.</p>



<p><em>*Note: There is no bag check or cloak room at any NEARCON venue</em>. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-female-open-web-trailblazers-kick-start-day-two">Female open web trailblazers kick start Day Two</h2>



<p>Day 2 of NEARCON ‘23’s celebrated diversity and technical milestones, highlighting transformative initiatives and strategic expansions within the ecosystem.</p>



<p>The &#8220;Women in Web3&#8221; brunch at NEARCON ‘23 spotlighted the vital contributions of women in blockchain, focusing on fostering inclusivity. Leaders in the space convened to discuss strategies for empowering women, emphasizing the NEAR Foundation’s commitment to diversity with initiatives like the Women in Web3 Changemakers list.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ecosystem-highlights-take-center-stage">Ecosystem highlights take center stage</h2>



<p><strong>FractalID unveils idOS on NEAR</strong></p>



<p>FractalID is redefining Web3 identity with the launch of idOS on NEAR, providing users with unparalleled control over their digital identity. This pivotal development promises to enhance user sovereignty and compliance in dApp interactions, bolstering NEAR&#8217;s position as a leader in decentralized identity solutions.</p>



<p><strong>Pyth Network</strong></p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s integration with the Pyth Network brings a wealth of real-time price feeds to its testnet, significantly enhancing the toolkit available to developers. This move, a year after Pyth&#8217;s Aurora integration, demonstrates NEAR&#8217;s dedication to equipping its platform with the data and tools required for leading-edge dApp development.</p>



<p><strong>Octopus Network restaking and IBC bridge</strong></p>



<p>As part of its Octopus 2.0 program, Octopus Network —&nbsp;built on NEAR Protocol —&nbsp;unveils $NEAR restaking for Ottochain launch in December. This initiative enhances validators&#8217; rewards and bolsters appchain security, incentivizing $NEAR&#8217;s wider use and fostering equilibrium in the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<p>Octopus Network also introduced Adaptive IBC, bridging Cosmos and NEAR ecosystems for enhanced interoperability with Secret Network poised to be the first adopter.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Tangem Cold Wallet integrates NEAR Protocol</strong></p>



<p>The Tangem Wallet, renowned for its Swiss-made security and simplicity, now fully supports the NEAR Protocol, ensuring effortless self-custody for NEAR holders. This collaboration embodies NEAR&#8217;s commitment to making Web3 accessible, offering users a secure and straightforward way to manage their digital assets with confidence.</p>



<p><strong>Jump DeFi broadens DeFi accessibility on NEAR</strong></p>



<p>Jump DeFi has extended its decentralized finance platform to Telos, making strides toward widespread DeFi adoption. By integrating with NEAR Protocol, Jump DeFi simplifies user and developer engagement, streamlining access to a previously fragmented DeFi ecosystem with its all-in-one solution for core financial activities.</p>



<p><strong>MotoDEX accelerates on NEAR Blockchain</strong></p>



<p>MotoDEX, integrating with the NEAR blockchain, offers a thrilling motorcycle racing game directly on app stores. It caters to 13,000 daily players, blending the thrill of racing with the perks of blockchain tech. The game&#8217;s seamless Web3 integration ensures accessibility for all, fueling a new era of blockchain gaming.</p>



<p><strong>GeekPay rides high on NEAR Blockchain</strong></p>



<p>GeekPay also announced impressive growth with a $1M turnover, a quarter of which was on NEAR. GeekPay simplifies payroll for businesses like theirs. Its recent accolade includes a nod from the Tenity Incubation Program, affirming GeekPay&#8217;s pivotal role in the gig economy and future of work.</p>



<p><strong>DevHub&#8217;s bold new rebrand</strong></p>



<p>DevHub unveiled a fresh brand identity to resonate with its evolution into a thriving NEAR developer ecosystem. This rebranding is more than a visual facelift — it represents DevHub&#8217;s commitment to fostering innovation and supporting builders at every stage. Dive into the enhanced experience at <a href="https://neardevhub.org/">neardevhub.org</a> and join the ranks shaping the Open Web with NEAR.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-key-sessions-and-panels">Key sessions and panels</h2>



<p><strong>SK Telecom ports into the metaverse</strong></p>



<p>Sehyeon Oh from SK Telecom detailed the Korean company’s strategic foray into the open web, highlighting their collaboration with NEAR Foundation and plans for a Web3 wallet and NFT marketplace. SKT&#8217;s approach aims to fuse digital and tangible realms, from art NFTs to metaverse developments while community building with education and blockchain integration.</p>



<p><strong>FractalID unveils idOS on NEAR&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Julian Leitloff from Fractal ID and Johan Salaï Bondioli of Pagoda introduced the idOS at NEARCON ‘23, a leap forward in Web3 identity, granting users control over their digital presence. This initiative is set to redefine the interaction landscape for dApp users, solidifying NEAR&#8217;s leadership in decentralized identity solutions.</p>



<p><strong>NEAR’s evolution from Nightshade to Starsight</strong></p>



<p>Bowen Wang from Pagoda offered a compelling overview of NEAR Protocol&#8217;s evolution, highlighting the advances in stateless validation and zero-knowledge technologies. Wang teased the upcoming Starsight project, promising a leap forward in blockchain&#8217;s usability, scalability, and decentralization in 2024.</p>



<p><strong>Illia Polosukhin on AI&#8217;s Role in NEAR&#8217;s Future</strong></p>



<p>NEAR co-founder and CEO Illia Polosukhin dove into the future of AI and its integration with blockchain. He emphasized AI&#8217;s potential to drive work and governance on NEAR, forecasting AI agents that execute tasks autonomously, enhancing efficiency within decentralized systems and contributing to the evolution of DAOs into truly autonomous organizations.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-side-events-and-networking">Side events and networking</h2>



<p>As Day Two winds down, don’t forget to head on over to the Community HQ for the Movers and Shakers Happy Hour, sponsored by Glass and Moonbounce. Just a few steps down the cobbled Lisbon streets from HackerHQ, Movers and Shakers will be a great chance to sip some cocktails and learn about Glass, an innovative app bringing the adult beverage closer to brand enthusiasts on the NEAR blockchain.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-looking-ahead-to-day-three">Looking ahead to Day Three</h2>



<p>Day Three of NEARCON ‘23 is your final opportunity to dive into immersive open web sessions starting at 10:45 AM, after doors open at 9 AM. The day will highlight the Hackathon&#8217;s brightest innovations with judging from 12:00 PM and the NEAR Pitch Competition and Hackathon Awards Ceremony from 2:35 PM to 3:50 PM on the Main Stage, showcasing top project pitches.</p>



<p>NEARCON ‘23 then goes out with a massive bang at the Closing Party at the LX Factory, sponsored by The Littles. The bash begins at 9:00 PM, and will be a chance for attendees to unwind, network, and reflect on everything that was NEARCON ‘23. Not to mention dancing the night away in one of Lisbon’s most happening party venues.</p>



<p>We hope you had a fantastic Day Two at NEARCON ‘23, with the best yet to come. Enjoy another buzzing evening in Lisbon and see you on Day Three!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-2-roundup-web3s-women-shine-and-innovations-unfold/">NEARCON ‘23 Day 2 Roundup: Web3&#8217;s Women Shine and Innovations Unfold</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get Ready for [REDACTED] at NEARCON ‘23</title>
		<link>/blog/get-ready-for-redacted-at-nearcon-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 14:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEARCON ‘23 is days away, and we’ve got a slate of exciting announcements and product releases, including ▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆ and ▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆.&#160; …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/get-ready-for-redacted-at-nearcon-23/">Get Ready for [REDACTED] at NEARCON ‘23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEARCON ‘23 is days away, and we’ve got a slate of exciting announcements and product releases, including ▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆ and ▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s take a look at a [HEAVILY REDACTED] teaser of the major upcoming NEAR news.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-november-8th-2-00-pm-gmt-illia-to-announce">November 8th, 2:00 pm GMT — Illia to announce ▆▆▆▆▆▆▆ !!!</h2>



<p>From the Main Stage, NEAR Co-founder Illia Polosukhin will take the stage to announce ▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆. Illia will explain what the ▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆&nbsp; means for Web3 app developers building on NEAR.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-november-9th-2-50-pm-gmt-near-tasks-to-launch-marketplace">November 9th, 2:50 pm GMT — NEAR Tasks to launch ▆▆ Marketplace</h2>



<p>At NEARCON ‘23, NEAR Tasks (formerly Satori), will launch its new ▆▆ Marketplace on NEAR to revolutionize the future of work. NEAR Tasks will redefine ▆▆▆▆▆▆ with ▆▆▆▆-centric innovation.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-november-10th-12-30pm-gmt-illia-to-unveil">November 10th, 12:30pm GMT — Illia to unveil ▆▆▆▆▆▆▆&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Illia will take the stage again on Day 3 for yet another major announcement. He will talk about how NEAR Foundation and ▆▆▆▆▆▆ are teaming up to build and deploy ▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆, which will make it easier for developers to create a more secure, interoperable Web3 ecosystem for an open web.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-november-10th-1-30-pm-gmt-near-foundation-and-to-announce-new-partnership">November 10th, 1:30 pm GMT —&nbsp; NEAR Foundation and ▆▆▆▆▆▆ to announce new partnership</h2>



<p>NEAR Foundation and ▆▆▆▆▆▆ will announce a partnership to build a ▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆, a first of its kind in Web3. The NEAR-▆▆▆▆ solution will power fast and inexpensive ▆▆-▆▆▆ transactions, enabling finality in seconds rather than minutes to days —&nbsp;a major improvement for anyone using ▆▆▆▆▆▆ scaling solutions.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-register-for-nearcon-and-journey-into-the-open-web">Register for NEARCON and journey into the open web</h2>



<p>Want to get firsthand details on Illia’s  ▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆▆ announcement , the unveiling of NEAR Foundation and ▆▆▆▆▆▆’s new collaboration, NEAR Tasks’s  ▆▆ Marketplace, and NEAR Foundation’s new ▆▆▆▆▆▆? Then NEARCON ‘23 is the place to be.</p>



<p>If you still haven’t registered, then head over to the <a href="http://nearcon.org/">NEARCON registration</a> page, and join the NEAR community for an iconic 4-day journey into the open web!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/get-ready-for-redacted-at-nearcon-23/">Get Ready for [REDACTED] at NEARCON ‘23</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON &#8217;23: Developer, Founder, and Creative Talks You Shouldn&#8217;t Miss</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-23-developer-founder-and-creative-talks-you-shouldnt-miss/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 19:39:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creatives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEARCON &#8217;23 in scenic Lisbon, Portugal is your go-to event for everything AI, the open web, and more. Whether you&#8217;re …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-developer-founder-and-creative-talks-you-shouldnt-miss/">NEARCON &#8217;23: Developer, Founder, and Creative Talks You Shouldn&#8217;t Miss</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEARCON &#8217;23 in scenic Lisbon, Portugal is your go-to event for everything AI, the open web, and more. Whether you&#8217;re a developer, entrepreneur, or artist, there&#8217;s a session for you. Web3 regulatory aficionados, we&#8217;ve got you covered too (more on that later).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here’s a rundown of sessions that are a must-see.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-developer-track-build-better-on-near">Developer track: build better on NEAR</h2>



<p><strong>NEAR: The Open Web Stack&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>NEAR co-founder Illia Polosuhin reveals game-changing updates for the NEAR ecosystem. A lot of new and exciting NEAR products and tools are in the works for developers. So, if you’re a dev, you won’t want to miss this talk from Illia.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Why Build Web3 Games&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Hosted by <a href="http://www.playember.com/">PlayEmber’s</a> Hugo Furneaux, this panel dissects the massive potential of gaming on the open web. Learn about player-owned economies and why you should consider NEAR for your next gaming project. An essential session for forward-thinking game developers.</p>



<p><strong>Unlocking NEAR Data&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Data extraction got you puzzled? Pavel Kudinov, senior engineering manager at NEAR, will walk you through using SQL queries on NEAR BigQuery Datasets and the NEAR Query API to build and analyze. This is the toolkit you&#8217;ve been waiting for.</p>



<p><strong>Inside the BUILD Incubator&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Will Russell, Michael Yu, and Max Mizzi from student hackathon league <a href="https://mlh.io/">Major League Hacking</a> take a deep dive into the BUILD Incubator Fellowship. Hear firsthand experiences and gather invaluable insights that could jump-start your open web development journey.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-entrepreneurial-track-jumpstart-your-journey">Entrepreneurial track: jumpstart your journey</h2>



<p><strong>Building Web3 Communities&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>This panel brings together experts from community building collective <a href="http://kryptoseoul.com/">KryptoSeoul</a>, decentralized identity project <a href="https://galxe.com/">Galxe</a>, <a href="https://near.social/mob.near/widget/MyPage?accountId=devgovgigs.near">NEAR DevHub</a>, and Web incubator <a href="https://www.cryptooracle.io/">CryptoOracle Collective</a> to discuss the art of fostering a vibrant, diverse community around any project.</p>



<p><strong>CryptoEconomics 101&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Lisa Jy Tan, CEO of tokenomics consulting firm <a href="https://economicsdesign.com/">Economics Design</a>, dives into the world of cryptoeconomics, helping you understand the fundamentals and real-world applications of economic principles, drivers, and incentives at play in the open web.</p>



<p><strong>Hiring Smart in Web3&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Hiring in the open web is both exciting and fraught with potential landmines. Dan Eskow, founder of specialized Web3 talent agency <a href="https://uptopsearch.com/">Up Top</a>, will share valuable tips on sourcing top talent, effective company branding, and red flags to look out for during the interview process.</p>



<p><strong>Funding Trends in Web3&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>A frontline perspective on open web investment from venture capital firms <a href="https://accomplice.co/">Accomplice VC</a>, <a href="https://acapital.com/">a_capital</a>, <a href="https://rockawayx.com/">RockawayX</a>, and <a href="https://www.genventures.xyz/">Generative Ventures</a>. The expert VC panel will offer insights into funding trends and standout pitch decks to help founders stay ahead of the curve.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-creative-track-redefining-art-marketing-and-gaming">Creative track: redefining art, marketing, and gaming</h2>



<p><strong>Asia&#8217;s Impact on Web3 Gaming&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>This panel explores Asia&#8217;s key role in Web3 gaming, particularly Korea&#8217;s leadership in the space. Hear from Jay Hoonjai Lee, CEO of <a href="https://twitter.com/vrtx_dao">Vortex Gaming DAO,</a> and <a href="https://nearkorea.org/">NEAR Korea Hub’s</a> general manager Scott Lee on what the entire blockchain gaming space can learn from Asia.</p>



<p><strong>Marketing in the Open Web&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Learn how decentralization and the open web is changing marketing and branding from Lex B., co-founder of <a href="https://www.nearstudio.co/">NEAR Studio</a>, a creative agency dedicated to the NEAR ecosystem. Everything you need to know about marketing in the open web, including real-life case studies and successes.</p>



<p><strong>Advertising in Web3&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Anjali Young from <a href="https://www.collab.land/">Collab.Land</a>, an innovative project helping implement token-gated communities, discusses how Web3 is transforming the advertising landscape, allowing for more effective brand-customer engagement and immediate feedback.</p>



<p><strong>The Power of NFTs&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Explore how NFTs are driving decentralized creativity, redefining loyalty, and reshaping cultural norms. Hear from the likes of Wilson Lee, co-founder of blockchain-based carnival app <a href="https://thefunpass.io/">TheFunPass™,</a> and Stipe Plejic, CEO of social NFT marketplace <a href="https://endemic.app/">Endemic</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-nearcon-23-get-in-on-the-action">NEARCON ‘23: get in on the action</h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re passionate about the transformative power of the open web, NEARCON &#8217;23 is a can&#8217;t-miss conference. We&#8217;ve carefully curated speaker tracks and sessions to fuel your imagination and skills, whether you&#8217;re a developer, entrepreneur, or creative mind. And the policy-minded need not fret, there’s a special Regulatory Track chock full of insights about evolving legal frameworks, governance, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With NEAR&#8217;s unique approach — super cheap, super fast, super secure — you&#8217;ll discover how the open web is solving real-world problems today.</p>



<p>So why wait?<a href="https://nearcon.app/nearpad.testnet/widget/Index?tab=register"> Register for NEARCON &#8217;23 now</a> to secure your spot!</p>



<p>Special offers are available for<a href="/blog/%d1%83%d0%bd%d1%96%d0%ba%d0%b0%d0%bb%d1%8c%d0%bd%d0%b0-%d0%bc%d0%be%d0%b6%d0%bb%d0%b8%d0%b2%d1%96%d1%81%d1%82%d1%8c-%d0%b4%d0%bb%d1%8f-%d1%83%d0%ba%d1%80%d0%b0%d1%97%d0%bd%d1%86%d1%96%d0%b2-%d0%b1/?_gl=1%2A1deejbu%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTY4MTY0NTc0NS4xNjk4MTUxODc4%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5ODE1MTg3NC4xLjEuMTY5ODE1MjI2NC4wLjAuMA.."> Ukrainians</a>, students in<a href="/blog/entradas-gratuitas-a-nearcon-23-para-estudiantes-en-espana/?_gl=1%2A1deejbu%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTY4MTY0NTc0NS4xNjk4MTUxODc4%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5ODE1MTg3NC4xLjEuMTY5ODE1MjI2NC4wLjAuMA.."> Spain</a> and<a href="/blog/estudantes-terao-ingressos-gratis-no-nearcon23/?_gl=1%2A1clz06g%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTY4MTY0NTc0NS4xNjk4MTUxODc4%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5ODE1MTg3NC4xLjEuMTY5ODE1MjI2NC4wLjAuMA.."> Portugal</a>, and<a href="/blog/nearcon-irl-hackathon-2023-build-the-open-web/?_gl=1%2A1fu2kk1%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTY4MTY0NTc0NS4xNjk4MTUxODc4%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTY5ODE1MTg3NC4xLjEuMTY5ODE1MjI2NC4wLjAuMA.."> hackathon registrants</a>. Head over to those pages and register for your free NEARCON ‘23 pass!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-developer-founder-and-creative-talks-you-shouldnt-miss/">NEARCON &#8217;23: Developer, Founder, and Creative Talks You Shouldn&#8217;t Miss</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
