<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Case Studies Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/category/case-studies/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/category/case-studies/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 15:35:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Case Studies Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/category/case-studies/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Case Study: Flipside Crypto on Building an Analytics Platform on the BOS</title>
		<link>/blog/case-study-flipside-crypto-on-building-an-analytics-platform-on-the-bos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipside]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-flipside-crypto-on-building-an-analytics-platform-on-the-bos/">Case Study: Flipside Crypto on Building an Analytics Platform on the BOS</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR to effortlessly create and distribute innovative decentralized apps, while helping build a more open web — free from centralized platforms. In these Case Study videos, NEAR Foundation showcases some of these projects.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>In the latest NEAR Foundation Case Study video, we hear Flipside Crypto’s Evan “Captain” Owens and GJ Flannery. Not only is Flipside a team building innovative on-chain data and analytics solutions on NEAR, but they were one of the first ecosystem projects to build on the Blockchain Operating System (BOS).&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this case study video, GJ Flannery (Growth &amp; Community) and Captain Owens (Strategic Partnerships) talk about the platform’s ecosystem of analytics and developers building widgets on the BOS with Flipside’s on-chain data. If you’re a founder or developer looking to hear directly from developers who’ve built on the BOS, then this Flipside Case Study video is not to be missed.&nbsp;</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Case Study: Flipside Crypto on Building an Analytics Platform on the BOS" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JtYnC3dEIeU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-flipside-crypto-on-building-an-analytics-platform-on-the-bos/">Case Study: Flipside Crypto on Building an Analytics Platform on the BOS</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Study: Satori&#8217;s Jeff Bissinger Talks NEAR Tasks for the Gig Economy</title>
		<link>/blog/case-study-satoris-jeff-bissinger-talks-near-tasks-for-the-gig-economy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gig Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Tasks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satori]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20761</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-satoris-jeff-bissinger-talks-near-tasks-for-the-gig-economy/">Case Study: Satori&#8217;s Jeff Bissinger Talks NEAR Tasks for the Gig Economy</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR to effortlessly create and distribute innovative decentralized apps, while helping build a more open web — free from centralized platforms. In these Case Study videos, NEAR Foundation showcases some of these projects.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>In the latest NEAR Foundation Case Study video, we hear from Jeff Bissinger, Product Manager at <a href="https://satori.art/">Satori</a>. As a product team building innovative Web3 solutions, Satori is creating AI integrations that enable people to work with purpose. NEAR Tasks, which launched at Consensus 2023 in Austin, is one of Satori’s latest products.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this case study video, Jeff Bissinger takes viewers on a trip into NEAR Tasks —&nbsp;Satori’s effort to blend the gig economy with blockchain technology. With NEAR Tasks, users can earn $NEAR while completing simple, yet meaningful, AI related tasks.&nbsp;</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Case Study: Satori&#039;s Jeff Bissinger Talks NEAR Tasks for the Gig Economy" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eAzuG-iQw2o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-satoris-jeff-bissinger-talks-near-tasks-for-the-gig-economy/">Case Study: Satori&#8217;s Jeff Bissinger Talks NEAR Tasks for the Gig Economy</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Study: NEAR Foundation&#8217;s Laura Cunningham on the NEAR Horizon Startup Accelerator</title>
		<link>/blog/case-study-near-foundations-laura-cunningham-on-the-near-horizon-startup-accelerator/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Horizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3 Accelerator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20758</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-near-foundations-laura-cunningham-on-the-near-horizon-startup-accelerator/">Case Study: NEAR Foundation&#8217;s Laura Cunningham on the NEAR Horizon Startup Accelerator</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR to effortlessly create and distribute innovative decentralized apps, while helping build a more open web — free from centralized platforms. In these Case Study videos, NEAR Foundation showcases some of these projects.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>In the latest NEAR Foundation Case Study video, viewers hear from Laura Cunningham, Team Lead at NEAR Horizon and General Manager at NEAR Foundation. NEAR Horizon is a Web3 accelerator program revolutionizing how founders and builders receive support in the open web. Laura takes viewers on a deep dive into Horizon’s startup accelerator marketplace, which the Horizon team built on the Blockchain Operating System (BOS). </p>



<p>“The BOS was our platform of choice for building NEAR Horizon because it makes Horizon much more accessible to founders and projects that are already in the ecosystem. And then ones coming in new, you can be building on another chain as long as you have some component of your stack on NEAR then you can apply and be part of NEAR Horizon,  ” she adds. “It is also incredibly composable, so we were able to fork different attributes that were already available on BOS and make use of them in our front end, so it made it a lot quicker to actually develop.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Case Study: NEAR Foundation&#039;s Laura Cunningham on the NEAR Horizon Startup Accelerator" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8R9rtRuk5Vw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-near-foundations-laura-cunningham-on-the-near-horizon-startup-accelerator/">Case Study: NEAR Foundation&#8217;s Laura Cunningham on the NEAR Horizon Startup Accelerator</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Study: Building on the NEAR Blockchain Operating System (BOS)</title>
		<link>/blog/case-study-building-on-the-near-blockchain-operating-system-bos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain Operating System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BOS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-building-on-the-near-blockchain-operating-system-bos/">Case Study: Building on the NEAR Blockchain Operating System (BOS)</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR to effortlessly create and distribute innovative decentralized apps, while helping build a more open web — free from centralized platforms. In these Case Study videos, NEAR Foundation showcases some of these projects. </em></p>



<p>In the latest NEAR Foundation Case Study video, viewers take a deep dive into the <a href="http://near.org/">Blockchain Operating System</a> (BOS). We explore how the BOS, like a decentralized app store, isn’t controlled by any centralized entities. Other topics of conversation include BOS Gateways, the discoverability and composability of BOS apps and components, building on the BOS with Javascript, and integrations with Visual Studio Code and Github. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Case Study: Building on the NEAR Blockchain Operating System (BOS)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lM1DBtkmPMQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-building-on-the-near-blockchain-operating-system-bos/">Case Study: Building on the NEAR Blockchain Operating System (BOS)</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Solaire is Revolutionizing the Fashion Industry with Web3 Technology and Building the Retail Infrastructure on NEAR</title>
		<link>/blog/how-solaire-is-revolutionizing-the-fashion-industry-with-web3-technology-and-building-the-retail-infrastructure-on-near/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 13:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Solaire – an exciting web3 retail platform that merges physical and digital assets – is revolutionizing the way consumers interact …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/how-solaire-is-revolutionizing-the-fashion-industry-with-web3-technology-and-building-the-retail-infrastructure-on-near/">How Solaire is Revolutionizing the Fashion Industry with Web3 Technology and Building the Retail Infrastructure on NEAR</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.thespotroom.com/">Solaire</a> – an exciting web3 retail platform that merges physical and digital assets – is revolutionizing the way consumers interact with fashion brands. By harnessing the power of web3 and the NEAR blockchain, Solaire is building out key protocol infrastructure and APIs that will expand decentralized retail and unlock new opportunities for both shoppers and fashion brands alike.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Solaire is pioneering phygital use cases and brands will be able to leverage the NEAR blockchain in tandem with Solair’s powerful APIs to engage with their audience in novel ways.  Solaire&#8217;s suite of APIs seamlessly integrates with a brand&#8217;s existing retail channels. This enables new revenue channels and richer data. </p>



<p></p>



<p>Solaire’s entire backend is fully on-chain and facilitates an easy-to-use web2 interface, with no wallet or crypto needed from shoppers. The NEAR blockchain helps Solaire provide these benefits for brands, as well as unique integrations with NEAR. This includes Solaire integration with the NEAR Mainnet, native NEAR wallet support, and the NEAR token as a payment option.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-solaire-is-changing-fashion-with-phygital">How Solaire is Changing Fashion with Phygital</h2>



<p>Solaire establishes a 1:1 connection between a physical object and its digital twin. Brands can then leverage Solaire’s infrastructure and suite of APIs to engage customers with NFTs and phygital experiences in a seamless, user-friendly way, removing some of the typical web3 friction points.</p>



<p></p>



<p>“We aim to do all the hard work on the backend so that brands and consumers can enjoy a familiar user experience with all the benefits of Web3 but without the hassle of dealing with wallet or crypto,” says Vivian Zhang, CEO of Solaire. “And NEAR&#8217;s blockchain is perfectly suited to run enterprise-level protocols to ensure a seamless and frictionless user experience.&#8221;</p>



<p></p>



<p>Soliare infrastructure helps brands create meaningful digital twins for physical goods, as well as providing a means for consumers to buy and trade phygital assets. Solaire allows for minting unique NFTs attached to physical goods and offers an end-to-end solution for securing and tracking a product from manufacturing through its entire product lifecycle.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Solaire has already collaborated with major fashion brands like <a href="https://freemanjewelry.com/">Freeman&#8217;s Limited Edition Phygital Harry Potter™</a> Collection and <a href="https://www.ilonasong.com/">Ilona Song</a>. Smart contracts facilitate shipping, returns, and exchanges all on the NEAR blockchain This allows customers to shop and purchase with transparency and confidence.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-benefits-of-phygital-assets-for-fashion-brands">Benefits of Phygital Assets for Fashion Brands</h2>



<p>Phygital assets are a new way for fashion brands to engage consumers, combining the physical and digital worlds to create a more immersive shopping experience. For example, when a customer buys a dress in real life, they also receive a digital wearable. This can be in the form of an AR filter, a digital skin in their favorite game, or to wear in the metaverse.&nbsp;</p>



<p></p>



<p>“Solaire&#8217;s mission is to empower the retail industry with web3 tools to cultivate a more connected and automated ecosystem,” Zhang continues. “With our suite of APIs, brands are able to maximize revenue and gain valuable data from digital assets, facilitate the secondary market, and build community.”</p>



<p></p>



<p>Brands can then use Solaire as a powerful CRM tool. Through the digital twin in customers&#8217; wallets, brands will have a constant open channel of communication with both the primary customer and secondary owners. Smart contracts also automate royalties from secondary selling, giving brands visibility into trading data.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Another exciting feature is the secondary market experience brands can now provide. Solaire’s backend enables peer-to-peer physical asset trading without a middleman, utilizing blockchain-secured data and smart contracts. Buyers and sellers can independently confirm possession and authenticity of assets on-chain, and smart contracts resolve any disputes.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-solaire-and-near-building-a-phygital-fashion-future">Solaire and NEAR Building a Phygital Fashion Future</h2>



<p>&#8220;We’re building on NEAR because it champions community, and it’s one we have found to be incredibly supportive,” remarks Vivian Zhang, CEO of Solaire. “We’ve been able to connect and collaborate with so many partners as we build an entire retail ecosystem together on NEAR.”</p>



<p>As fashion brands recognize the value of web3, NFTs, and phygital technology as important audience touchpoints, Solaire has the potential to partner with even more fashion brands and designers. Solaire’s game-changing approach and tech stack – aided by the NEAR blockchain – will bring web3 to more fashionistas without some of the usual pain points.</p>



<p>“Together with NEAR, we hope to lay out the Web3 infrastructure for the retail industry to onboard the next billion users into web3,&#8221; concluded Zhang. </p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/how-solaire-is-revolutionizing-the-fashion-industry-with-web3-technology-and-building-the-retail-infrastructure-on-near/">How Solaire is Revolutionizing the Fashion Industry with Web3 Technology and Building the Retail Infrastructure on NEAR</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing SeatlabNFT: The Web3 Startup Changing the Ticketing Game </title>
		<link>/blog/introducing-seatlabnft-the-web3-startup-changing-the-ticketing-game/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 09:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18720</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Music, sports, and entertainment ticketing is about to be completely reimagined. SeatlabNFT, an NFT ticketing platform built on the NEAR …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-seatlabnft-the-web3-startup-changing-the-ticketing-game/">Introducing SeatlabNFT: The Web3 Startup Changing the Ticketing Game </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Music, sports, and entertainment ticketing is about to be completely reimagined. <a href="https://www.seatlabnft.com/about">SeatlabNFT</a>, an NFT ticketing platform built on the NEAR blockchain, is bringing fans closer to their favorite artists and sports teams, while also making the ticketing game a lot fairer by reducing scalping and touting.</p>



<p>NFTs in sports and entertainment are becoming more widespread and high-profile. Professional athletes and musicians love flexing their profile pic NFTs these days. But there are more meaningful ways to use NFT technology in the Web3 space. This is precisely SeatlabNFT’s aim: use NFTs and the underlying technology to revolutionize ticketing.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-nfts-can-make-ticketing-fairer">How NFTs can make ticketing fairer</h2>



<p>A major long-standing issue in the ticketing industry is control over the secondary market. Tickets to popular events often sell out in a matter of minutes—often due to scalpers and ticket wholesalers—only to reappear on the secondary market at a significant markup. It’s an unfortunate reality that many music and sports fans have come to accept.</p>



<p>“While various ideas to beat scalpers have been tried in the past, Web2 lacks the tools required to provide genuine control over the secondary market,” wrote Ryan Kenny, CEO of SeatlabNFT, in a <a href="https://www.cityam.com/nft-ticketing-is-inevitable-and-its-more-than-just-a-form-of-access-control/">recent op-ed for City A.M</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The result, in many cases, is that fans are unable to see the performers they love without paying extortionate amounts of money,” he added. “And, with the profit falling into the hands of scalpers, artists miss out on any revenue generated by secondary sales.”</p>



<p>The SeatlabNFT live event and ticketing platform, built on NEAR, has a clear plan to solve those issues. Artists will be able to mint and sell tickets directly to fans on SeatlabNFT, while those who purchase will avoid scalper markups. And unlike buying a ticket in today’s secondary market, NFT technology will ensure that the ticket they buy isn’t fraudulent.</p>



<p>“With the arrival of Web3, there is a huge opportunity to change this dynamic by issuing tickets as NFTs,” wrote Kenny. “NFT technology is a natural fit for ticketing, as it solves many main problems plaguing the event ticketing industry.”</p>



<p>But maintaining fair pricing and putting more revenue into the pockets of creators themselves is just the tip of the iceberg. SeatlabNFT has other ideas for how to use NFTs to change the ticketing landscape.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-creating-more-profound-relationships-with-fans">Creating more profound relationships with fans</h2>



<p>SeatlabNFT has big plans to help artists and teams make the fan experience much more fun, immersive, and bi-directional. Fans and attendees will feel less like consumers being sold an experience, and more like active participants. SeatlabNFT’s NFT platform will open doors and opportunities to increase fan engagement and loyalty.</p>



<p>For starters, artists will be able to create, issue, and sell NFT collectibles associated with various live events. This goes beyond images, as NFTs can also exist on the blockchain in the form of audio recordings, videos, and other forms of digital artwork. These event-associated NFTs could be airdropped on demand, displayed online, or traded with the same smart contracts used to control the secondary market for tickets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Creators can also airdrop event-based NFTs or collectibles using SeatlabNFT smart contracts, rewarding some of the best and most loyal fans who attend live events. For instance, a musical artist could airdrop NFTs to fans who have been to multiple live shows, with their attendance verified by the blockchain. This gives creators the chance to issue everything from digital collectibles to utility NFTs that grant things like discounts on merch, early access to future sales or even unlock on-site perks like access to restricted areas or free food and drink.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ticket royalty splits and price ceilings </h2>



<p>Underpinning all of these NFT ticketing value propositions is SeatlabNFT’s smart contracts that enable royalty splits (on NEAR, royalty splits are baked into smart contracts) and price ceilings. Royalty splits and price ceilings give artists and event organizers the tools they need to fight back against scalping. It allows creators to configure the tickets before they go on sale, and ensures that even on the secondary market, event creators can still capture the value they create.  </p>



<p>With these cutting-edge ticketing efforts, SeatlabNFT is working to create a fairer, more transparent, and equitable playing field for all parties.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-s-next-for-seatlabnft">What’s next for SeatlabNFT</h2>



<p>SeatlabNFT is currently in Phase 2 of its roadmap, with a variety of features and functions already live. The SeatlabNFT app is downloadable on the Apple App Store and Google Play Store, with tickets to various events currently on sale.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The SeatlabNFT membership card available on the app is also a precursor to the <a href="http://www.seatlabnft.com/blog/how-immersive-fan-passes-can-engage-fans-globally">Immersive Fan Pass</a>, an NFT-based fan membership card program exclusively on SeatlabNFT. These passes will be NFTs with various tiered utility and benefits that artists can offer as part of an immersive fan club package. Backstage passes, early access to demo tracks, and artist meet-and-greets are just a few potential ways the Immersive Fan Pass could be used.</p>



<p>SeatlabNFT also just <a href="https://twitter.com/SeatlabNFT/status/1584952941773045763?s=20&amp;t=RLtGCj4N4mDndStMl_byLw">announced</a> a new partnership with Elrow, one of the world’s biggest dance brands. At Elrow’s Dubai festival, scheduled for February 18, 2023 , SeatlabNFT technology will be used for exclusive VIP ticketing and immersive experiences. Elrow Dubai is taking place at D3 Dubai Design District, which can accommodate up to 10,000 people, making it a great opportunity to onboard many new people into both NEAR and Web3.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">VIP tickets for <a href="https://twitter.com/elrow_?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@elrow_</a> Dubai will be available exclusively via SeatlabNFT from 02.11.22 🐙<br><br>This is going to be a unique immersive experience you won’t want to miss… <a href="https://t.co/o8S5DSHuQb">pic.twitter.com/o8S5DSHuQb</a></p>&mdash; SeatlabNFT 🎟️ (@SeatlabNFT) <a href="https://twitter.com/SeatlabNFT/status/1584952941773045763?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 25, 2022</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>The ticketing industry and experience are long overdue for disruption, and SeatlabNFT is well on the way to doing just that. Artists, creators, and sports teams can offer more fair pricing to their fans while receiving a greater share of the revenue via SeatlabNFT’s royalty split smart contracts. And fans get better pricing with the peace of mind that they’re purchasing an authentic ticket.</p>



<p>And even more exciting, integrating NFT technology into the ticketing space opens the door for limitless possibilities in connecting fans with their favorite artists and teams. Linking exclusive digital NFT collectibles and airdrops with tickets is ripe for experimentation, and the Immersive Fan Pass will engage fans on a level never before seen.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-seatlabnft-the-web3-startup-changing-the-ticketing-game/">Introducing SeatlabNFT: The Web3 Startup Changing the Ticketing Game </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inside the Tech: NFT.HipHop Marketplace</title>
		<link>/blog/inside-the-tech-nft-hiphop/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 15:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=12549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The NFT.HipHop marketplace auction of the Hip Hop Heads collection began on Juneteenth and will run for 37 days, until …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inside-the-tech-nft-hiphop/">Inside the Tech: NFT.HipHop Marketplace</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><a href="https://nft.hiphop/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NFT.HipHop</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> marketplace auction of the Hip Hop Heads collection began on Juneteenth and will run for 37 days, until July 25. A celebration of the history of hip hop and its most iconic artists, the pop-up marketplace also highlights some engineering innovations that highlight the advanced NFT developer and user experience on NEAR. NFT.HipHop incorporates seamless NEAR account creation, the ability to purchase NFTs with a credit card, customizable royalty splits that follow NFTs across marketplaces, and the debut of NFTs displaying in the NEAR wallet. </span></p>
<h3>Inside the User Experience</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The NFT.HipHop auction marks a radical change in the way that NFT marketplaces can be executed. The user onboarding flow makes the process universally accessible and as familiar as any Web2 purchasing experience. With this new creative approach, end users with no existing crypto knowledge can easily purchase NFTs without the hurdles of onboarding to an exchange, purchasing cryptocurrency, or choosing and connecting a wallet. Thanks to the app’s wallet faucet and NEAR’s human-rea</span>dable account naming system, all a user has to do is choose a NEAR name and the application handles the rest.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-12737" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inside-nfthiphop-ux.png" alt="" width="1400" height="520" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inside-nfthiphop-ux.png 1400w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inside-nfthiphop-ux-300x111.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inside-nfthiphop-ux-1024x380.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inside-nfthiphop-ux-768x285.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1400px) 100vw, 1400px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marketplace credits for placing NFT bids can be purchased with a credit card. There is no complex, multi-step process of purchasing crypto through an exchan</span>ge and paying high transaction fees as would be required with other NFT marketplaces today. Using crypto can be a confusing process for a novice, but by employing this progressive onboarding flow, the barrier to entry for crypto has been all but eliminated. The goal is to make NFTs accessible to all kinds of hip hop fans, not just crypto-native fans.</p>
<h3>Inside the App</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At its core, the NFT.HipHop marketplace is a standard React application with state management. dApp developers retrieve on-chain state using the NEAR API Helper, which interacts with the NEAR blockchain via CloudFlare. This tool allows caching heavy queries when the user lands on the page, as there are 103 portraits in the Hip Hop Heads collection and 37 available editions of each Head. As the user explores the marketplace, they’re only viewing one basic type of NFT. The canonical tokens, or “gem tokens,” are stored, and individual edition bids and sales are visible to the user within each gem. When clicking on an individual token, one sees which editions are for sale and the bidding history is pulled from the marketplace contract.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the user is ready to bid on an NFT, a React component handles the flow of creating a NEAR account; if you already have a NEAR Wallet, you go straight to buying credits. Then the user gets a prompt to add “credits” to their account using </span><a href="https://stripe.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stripe</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This happens through a custom-built </span><a href="https://github.com/mehtaphysical/stripe-pay-sandbox"><span style="font-weight: 400;">stripe-payment-sandbox</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which converts fiat into credits that are actually native fungible tokens usable only on the NFT.HipHop app. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This Stripe payment fiat onramp is accomplished by wrapping the fungible token standard with a </span><a href="https://github.com/mehtaphysical/stripe-pay-sandbox/blob/main/contract/src/lib.rs#L197-L221"><span style="font-weight: 400;">custom API</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to ensure that only transfers to the marketplace or started by the marketplace are possible, in addition to tracking Stripe charges used to mint the tokens. The latter makes it possible to automate refunds when the auction concludes. The standard contract methods are wrapped so that an “assertion” can be added, verifying that transfer requests involve the marketplace. If the assertion fails, the smart contract will “panic,” displaying an alert indicating that “only transfers from the marketplace are allowed.”</span></p>
<h3>Inside NFT Royalties on NEAR</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nearly all of the backend accounting is done transparently on the blockchain and is visible on </span><a href="https://explorer.nearpages.wpengine.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR Explorer</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, allowing for transparency paired with a real ability to illustrate the flow of funds. Using the </span><a href="https://nomicon.io/Standards/NonFungibleToken/Payout.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Standard for a Multiple-Recipient-Payout mechanic on NFT Contracts</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, royalties on NEAR follow the NFTs in perpetuity. This allows for royalty enforcement across different marketplaces and applies to secondary sales. A user could have an NFT in their NEAR wallet and go to a different marketplace on NEAR, such as </span><a href="https://paras.id/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Paras</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or </span><a href="https://www.mintbase.io/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mintbase</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, for a potential resale. With the royalties embedded in the actual NFT token, they must be respected in order to complete the transfer of that NFT. Completely customizable, royalties can be split between multiple contributors, beneficiaries, and even DAOs. This standard is the first of its kind and a key differentiator for NFT developers, artists, and users alike.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the 36-day marketplace draws to a close, every auction winner will see their NFT displayed in their NEAR wallet––in fact, all NEAR NFTs from any marketplace are displayed in a collectibles tab in the wallet. Like art hanging on a gallery wall or in your home, the user’s collection is accessible within a few clicks, and not just within an individual marketplace. </span></p>
<h3>Inspired? Start Building!</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Supporting documentation and open source repositories for building NFT marketplaces on NEAR are available to all. Any developer can utilize the concepts in this marketplace and model their dApps on this construct or remix different elements as part of a new idea. Head over to </span><a href="http://nft.hiphop/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NFT.HipHop</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to see how NEAR’s seamless and easy tech can empower builders to create accessible, delightful user experiences.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inside-the-tech-nft-hiphop/">Inside the Tech: NFT.HipHop Marketplace</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How blockchain will save the Creator Economy</title>
		<link>/blog/how-blockchain-will-save-the-creator-economy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 16:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=12505</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Why NFTs, DAOs and Open Finance will change the world for artists and their communities. Creators are Innovators Creative industries …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/how-blockchain-will-save-the-creator-economy/">How blockchain will save the Creator Economy</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Why NFTs, DAOs and Open Finance will change the world for artists and their communities.</em></strong></p>
<h2>Creators are Innovators</h2>
<p>Creative industries have always led innovation because they’re fundamentally exploratory and hungry for ways to help create sustainably.</p>
<p>Hip Hop, for example, pushed the envelope in almost every possible way during its ascent from the streets to becoming the dominant form of music in the world.  DJ Kool Herc, its commonly acknowledged progenitor, birthed a new art form when he extended dance-friendly breaks by combining multiple records across turntables in the ‘70s and others in the industry have driven innovation ever since.</p>
<p>Just like that first technological experimentation to make better dance parties in the Bronx started a revolution in music production, today we’re seeing the emergence of a new set of tools with the same power to enable artists to engage their fans and change the world.</p>
<p>In this post, I’ll walk through some of the problems that creators and communities face today and how a new blockchain-enabled toolkit will make them more aligned, engaged and sustainable.</p>
<h2>The Creator Economy</h2>
<p>The advent of the Internet in the late ’90s ushered in an era where people around the world could both create and consume much more easily than ever before. You can do more with a Macbook today than a whole studio could 20 years ago.</p>
<p>It also became substantially easier to find communities of common interest regardless of geography, and a larger portion of all our lives migrated into the digital realm. New hardware and software tools made it much easier to produce content &#8212; whether multi-platinum albums or simply micro-niche blog posts &#8212; while the web’s scale made it much easier to distribute this content.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the boom in creation and the massive expansion of platforms to support large fanbases wasn’t matched by a similar boom in the sustainability of creators. In fact, while the increased size of audiences allowed top creators to reach a grander scale, the infinite replication of content and the power of distributors as middlemen made it more difficult for most other creators to benefit from their intellectual property (“IP”).</p>
<p>The relationship between creators and their communities drives the so-called Creator Economy, which is a dynamic between 3 factors:</p>
<ol>
<li><b>Creators</b> who produce something of value</li>
<li><b>Communities</b> who support these creators</li>
<li><b>Financial tools</b> and platforms to help make creators and their communities sustainable</li>
</ol>
<p>The line between creators and communities can be blurry, for example when users generate content, but ultimately someone has to pay for something in order to create a sustainable economy.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-12558" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_simple-1.png" alt="" width="2160" height="2016" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_simple-1.png 2160w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_simple-1-300x280.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_simple-1-1024x956.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_simple-1-768x717.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_simple-1-1536x1434.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_simple-1-2048x1911.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2160px) 100vw, 2160px" /></p>
<p>Today, this economy is generally a one-way path where the creator produces something (eg an album), gets fans to consume it (typically losing most of the proceeds to the middlemen who control their relationship with fans) and tries to earn real income from secondary revenue streams like concerts or merchandise or sponsorships. This system is rife with problems and it’s only sustainable for creators with enormous or highly engaged fan bases, particularly if they’ve given away their IP rights along the way. This leaves the so-called “long tail” of smaller creators underserved and makes things tough even for the larger ones due to all the middlemen who have their hands in the pie.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>What’s Changing Today</h2>
<p>So how do we make the creator economy more sustainable for everyone?</p>
<p>It requires improving the underlying technology of the web to unlock new tools for both creators and their communities to build stronger, more sustainable bonds.  Specifically, it means merging the technological revolution which started with Bitcoin in 2008 with today’s Internet to create new tools like NFTs, DAOs, Fungible Tokens and Open Finance (“defi”).</p>
<p>Here’s how it all fits together.</p>
<p>If you go back to the Creator Economy Triangle from before, each corner has needs that weren’t met before:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Creators</b> haven’t been able to sustainably benefit from their IP because of the commodification of content in the digital world which devalues their creativity and which leaves them at the mercy of their distribution partners and the platforms holding their fanbases.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Communities</b> haven’t been able to effectively self-organize outside of existing social platforms, make themselves sustainable or align their interests with those of the creators they support.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Financial tooling</b> has limited the economy itself to one-time or recurring payments for goods or services because the tooling has been anchored in a world of bank accounts and Paypal-like providers. Royalty schemes and payments are also notoriously arcane, inconsistent and exploitative to creators.</li>
</ul>
<p>In 2021, blockchain technology has finally arrived at the point where it can solve all three of these issues and unblock the Creator Economy.</p>
<p>This is because each of the key aspects of the Creator Economy is served by a specific set of tools which weren’t possible to combine like this before a platform like NEAR was available.  This gives us a new Creator Economy Triangle, which shows how these tools &#8212; NFTs, DAOs, Fungible Tokens and Open Finance (“defi”) &#8212; interact:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-12559" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_new.png" alt="" width="2160" height="2016" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_new.png 2160w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_new-300x280.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_new-1024x956.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_new-768x717.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_new-1536x1434.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/creator-economy_new-2048x1911.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2160px) 100vw, 2160px" /></p>
<p>At a high level, it breaks down like this:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>NFTs</b> are basically digital containers which can hold IP but which liberated it to be owned and traded so <b>creators</b> have a world of new ways to produce, distribute, remix and monetize content.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>DAOs</b> are basically like shared bank accounts for <b>communities</b> which are entirely digital so it’s really easy for communities to act almost like official co-ops or companies and build sustainable models for themselves. They can issue <b>fungible tokens</b> which are basically membership cards with a lot more potential superpowers to drive more engagement.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Open (“decentralized”) Finance</b> is a whole toolkit which allows creators, communities, NFTs, DAOs, fungible tokens and all the other pieces of the digital economy to plug into each other in ways that no one has ever done before, allowing entirely new ways of earning income for creators or benefitting from the upside of membership for community members.</li>
</ul>
<p>Let’s look a little deeper into each of these pieces and why they’re so powerful to help creators.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>NFTs: Tools for Creators</h2>
<p>NFTs are understandably confusing for many people, so I’ll break it down in plain English.</p>
<p>The most important concept in NFTs is that, after decades of infinitely sharing creative output on the Internet, we finally have <i>digital scarcity.</i> That means that we can finally prove that a particular file or piece of content or piece of data is uniquely owned by a single person.</p>
<div class="text-12 md:text-14 text-gray w-100 md:w-1/3 p-20 my-20 md:m-30" style="background:#f7f6f1; display: inline; float: right; border-left: 4px solid #f4efe7;">&gt; <strong>Aside: Bitcoin to NFTs</strong></p>
<p>All digital tokens, including NFTs, are based on the same principle as Bitcoin because it uses the same type of technology &#8212; “blockchain.” What the creator of Bitcoin figured out is that, if we create a globally shared ledger that records the owner of every single bitcoin in the world, we can always know exactly how many Bitcoin there are in the world and make sure no one is spending them twice.</p>
<p>If you ever hosted a website on Geocities back in the day and watched it get lost forever because their platform shut down, you understand the value of protecting your important assets from deletion.  What Bitcoin figured out is that you can essentially share the hosting of this ledger among thousands of people around the world so, unlike Geocities, it can never get deleted just because one of them got shut down.</p>
<p>So, fundamentally, an NFT is just like a Bitcoin &#8212; it’s a unique piece of data that everyone in the world agrees is owned by, say, Joe Smith because thousands of people are running the NEAR network together and agree on it. What’s different is that NFTs are much more advanced than Bitcoins.</p>
<p>A bitcoin is really pretty boring &#8212; I can show you that I own one, I can send it to my friend to pay for something and I can do a few more simple operations with it. An NFT, because it’s built on a much more advanced network, is basically an empty container that can hold any type of data AND you can program it to do anything just like software.</p></div>
<h3>Why NFTs are so powerful</h3>
<p>Here’s why that’s so useful for artists, using a simple example. Let’s say an artist has created a piece of digital artwork.  In today’s world, those rights are usually stored in the server of some record label somewhere and backed up by a paper signature on some lawyer’s document or, if the creator is independent, it’s at least protected by copyright law so the artist just owns it. Every time the artist allows someone to use it (officially), they or their manager have to explicitly allow it to happen with some sort of signature, which really slows things down and limits how it can be used.</p>
<p>If the artist assigns the IP rights to an NFT, that NFT becomes like a bearer-bond because whoever holds it can now use the legal right. In the simplest case, that person can display it on their digital wall just like a piece of art in the real world and they can know that it’s truly *theirs* to display. But, unlike a painting in the real world which can be bought or sold in a smoke-filled room somewhere and the artist never knows, NFTs are digital objects that can be programmed to do <i>anything</i> and you can always know where they are.</p>
<p>In the physical world, the artist makes revenue from selling an original edition and maybe the rights to produce more. When these things are resold, the artist never knows about it and never earns any income from it.  Because NFTs are digital objects that live on the NEAR blockchain, every time they are bought and sold, the artist can be notified and paid a commission. <i>Every time, in every location.</i> Not just that, but the NFT can be programmed to permanently split that revenue however you want &#8212; maybe 10% goes to the artist, 5% to the agency which helped create it, 4% to the artist’s union and 1% to a charity they support. Maybe 5% gets split among everyone who previously owned this NFT so they are incentivized to help it retain value. <i>Anything is possible.</i></p>
<p>That’s not even the best part.</p>
<p>Because NFTs can send cash back to the artist automatically when they’re traded, they can be traded <i>anywhere.</i> Before today, digital items were stuck in centralized marketplaces because that was the only way that companies could pull revenue from their resales.  For example, digital skins which are created and traded in the Fortnite ecosystem need to be purchased on Fortnite’s proprietary platform so they can get their cut.  But now that the NFT itself will always send the money back home, it can be traded <i>anywhere</i> and the artist or original IP holder will always get paid.</p>
<p>Let me ask you &#8212; back when you were a kid and traded collectibles, did you do so on some official company marketplace or unofficially among your friends? Exactly. Now, everyone from artists to big IP-holding companies are incentivized to set their NFTs free so people can trade them anywhere in the world.  Suddenly, everyone’s interests are aligned to set the art free! This will result in orders of magnitude more transactions. More trading.</p>
<p>Because NFTs are infinitely programmable, <i>we don’t even know yet</i> all the cool ways they can be used.  It’s possible to use NFTs as membership cards which give people access to special events. The artwork becomes more than just a thing to display or a cash flow, they become a special designation of <i>status</i> that the artist <i>or anyone else</i> can use to give special privileges to the holder of. What else might be possible?</p>
<h2>DAOs and FTs: Tools for Communities</h2>
<p>A “DAO” is a decentralized autonomous organization–– which uses an admittedly clunky acronym to represent a formalized community that can self-govern and take on some aspects of a company.</p>
<p>Everyone who uses the blockchain gets a NEAR account.  It’s sort of like a Facebook or Google or bank account except that, just like NFTs, it’s permanent because it lives on NEAR’s “forever network” and it’s not associated with any particular company.  It’s 100% yours and you can call it whatever you want &#8211; for example by naming it after your Twitter or Insta handle (I see you `machoman99`).  This account can store your tokens, your NFTs or pretty much anything else you do on the platform.</p>
<p>A DAO is basically just a more advanced account which can be shared between a group of people.  In this way, it’s similar to a bank account but it doesn’t actually need a bank.</p>
<h3>Why DAOs are so powerful</h3>
<p>DAOs are useful because they can do anything an individual user can but they can also represent <i>all of the users who are their members</i>. In the simplest example, you can store a bunch of tokens in a DAO and the group of users in the community can vote to send them to different places.  Let’s use the example of a fanclub DAO we’ll call `dj_blokk_fanclub`, where fans of that artist pool funds to buy VIP tickets for a show and raffle them off. Because the community exists on a permanent platform like NEAR, it isn’t lost if Facebook or Snap suddenly become less popular.</p>
<p>This example is simple but bear with me. Just like NFTs, DAOs are a basic tool that quickly gets extremely powerful.</p>
<p>For example, a community can issue a token (it’s called a “Fungible Token” aka “FT”) and use that token to determine what kind of privileges their members get.  For example, let’s say our DAO issues 10,000 `$BLOKK` tokens to split among the fanclub’s early members and then automatically creates another 10,000 each year that can be distributed to new members, really helpful members who help the group govern itself, or people who refer new members.  And let’s say members need to hold 10 `$BLOKK` tokens to join the VIP Discord server.  This incentivizes community members to be extra engaged and helpful.</p>
<p>Or maybe the community’s DAO issues the same 10,000 `$BLOKK` tokens but gives 1,000 to the actual DJ Blokk in appreciation and DJ Blokk gives special VIP show access to anyone who holds more than 100 `$BLOKK` tokens.  This is important because now the creator and the community are beginning to directly align themselves.  And the token suddenly has value as well.</p>
<p>Finally, it gets magical when we combine the DAO with NFTs. Let’s say DJ Blokk is putting together a new single and wants to fund it from within the community.  The artist can sell `$BLOKK` tokens and, in exchange, issue an NFT that sends some of its royalty stream back to the community’s DAO.</p>
<p>Suddenly, you’ve unlocked:</p>
<ol>
<li>A way for communities to be platform independent and distribute funds</li>
<li>A crowdfunding mechanism for artists</li>
<li>A way for community members to be financially aligned with making the artists they support successful, creating extremely high engagement and virality.</li>
</ol>
<p>As with NFTs, <i>we still don’t know all the ways you can use DAOs</i> to support creators and communities but just these few are enough to break existing industry models.</p>
<h2>Decentralized Finance: Making it Sustainable</h2>
<p>Creators usually only think about payments when they’re broken.  “Can people in [insert country] buy my merch? Great.”  As a quick review, we’ve already introduced some new NEAR-powerd financial tools &#8212;</p>
<ol>
<li>NFTs can be programmed to send royalties anywhere when they are traded</li>
<li>DAOs give communities the ability to send payments and issue tokens without a traditional bank account</li>
</ol>
<p>As before, let’s explore what’s possible by building up from the simple stuff.</p>
<p>For starters, our creator’s NFTs or our community’s `$BLOKK` token need to be bought and sold somehow.  Consumers need to easily click an Instagram link to purchase the initial NFT, buy it on a marketplace somewhere or get their hands on `$BLOKK` tokens so they can get in the VIP club. This is all straightforward stuff that can be done with familiar credit card processing on NEAR.</p>
<p>Things get more interesting when you consider what people might do when they are holding their new NFT or `$BLOKK` token in their accounts.  Before today, if I bought a collectible online or received it for attending a concert, it would just sit in my account on that one single platform or scattered across multiple independent platforms which don’t communicate with each other.</p>
<p>Today, getting those collectibles is just the beginning.  For example, a community of fans may decide to set up a DAO for themselves which purchases very rare NFTs. These NFTs can then be used as collateral in automated lending platforms to borrow more money to participate in future sales that might only be open to the holders of those NFTs.  The community DAO could even issue their own tokens so small pieces of the portfolio can be easily traded and people around the world can participate. All of this is part of a stable, global financial system which has previously only been accessible to the wealthier countries.</p>
<p>Essentially, assets that were created in the digital world have access to the entire suite of sophisticated financial tools that historically were only available to wealthy investors.  Because of this, there are markets around the world for each of these tokens and NFTs which makes them much more liquid and thus more desirable to hold.  It’s hard to sell a Picasso, but much easier to sell tiny portions of NFTs from the DAO above.</p>
<p>More simply, holders of these collectibles can buy, sell, trade or combine them with others to access real world benefits, play in digital games, or otherwise engage more deeply with their creators.</p>
<p>If you’re lost in the financial language, the key takeaway is this &#8212; NFTs issued by artists typically benefit most when they are frequently traded and the new decentralized financial toolkit makes this extremely easy compared to the way it works in the traditional world.</p>
<p>But, as with NFTs and DAOs, <i>we still haven’t even figured out all the ways this technology can be used.</i>  Luckily, it’s easier to remix these tools than it ever has been. A developer in a single weekend can now build sophisticated financial products that securely handle these assets and their cash flows, which normally would take a team of developers with millions of dollars in venture capital months to put together. This means that the speed of innovation is finally moving at the pace of creativity so artists can get directly involved in the creation, building, remixing and experimentation of new tools that produce new art, engage fans and generate novel revenue streams.</p>
<h2>Tying it all Together</h2>
<p>Where are we now and where is the ball going?</p>
<p>While blockchains have been around since Bitcoin arrived in 2008 and many of the core ideas &#8212; NFTs, DAOs, Fungible Tokens and Defi &#8212; have been in experimentation on Ethereum since 2016, NEAR’s launch late last year was the first time a platform came to life which could <i>make these tools accessible to everyday creators, communities and fans</i>.</p>
<p>A lot of the financial tooling of Defi was built and tested on Ethereum, particularly during mid-2020, but remains prohibitively expensive and complicated for most people to use.</p>
<p>NFTs had a moment in late 2020 and early 2021 when a bunch of artists started making eye-popping sales and big companies started playing with gamification but these experiences were incomplete because they either couldn’t be accessed by everyday people due to cost and and usability concerns or they were part of wholly owned “walled gardens” which leave the assets isolated.</p>
<p>DAOs are just starting to pick up momentum because, until now, there hasn’t been a way to make them useful to consumers due to cost and usability concerns. Now that this final piece has been solved on NEAR, DAOs will finally be able to serve communities as they were meant to.</p>
<p>So, the tech has finally arrived to use these tools but we’re still in the explore-and-mix phase. It’s like the first time DJ Kool Herc kept that break beat going between two records &#8212; we just had the major “aha!” moment and now it’s up to the creators and communities of the world to take these tools and get this party started.</p>
<p>&#8230;and, if you’re ready to do so, reach out!</p>
<p>For creators or IP holders with massive fanbases, reach out to <a href="mailto:bd@near.org">bd@near.org</a> to see how this can be transformed into an engaging, repeated revenue stream. For community leaders interested in upleveling their community engagement and sustainability, reach out to <a href="mailto:community@near.org">community@near.org</a>. Finally, if you’re a developer who wants to hack on this stuff, check out https://docs.near.org/ and the free 5-day bootcamp at <a href="https://learnnear.club/certified-near-developer-application/">https://learnnear.club/certified-near-developer-application/</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/how-blockchain-will-save-the-creator-economy/">How blockchain will save the Creator Economy</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NFT Marketplace for Hip Hop Heads Launches on NEAR</title>
		<link>/blog/nft-marketplace-for-hip-hop-heads-launches-on-near/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 16:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=11957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hey NEAR and Hip Hop Heads! Get ready for our first consumer-facing NFT pop-up shop! This project sprang from the …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nft-marketplace-for-hip-hop-heads-launches-on-near/">NFT Marketplace for Hip Hop Heads Launches on NEAR</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Hey NEAR and Hip Hop Heads!</h3>
<p>Get ready for our first consumer-facing NFT pop-up shop! This project sprang from the mind of Ed Young, one of the co-founders of the bible of hip-hop: <i>The Source Magazine</i>. He had this crazy idea, our team thought it was rad, and so we built it with him. What did we build? An epic collection of hip hop icons that you can own: <strong>Hip Hop Heads.</strong></p>
<p>The Hip Hop Heads First Edition NFT Collection is a tribute to the history and culture of hip hop, 47 years after its inception in the Bronx, New York City. The collection features 103 animated portraits of famous figures from Hip Hop created by André LeRoy Davis for “The Last Word” feature of <i>The Source </i>over the last few decades.</p>
<p>The marketplace auction is officially live! Check out the entire collection at <strong><a href="http://nft.hiphop/">nft.hiphop</a></strong>. Every day from now, Juneteenth, until July 25, one new edition of each Hip-Hop Head will be added to the auction. Each Hip-Hop Head will start with a reserve price and the current bid is bonded with the item until it is outbid or the auction closes. If a bid is returned, fans can immediately use the returned credits to bid again.</p>
<p>Here’s the best part: cash rules everything around me. Fans can purchase these NFTs with a credit card. The marketplace offers an easier way to buy NFTs than ever before: no complicated onboarding, no passing through an exchange, just a simple, familiar purchasing experience made possible on NEAR. Check out the auction flow in the graphic below. And at the end of the auction on day 37, each winning buyer’s NFTs will display right in their NEAR wallet. Boom. It’s radical.</p>
<p><a href="http://nft.hiphop/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="my-30 aligncenter size-full wp-image-11962" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hiphop-howto-fb.png" alt="" width="1200" height="630" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hiphop-howto-fb.png 1200w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hiphop-howto-fb-300x158.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hiphop-howto-fb-1024x538.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hiphop-howto-fb-768x403.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a></p>
<p>Another cool part: NFT royalties on NEAR are written right into the NFT code, which means that any secondary sales will automatically distribute royalties back to the creators, even if the NFT moves into different marketplaces. This is uniquely possible on NEAR thanks to the protocol’s contract-level NFT standard. On-chain, programmable royalties at the smart contract level put creative and financial power back in the hands of artists, and when you buy a NEAR NFT, you can be certain that the creators you love will continue to benefit from their work. A percentage of the royalties from the Hip Hop Heads NFT auctions and secondary sales will be gifted in perpetuity to the artists depicted or to their estates by Ed Young and André LeRoy Davis.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nfthiphop-infographic.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="my-30 aligncenter size-full wp-image-12030" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nfthiphop-infographic.png" alt="" width="1400" height="900" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nfthiphop-infographic.png 1400w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nfthiphop-infographic-300x193.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nfthiphop-infographic-1024x658.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nfthiphop-infographic-768x494.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1400px) 100vw, 1400px" /></a></p>
<p>I’m so pumped to announce this launch. This carries a lot of personal weight for me. I remember the very first time I listened to “Enter the Wu-Tang (36 Chambers).” Hip hop never let me go after that. It’s funny in some ways; imagine an angsty, small-town white kid, chasing his older brother and his surfer punk friends to the beach and singing every word to “C.R.E.A.M.” But in other ways, this was destined to happen because of the work of Ed Young at <em>The Source</em>. Hip hop has been a force pushing culture for almost 50 years, and now it is bridging into what’s been a somewhat fringe technology for the last five. This remix of crypto and hip hop is the first of what I’m sure will be many: a brand-new blend of culture and technology is now becoming possible.</p>
<p>We built this for people – fans – who know the feeling. Hip hop is so much more than music, and if you want to truly own a piece of its history, you should get on this! Try it out, start bidding, and let us know what you think. You only have 36 chambers…I mean days.</p>
<p><a class="btn bg-red my-20" href="http://nft.hiphop/">Bid on your favorite Hip Hop Head at NFT.hiphop!</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nft-marketplace-for-hip-hop-heads-launches-on-near/">NFT Marketplace for Hip Hop Heads Launches on NEAR</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Toward a Better Planet:Green NFTs</title>
		<link>/blog/toward-a-better-planet-green-nfts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 19:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=11340</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After the boom of decentralized finance in 2020, the blockchain industry has turned its attention to NFTs. Artists, celebrities, and …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/toward-a-better-planet-green-nfts/">Toward a Better Planet:&lt;br&gt;Green NFTs</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After the boom of decentralized finance in 2020, the blockchain industry has turned its attention to NFTs. Artists, celebrities, and blockchain enthusiasts alike are minting, buying, and selling NFTs. But NFTs aren’t without controversy. Many people are against them because:</p>
<ul>
<li>Minting an NFT costs so much <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/g/gas-ethereum.asp">gas</a> it becomes unviable for smaller artists.</li>
<li>NFTs run on technology that has a <a href="https://digiconomist.net/ethereum-energy-consumption">large, negative impact</a> on the environment.</li>
</ul>
<p>These are concerns that can both be addressed. The NEAR Foundation is excited to announce <b>Green NFTs</b>, a project where several environmentally conscious artists create art that will be put up for sale in a <a href="https://www.southpole.com/projects">South Pole</a> store on <a href="https://www.mintbase.io/">Mintbase</a>. Half of the proceeds from these artworks will go to the artist and the other half will go to a selection of certified climate action projects developed by South Pole, an award-winning project developer.</p>
<p><a class="btn my-20" href="https://www.mintbase.io/store/greennfts.mintbase1.near">View the Green NFT Project on Mintbase</a></p>
<p>South Pole projects range from protecting a strategic wildlife corridor in Zimbabwe and empowering local communities to generating renewable energy and helping create the circular economy with efficient waste disposal. While cutting carbon is the science underpinning their projects, building a socially just world is at the heart of what they do.</p>
<p><i>“We need to think about our impact on nature and take decisions that offset our impact. There aren’t that many crypto-art initiatives that are ethical and green, but NEAR and Mintbase fit the bill.” – </i><a href="https://linktr.ee/BarbaraTosti"><i>Barbara Tosti</i></a><i>, artist</i></p>
<h3>Collaborating For the Greater Good</h3>
<p>Because <a href="/how-mintbase-made-minting-nfts-cheaper-faster-scalable-and-secure-with-near/">Mintbase is built on NEAR</a>, creating a store and minting NFTs is affordable, fast, and scalable. Anyone can mint NFTs and sell them for whatever price they want, even if that’s less than ten dollars. Previously, gas fees would have made that economically unviable, but NFTs shouldn’t be a rich people’s game.</p>
<p>That’s not all. Artist collaborations have become much easier, because Mintbase allows anyone to easily split both the revenue and royalties of a piece of art. All you need to do is define who gets what percentage. The smart contract will do the rest. Consider how this encourages novelists to write a book together, musicians to compose music together, and artists to work together with climate organizations for the greater good.</p>
<h3>Built on Carbon-Neutral Technology</h3>
<p>Green NFTs are only possible because the underlying infrastructure is carbon-neutral. The NEAR Foundation has been working together with South Pole to measure and offset its carbon footprint, and South Pole recently awarded the NEAR protocol its <a href="/blog/near-climate-neutral-product/">climate-neutral product label</a>.</p>
<p>NEAR purchased carbon offsets from South Pole&#8217;s certified climate action projects to compensate for all direct and indirect emissions associated with the blockchain. Importantly, the NEAR protocol uses a <a href="/technology/">proof-of-stake consensus mechanism</a> instead of a proof-of-work consensus mechanism, which means that the NEAR protocol’s carbon emissions only amount to a fraction of any proof-of-work blockchain.</p>
<p>Measuring the carbon footprint of any blockchain is still a new field with many gray areas. Developments and changes to current methodologies can be expected as the field develops over time. But it’s important to start measuring today and iterate until we get it right instead of waiting for the perfect solution.</p>
<p><i>“The environment should be at the core of any technological product. I lost interest in crypto-art when I learned about its environmental impact, but NEAR is on the right path to dealing with this problem.” – </i><a href="https://www.instagram.com/rccrdtrrs/"><i>Riccardo Torresi</i></a><i>, artist</i></p>
<h3>A Step in the Right Direction</h3>
<p>NFTs needn’t be expensive to create and they needn’t be bad for the climate. Instead, when the infrastructure is clean and when the incentives are aligned properly, they can be a force for good. Linking NFT art and their proceeds to real projects with measurable climate benefits can nudge NFT creators and buyers toward valuable social and environmental causes.</p>
<p>The Green NFT project is one of the first examples of how this can be made possible. We believe it’s a step in the right direction, and hope to see many other projects contributing in similar ways for the greater good in the NEAR future. Keep your eyes out on our social media channels for an announcement on where you’ll be able to see and buy art from the Green NFT project.</p>
<p><i>“Nobody is without sin when it comes to their carbon footprint. But, while I don’t think anybody can be perfect, you can try to make better individual choices, particularly when the right solutions are already out there.” – </i><a href="https://www.zeitwarp.com/"><i>Zeitwarp</i></a><i>, artist</i></p>
<p><a class="btn my-20" href="https://www.mintbase.io/store/greennfts.mintbase1.near">View the Green NFT Project on Mintbase</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-11358 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/forest.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/forest.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/forest-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/06/forest-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>As well as storing carbon, forests provide innumerable benefits to humans and wildlife alike. This picture shows a sunset over the Kariba Forest Protection project. <i> | Credit: South Pole</i></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/toward-a-better-planet-green-nfts/">Toward a Better Planet:&lt;br&gt;Green NFTs</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
