<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Loyalty Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/loyalty/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/loyalty/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 16:23:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Loyalty Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/loyalty/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How GLASS is Uncorking Adult Beverage Loyalty with Web3 and NEAR </title>
		<link>/blog/how-glass-is-uncorking-adult-beverage-loyalty-with-web3-and-near/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GLASS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loyalty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rewards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>GLASS, the world&#8217;s first compliant Web3 community and loyalty platform for the $1.6 trillion alcohol industry, is deploying on the …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/how-glass-is-uncorking-adult-beverage-loyalty-with-web3-and-near/">How GLASS is Uncorking Adult Beverage Loyalty with Web3 and NEAR </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.glass.fun/brands">GLASS</a>, the world&#8217;s first compliant Web3 community and loyalty platform for the $1.6 trillion alcohol industry, is deploying on the NEAR blockchain to engage social drinkers. Founded by Zoe Leavitt, who formerly led early-stage social and entertainment investing for the VC arm of AB InBev, the world’s largest beer company, and serial blockchain entrepreneur and compliance tech expert Calvin Pak, GLASS redefines the ways alcohol brands connect with consumers during social occasions.</p>



<p>GLASS’s compliance infrastructure allows wine, beer, and spirits brands to directly engage social drinkers, introducing groundbreaking innovation to an industry navigating strict legal restrictions when it comes to sales and marketing.</p>



<p>Rather than spending seven million dollars on a 30-second Super Bowl ad spot, what if alcohol brands could send drinks directly to over four hundred thousand fan watch parties? Tapping into Web3, this is the future that GLASS plans to create. Brands on GLASS use tokens to incentivize fans to try new cocktail recipes, socialize with friends, vote on brand decisions, and more; and fans can use those tokens to unlock exclusive rewards and experiences.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-prominent-brands-stir-up-social-engagement-with-glass">Prominent brands stir up social engagement with GLASS</h2>



<p>Premium alcohol brands are already live on this groundbreaking new platform. These include premium Italian winemaker Lyons Wine; Talkhouse Encore, the canned cocktail brand affiliated with legendary music hall The Stephen Talkhouse; Hotaling &amp; Co’s Fiero Tequila, the spiciest infused tequila in the US; and Junipero Gin, the original American craft gin. Each brand is prepped to offer its customers unique rewards — from exclusive merchandise to money-can’t buy-experiences on Web3 with GLASS and the NEAR blockchain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We see great potential in building the Lyons Wine community on GLASS,” said Lyons Wine CEO and founder Chris Lyons. “Lyons Wine has always been driven by community and innovation, and we’re excited to leverage web3 to bring exclusive rewards to our network through this platform.”</p>



<p>Through upcoming integrations with alcohol e-commerce and point-of-sale platforms, GLASS members will be able to track purchases and earn for purchasing as well as socializing — in ways that comply with each member’s local regulations. From the bar, to the friend’s house, to the stadium, GLASS creates a unified platform for fans and brands to engage across the full universe of social occasions.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We’re excited to use this new platform to engage and grow the Fiero Tequila community of ‘heat seekers’ who rally around the spiciest infused tequila in the U.S,” said Jordan Parker, Head of Marketing for the Agave Portfolio at Hotaling &amp; Co. “The platform will help us bring our community together around the unique, social activations that Fiero has planned.”</p>



<p>GLASS will continue to announce new brand partnerships and roll out new features throughout the summer and fall. Consumers can sign up directly at <a href="http://www.glass.fun/">www.glass.fun</a> to start earning tokens today.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/how-glass-is-uncorking-adult-beverage-loyalty-with-web3-and-near/">How GLASS is Uncorking Adult Beverage Loyalty with Web3 and NEAR </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation and Sail GP Elevate Mobile Fan Engagement with The Dock</title>
		<link>/blog/near-foundation-and-sail-gp-elevate-mobile-fan-engagement-with-the-dock/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loyalty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SailGP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Dock]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SailGP and NEAR Foundation are embarking on a daring journey where sports meets blockchain. SailGP’s The Dock platform is ready …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-and-sail-gp-elevate-mobile-fan-engagement-with-the-dock/">NEAR Foundation and Sail GP Elevate Mobile Fan Engagement with The Dock</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>SailGP and NEAR Foundation are embarking on a daring journey where sports meets blockchain. SailGP’s <a href="https://sailgp.com/dock/">The Dock</a> platform is ready to make waves and redefine fan engagement in both sailing and sports at large. After its maiden voyage as a web-based platform on June 13th, The Dock is now ready to drop anchor with the launch of the new mobile app.</p>



<p>The Dock is SailGP&#8217;s free loyalty program that brings fans closer than ever to the sport and will now be available in both Apple and Google Play Stores. And by leveraging the NEAR blockchain, users of The Dock will be able to claim unique rewards and digital assets using Web3 to engage sports fans like never before.</p>



<p>Not to mention that The Dock is powered in part by Oracle, making the triad of SailGP and NEAR an excellent representation of building bridges between Web2 and Web3.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-dock-a-revolution-in-fan-engagement">The Dock: A revolution in Fan Engagement</h2>



<p>The Dock is an immersive loyalty platform designed to reward and engage sports and sailing enthusiasts globally. The platform — and now mobile app — gives fans a chance to create personalized accounts, engage with unique and exclusive SailGP content, and earn points redeemable for exclusive rewards.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With offerings ranging from VIP access to SailGP events and signed merchandise to once-in-a-lifetime experiences with teams and athletes, The Dock is every fan’s passport to an interactive way of engaging with their favorite SailGP athletes and teams. The platform essentially encourages fans to interact more, and in doing so earn more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With each interaction —± through videos, stories, behind-the-scenes content, quizzes, surveys, and polls — fans earn points that propel them closer to becoming a SailGP Champion. The accumulation of points unlocks new levels, each promising a unique set of exclusive benefits, enhancing the overall SailGP experience.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-dock-and-near-protocol-a-synergistic-partnership">The Dock and NEAR Protocol: A synergistic partnership</h2>



<p>A standout feature of The Dock is its fusion of Oracle&#8217;s CrowdTwist platform with the NEAR Protocol, symbolizing an industry-first partnership that bridges Web2 and Web3. This collaboration showcases how traditional and decentralized technologies can come together to revolutionize fan engagement in sports.</p>



<p>Through the Dock&#8217;s &#8216;Season Pass&#8217;, fans can link an existing NEAR account or create a new one. This paves the way for exciting blockchain-based rewards, including digital collectibles commemorating their progress. Fans can also trade these digital collectibles for limited-edition collectibles, adding another layer of engagement and excitement.</p>



<p>&#8220;Data is at the heart of SailGP — from the mid-race decisions made on the water to the league’s continued innovation around fan engagement,” said Rob Tarkoff, EVP of customer experience at Oracle. “We’re excited to support their newest CX initiative, The Dock, as they redefine their approach to the fan experience.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sailgp-s-journey-with-oracle-and-near">SailGP&#8217;s journey with Oracle and NEAR</h2>



<p>Since its inception in 2019, SailGP has harnessed the power of Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI) to expand from a five-team, six-event startup to one of the fastest-growing sports leagues in the world with ten teams competing in 12 events throughout 2023 and 2024. Oracle has stepped up as the Title Partner for the inaugural Los Angeles Sail Grand Prix. Scheduled for July 22 and 23, it’s a thrilling new addition to SailGP’s 12-event global calendar for Season 4, which kicks off in Chicago on June 16.</p>



<p>“Oracle’s cloud technology is at the heart of everything we do at SailGP, and this partnership extension reflects the power and results of our collaboration,” says Warren Jones, chief technology officer, SailGP. “We have no doubt Oracle will take our fan and athlete experience to even greater heights in the seasons to come and The Dock is a great example of this.”</p>



<p>With the launch of The Dock&#8217;s mobile app, this exciting world of interactive sailboat racing, fan engagement, and blockchain rewards is now just a tap away. Anyone can download the app and embark on their journey to become a SailGP Champion, while also exploring the new fandom possibilities offered by the blend of Web2 and Web3 technologies.</p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s mission is to push the boundaries of the Web3 world, create experiences that allow everyone to engage with decentralized technology, and foster partnerships that provide real-world utility for blockchain. Whether you&#8217;re immersed in the NEAR ecosystem or a sports enthusiast intrigued by the intersection of blockchain and sports.</p>



<p>The Dock promises an exciting glimpse into the future of fan engagement and loyalty platforms while bridging the gap between Web2 and Web3 with Oracle and NEAR. <br>Download The Dock mobile app today on the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/sailgp/id1445011811">Apple App Store</a> or <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sailgp.secondscreen&amp;hl=en_US&amp;pli=1">Google Play</a> and get started on your interactive journey.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-and-sail-gp-elevate-mobile-fan-engagement-with-the-dock/">NEAR Foundation and Sail GP Elevate Mobile Fan Engagement with The Dock</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rove World v2 Simplifies Web3 Ticketing and Loyalty for Brands</title>
		<link>/blog/rove-world-v2-simplifies-web3-ticketing-and-loyalty-for-brands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loyalty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ticketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Rove, one of the most user-friendly entertainment ecosystems in Web3, is now in collaboration with NEAR. Their next release, Rove …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/rove-world-v2-simplifies-web3-ticketing-and-loyalty-for-brands/">Rove World v2 Simplifies Web3 Ticketing and Loyalty for Brands</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://roveworld.xyz/">Rove</a>, one of the most user-friendly entertainment ecosystems in Web3, is now in collaboration with NEAR. Their next release, Rove World v2, will act as a one-stop mobile-based ticketing solution and loyalty rewards program for brands. The update will also feature an in-app store that will include major brands, sports leagues, and musical artists.</p>



<p>Rove and Rove World v2 removes many of the key friction points that occur when brands and creators try to engage their audience with Web3 technology. Notable brands are already on board, as Rove has collaborated with the likes of <a href="https://roveworld.xyz/events/tommy-hilfiger-fw2022">Tommy Hilfiger</a> on the Web2 side, alongside some of Web3’s largest brands such as Claynosaurz and MonkeDAO, with more exciting partnerships and activations to be announced soon.</p>



<p>“A multichain approach was always at the forefront of our long-term growth strategy for Rove,” said Jason Desimone, Founder of Rove. “Having built and launched the initial version of the Rove World mobile app, our goal is to now expand the reach and traction of Rove to other ‘Layer 1’ blockchain communities and ecosystems that align with our vision and will help us achieve our goals with the launch of Rove v2.”</p>



<p>Let’s take a look at how Rove World V2 is a game-changer for branded NFTs on NEAR.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-rove-is-helping-brands-amp-up-their-nfts">How Rove is helping brands amp up their NFTs</h2>



<p>The Rove ecosystem is a solution to many of the core issues facing brand and entertainment NFT campaigns, launches, and projects. That’s because Web3 itself is often difficult or daunting for the end user, who amongst other things might have questions about the value or utility of NFT ownership.</p>



<p>What Rove brings to the table is a user-friendly mobile app where NFTs are minted in mere seconds and with minimal steps. Brands can also easily add utility to the NFTs which are easily accessible by the user. Rove&#8217;s vision aligns seamlessly with NEAR’s Web2.5 strategy of making the onboarding of the next billion users into Web3 as easy as possible.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Brand and entertainment NFT experiences built atop Rove and NEAR lets users log in seamlessly through familiar means like social media log-in, Apple ID, or facial ID. NFTs are easily sent and received on the Rove app via usernames, again with a similar Web2 interface to that of Venmo.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-rove-world-v2-release-lets-brands-create-buzz">Rove World v2 release lets brands create buzz</h2>



<p>The Rove World v2 release will be a major part of Rove’s suite of tools that make it easy for brands to get started with blockchain technology. Their approach is to allow brands to engage with NFTs in a collaborative manner that benefits creators, brands, and end users alike. Rove World v2 on Near is a huge leap in that direction.</p>



<p>The main feature is the in-app store that brands can now leverage in combination with Rove’s flagship app for curated NFT launches and blockchain-based ticketing. Not only will attendees be able to claim NFTs instantly at the tap of their phone, but brands can also now leverage Rove World v2 to offer seamless in-app purchases via the mobile store.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-and-entertainment-continue-to-shine-with-rove">NEAR and entertainment continue to shine with Rove</h2>



<p>Rove has many brands in the pipeline across the fashion, film, music, and sports verticals that want a seamless NFT experience for their customers. This not only brings more notable and forward-thinking brands into NEAR’s orbit but also showcases how the NEAR ecosystem continues to make major strides in the sports and entertainment verticals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Eventually, Rove will serve as a central ticketing and NFT project on NEAR. Users can easily create assets, mint the NFT, and distribute it however they’d like. The entire experience will be on a single mobile app, bridging the technical gap between users and brands while giving a fairer share to creators than mainstream NFT marketplaces.</p>



<p>All assets on Rove and Rove World v2 also have some form of utility. Anyone who owns an NFT on Rove can stake that asset for Rove credits that unlock various perks. It’s a great example of how Rove is making all of Web3 simple, including things like staking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ticketing and NFT distribution for brands and creators are about to get a whole lot easier for everyone thanks to Rove. And with Rove World v2’s in-app store, major brands are lining up to be at the forefront of making web3 truly accessible, user-friendly, and financially fair.</p>



<p>“NEAR’s emphasis on onboarding the next billion users into Web3 with a specialized focus on entertainment, sports, and culture fit identically with our approach,” said Rove’s Desimone. “Not to mention NEAR’s industry-leading technology which enables a seamless migration of the easy-to-use features of the Rove World mobile app onto the NEAR blockchain.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/rove-world-v2-simplifies-web3-ticketing-and-loyalty-for-brands/">Rove World v2 Simplifies Web3 Ticketing and Loyalty for Brands</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
