<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ticketing Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/ticketing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/ticketing/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 19:09:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ticketing Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/ticketing/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Rove World v2 Simplifies Web3 Ticketing and Loyalty for Brands</title>
		<link>/blog/rove-world-v2-simplifies-web3-ticketing-and-loyalty-for-brands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loyalty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ticketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Rove, one of the most user-friendly entertainment ecosystems in Web3, is now in collaboration with NEAR. Their next release, Rove …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/rove-world-v2-simplifies-web3-ticketing-and-loyalty-for-brands/">Rove World v2 Simplifies Web3 Ticketing and Loyalty for Brands</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://roveworld.xyz/">Rove</a>, one of the most user-friendly entertainment ecosystems in Web3, is now in collaboration with NEAR. Their next release, Rove World v2, will act as a one-stop mobile-based ticketing solution and loyalty rewards program for brands. The update will also feature an in-app store that will include major brands, sports leagues, and musical artists.</p>



<p>Rove and Rove World v2 removes many of the key friction points that occur when brands and creators try to engage their audience with Web3 technology. Notable brands are already on board, as Rove has collaborated with the likes of <a href="https://roveworld.xyz/events/tommy-hilfiger-fw2022">Tommy Hilfiger</a> on the Web2 side, alongside some of Web3’s largest brands such as Claynosaurz and MonkeDAO, with more exciting partnerships and activations to be announced soon.</p>



<p>“A multichain approach was always at the forefront of our long-term growth strategy for Rove,” said Jason Desimone, Founder of Rove. “Having built and launched the initial version of the Rove World mobile app, our goal is to now expand the reach and traction of Rove to other ‘Layer 1’ blockchain communities and ecosystems that align with our vision and will help us achieve our goals with the launch of Rove v2.”</p>



<p>Let’s take a look at how Rove World V2 is a game-changer for branded NFTs on NEAR.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-rove-is-helping-brands-amp-up-their-nfts">How Rove is helping brands amp up their NFTs</h2>



<p>The Rove ecosystem is a solution to many of the core issues facing brand and entertainment NFT campaigns, launches, and projects. That’s because Web3 itself is often difficult or daunting for the end user, who amongst other things might have questions about the value or utility of NFT ownership.</p>



<p>What Rove brings to the table is a user-friendly mobile app where NFTs are minted in mere seconds and with minimal steps. Brands can also easily add utility to the NFTs which are easily accessible by the user. Rove&#8217;s vision aligns seamlessly with NEAR’s Web2.5 strategy of making the onboarding of the next billion users into Web3 as easy as possible.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Brand and entertainment NFT experiences built atop Rove and NEAR lets users log in seamlessly through familiar means like social media log-in, Apple ID, or facial ID. NFTs are easily sent and received on the Rove app via usernames, again with a similar Web2 interface to that of Venmo.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-rove-world-v2-release-lets-brands-create-buzz">Rove World v2 release lets brands create buzz</h2>



<p>The Rove World v2 release will be a major part of Rove’s suite of tools that make it easy for brands to get started with blockchain technology. Their approach is to allow brands to engage with NFTs in a collaborative manner that benefits creators, brands, and end users alike. Rove World v2 on Near is a huge leap in that direction.</p>



<p>The main feature is the in-app store that brands can now leverage in combination with Rove’s flagship app for curated NFT launches and blockchain-based ticketing. Not only will attendees be able to claim NFTs instantly at the tap of their phone, but brands can also now leverage Rove World v2 to offer seamless in-app purchases via the mobile store.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-and-entertainment-continue-to-shine-with-rove">NEAR and entertainment continue to shine with Rove</h2>



<p>Rove has many brands in the pipeline across the fashion, film, music, and sports verticals that want a seamless NFT experience for their customers. This not only brings more notable and forward-thinking brands into NEAR’s orbit but also showcases how the NEAR ecosystem continues to make major strides in the sports and entertainment verticals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Eventually, Rove will serve as a central ticketing and NFT project on NEAR. Users can easily create assets, mint the NFT, and distribute it however they’d like. The entire experience will be on a single mobile app, bridging the technical gap between users and brands while giving a fairer share to creators than mainstream NFT marketplaces.</p>



<p>All assets on Rove and Rove World v2 also have some form of utility. Anyone who owns an NFT on Rove can stake that asset for Rove credits that unlock various perks. It’s a great example of how Rove is making all of Web3 simple, including things like staking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ticketing and NFT distribution for brands and creators are about to get a whole lot easier for everyone thanks to Rove. And with Rove World v2’s in-app store, major brands are lining up to be at the forefront of making web3 truly accessible, user-friendly, and financially fair.</p>



<p>“NEAR’s emphasis on onboarding the next billion users into Web3 with a specialized focus on entertainment, sports, and culture fit identically with our approach,” said Rove’s Desimone. “Not to mention NEAR’s industry-leading technology which enables a seamless migration of the easy-to-use features of the Rove World mobile app onto the NEAR blockchain.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/rove-world-v2-simplifies-web3-ticketing-and-loyalty-for-brands/">Rove World v2 Simplifies Web3 Ticketing and Loyalty for Brands</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
