<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Hackathon Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/hackathon/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/hackathon/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 18:59:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Hackathon Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/hackathon/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</title>
		<link>/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI is NEAR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hackathon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with Edge and Polygon Labs, the NEAR Foundation will co-sponsor a Decentralized AI Summit and “Autonomous Agent,” an …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/">Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In collaboration with Edge and Polygon Labs, the NEAR Foundation will co-sponsor a Decentralized AI <a href="https://lu.ma/fvoeazk8">Summit</a> and “Autonomous Agent,” an AI x Web3 <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/autonomous-agent-hackathon">Hackathon</a>, at ETHDenver on February 26 and 27. The events will bring together visionaries, developers, and enthusiasts working at the intersection of AI and Web3 along with a hackathon for builders and researchers to dive into the buzziest tech topic of today. Speakers at the Summit will include Vitalik Buterin of the Ethereum Foundation, Illia Polosukhin of NEAR Foundation, Sandeep Nailwal of Polygon Labs, and Sreeram Kannan of EigenLayer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Autonomous Agent” is the first event in the &#8220;{Chain}-of-Thought&#8221; series from <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/">Edge</a>, which will explore and harness the potential of Web3 and open source AI. Edge is a research and development organization dedicated to democratizing access to open intelligence and advancing the evolution of next-generation web architecture. Hackers can expect hands-on hacking sessions, workshops, and mentorship opportunities with a chance to learn from those at the cutting edge of decentralized AI development. </p>



<p>The intersection of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Web3 technology is poised to revolutionize industries, with many Web3 projects now incorporating AI into decentralized applications and developer tools. Ethereum Co-Founder Vitalik Buterin recently shared his <a href="https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2024/01/30/cryptoai.html">observations</a> about the intersection, and NEAR Co-Founder Illia Polosukhin shared how AI fits into the vision for the NEAR ecosystem in a recent <a href="/blog/self-sovereignty-is-near-a-vision-for-our-ecosystem/">post</a>. </p>



<p>As the risks from centralized AI controlled primarily by major corporations become more apparent, investing in open source, transparent AI development will become increasingly important––along with community building, governance experiments, and advocacy. “{Chain} of Thought” will lead the way in bringing members of the AI and Web3 ecosystems together to advance these initiatives and make concrete progress.</p>



<p>In addition to the premier sponsors, the “Autonomous Agent” hackathon is co-sponsored by <a href="https://www.eigenlayer.xyz/">EigenLayer</a>, <a href="https://www.gensyn.ai/">Gensyn</a>, and <a href="https://www.hyperoracle.io/">Hyper Oracle</a>, with co-hosting participation from Sentient, Lightspeed, and Symbolic Capital. Benefits of participation include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Cutting-Edge Workshops:</strong> Engage with industry experts and thought leaders through immersive workshops exploring the latest trends and technologies in AI x Web3.</li>



<li><strong>Hackathon Challenges:</strong> Tackle real-world challenges and showcase your creativity by developing innovative solutions at the forefront of AI and Web3 integration.</li>



<li><strong>Networking Opportunities:</strong> Connect with like-minded individuals, potential collaborators, and industry professionals to expand your network and exchange ideas.</li>



<li><strong>Prizes and Recognition:</strong> Compete for exciting prizes and gain recognition for your contributions to the advancement of AI x Web3 technology.</li>
</ul>



<p>Join NEAR Foundation, Polygon Labs, and Edge in Denver and be a part of the next great tech revolution. Those interested in attending the Decentralized AI Summit can register <a href="https://lu.ma/fvoeazk8">here</a>. Researchers, developers, and hackers interested in participating in the <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/autonomous-agent-hackathon">hackathon</a> can apply <a href="https://lu.ma/k6dw9jk2">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/">Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Near at ETHDenver Hackathon Bounty Winners</title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-ethdenver-hackathon-bounty-winners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 18:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHDenver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hackathon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For the 2023 edition of ETHDenver, the Near ecosystem offered a number of bounties across a range of Web3 verticals, …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethdenver-hackathon-bounty-winners/">Near at ETHDenver Hackathon Bounty Winners</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>For the 2023 edition of ETHDenver, the Near ecosystem offered a number of bounties across a range of Web3 verticals, including DeFi, Content, Search, Social Media, Interoperability, Smart Contract History, and more. There were 3 main prize pools from Aurora, Proximity, and Developer Governance (DevGov).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congratulations to all Near winners. who received over 30k in USDC! Let’s have a look at the winning projects of the Near at ETHDenver bounties. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-aurora-bounty-winners">Aurora Bounty Winners</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-open-aurora-bounty">Open Aurora Bounty</h3>



<p><em>Winner &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/stakingpool-aurora'"><em>StakingPool Aurora</em></a></p>



<p>Implements a liquid staking protocol around Aurora Plus staking. Users will deposit AURORA and receive a share in $stAUR tokens, which distributes the APY rewards. $stAUR could be immediately converted with a fee or wait for a delayed unstake.</p>



<p><em>Runner Up &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/geni"><em>Geni</em></a></p>



<p>AI-powered specifications generator of security tests for smart contracts.</p>



<p><em>Runner Up &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/demeter"><em>Demeter</em></a></p>



<p>A lending platform that offers yield advancements, i.e., self-paying loans. Borrowers’ collateral is invested in RWA protocols, and the yield pays off debt.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-proximity-bounty-winners">Proximity Bounty Winners</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-deploy-a-decentralized-frontend-component">Deploy a Decentralized Frontend Component</h3>



<p><em>Winner &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/boswrap"><em>BosWrap</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>BosWrap used the Near Blockchain Operating System to build a decentralized widget for wrapping/unwrapping ETH.</p>



<p><em>Runner Up &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/abi-bos-widget"><em>ABI BOS Widget</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>A solidity explorer widget that allow users to explore any smart contract for a given ABI. You can get ABI from <a href="https://etherscan.io/">Etherscan website</a>.</p>



<p><em>Runner Up &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/bossed-up"><em>Bossed Up</em></a></p>



<p>A project focusing on Ethereum frontends, Blockchain Operating System improvements, and NEAR Social widgets that interact with NEAR contracts.</p>



<p><em>Runner Up &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/undrip"><em>Atmosph3re</em></a></p>



<p>A dApp for reducing the homeless crisis in the United States by giving those living on the streets a decentralized identity, mentoring and community support, and funds for spending on their basic needs to help them thrive. </p>



<p><em>Runner Up &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/ethdenver2023uwca"><em>EthDenver2023UWCA</em></a></p>



<p>A dApp on NeaR’s new frontend with BOS.GG. Integrates with Rocketpool to offer quick swaps on Ethereum.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-devgov-bounty-winners">DevGov Bounty Winners</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-extensive-developer-profile-widget">Extensive Developer Profile Widget</h3>



<p><em>Winner &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/developer-profile"><em>Developer Profile</em></a></p>



<p>A recreation of Github profile for NEAR social developers in the Blockchain Operating System. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-fuzzy-search-widget-promoted-posts-banner-widget-top-posts-widget-post-history-with-diff-widget">Fuzzy Search Widget / Promoted Posts Banner Widget / Top Posts Widget&nbsp; / Post History with Diff Widget</h3>



<p><em>Winner &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/near-social-update"><em>Near.Social DevGovGigs Improvements</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>A new Developer Governance Gigs interaction experience for Near.Social. Features: 1) Fuzzy Searching that can handle typos, 2) Promote posts and Promoted Post viewer, 3) Hottest Posts viewer, and 4), Post editing history viewer.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-social-bots-coded-in-javascript">Near.Social Bots Coded in Javascript</h3>



<p><em>Winner &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/js-bot-widget"><em>JS Bot Widget</em></a></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Verifiable RPC Replies</h3>



<p><em>Winner &#8211; </em><a href="https://app.buidlbox.io/projects/project-2"><em>Near Verifiable RPC Endpoints for Viewing Access Keys</em></a></p>



<p>Adds proof generation support to RPC read access key endpoints on the NEAR protocol to help pave the road for light client support. </p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethdenver-hackathon-bounty-winners/">Near at ETHDenver Hackathon Bounty Winners</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
