<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ethereum Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/ethereum/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/ethereum/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 14:05:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ethereum Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/ethereum/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Mantle Ecosystem Gateway Launches on the NEAR Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S)</title>
		<link>/blog/mantle-ecosystem-gateway-launches-on-the-near-blockchain-operating-system-b-o-s/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B.O.S]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain Operating System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mantle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20896</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>An ecosystem gateway for Mantle, the layer-2 scaling solution built on Ethereum, has launched on the NEAR Blockchain Operating System …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/mantle-ecosystem-gateway-launches-on-the-near-blockchain-operating-system-b-o-s/">Mantle Ecosystem Gateway Launches on the NEAR Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S)</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>An<a href="https://bos.fusionx.finance/"> ecosystem gateway for Mantle</a>, the layer-2 scaling solution built on Ethereum, has launched on the NEAR Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S) to offer a unified point of entry into the Mantle ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hosted by popular Mantle dApp <a href="https://fusionx.finance/">FusionX</a>, the gateway, built in collaboration with the NEAR community, streamlines the discovery of Mantle applications and helps aggregate components of top dApps including the <a href="https://bridge.mantle.xyz/">Mantle Bridge</a>, <a href="https://agni.finance/">Agni</a>, <a href="https://www.ammos.fi/">Ammos</a>, <a href="https://mantle.izumi.finance/">iZiSwap</a>, FusionX, <a href="https://www.gamma.xyz/">Gamma</a>, <a href="https://www.lendle.xyz/">Lendle</a>, and soon Pendle, in one place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The gateway offers greater accessibility for developers and users, easier discoverability for the apps they build, and powerful composability. This was all made possible thanks to the B.O.S.</p>



<p>“Mantle has seen some great traction since their launch and we’re very excited to have a Mantle gateway built on B.O.S. Ethereum and DeFi users interested in discovering new projects can now find lots of Mantle apps in one place, with bridging already solved so they can get started right away,” says Illia Polosukhin, co-founder of NEAR Protocol. “The Mantle gateway demonstrates the value of B.O.S gateways for other L2s and EVM projects looking to increase discoverability.”&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-unlocking-the-web3-ecosystem">Unlocking the Web3 ecosystem&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Mantle’s development on NEAR is a testament to the protocol’s commitment to creating the foundations for the open web. “We are delighted to ally with NEAR in bringing leading Mantle dApps to a wider community through the Mantle Ecosystem Gateway on B.O.S,” says Arjun Kalsy, head of ecosystem of Mantle. “Through this effort, we look to provide even more support to our dev community, and allow for more cross-pollination in our respective Web3 communities.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Mantle gateway joins a growing list of projects that have partnered with the B.O.S to help unlock the full potential of Web3. A <a href="https://bos.quickswap.exchange/">zkEVM B.O.S gateway</a> for the Polygon ecosystem launched on NEAR to help increase accessibility and discoverability for developers, while also improving the user experience for end users exploring L2 ecosystems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While the B.O.S is built on NEAR, it offers many benefits&nbsp; to founders and builders from EVM projects and across the whole Web3 ecosystem. The Blockchain Operating System speeds up the process of building multi-chain experiences, empowering builders from any ecosystem––including EVM projects such as Ethereum layer 2s––to focus on creating great products for users rather than on managing infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Developers can quickly build composable apps for the open web from thousands of flexible components, as well as seamlessly onboard users and increase discoverability across Web3 since every application utilising B.O.S is visible on a common interface. This collaboration brings new capabilities to developers and lets them build apps that can quickly reach more users.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/mantle-ecosystem-gateway-launches-on-the-near-blockchain-operating-system-b-o-s/">Mantle Ecosystem Gateway Launches on the NEAR Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S)</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR at ETHCC: Step into the Open Web on the BOS</title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-ethcc-step-into-the-open-web-on-the-bos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce that NEAR will be returning to ETHCC 2023. The Foundation will be hosting a …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-step-into-the-open-web-on-the-bos/">NEAR at ETHCC: Step into the Open Web on the BOS</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce that NEAR will be returning to ETHCC 2023. The Foundation will be hosting a 2-day side event at the Paris tech conference on July 16-17.</p>



<p>NEAR experts will be on hand at ETHCC to share the latest updates for building apps on the open web&nbsp; with the BOS&nbsp; — an industry-first OS that makes it easy to use the tools you already know to build apps that engage users, while fostering an open web untethered from centralized platforms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Also, learn how your project can get funding and other support from NEAR Horizon, the new Web3 startup platform built on the BOS. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-at-ethcc-what-to-expect">NEAR at ETHCC — What to expect</h2>



<p>NEAR is hosting a two-day ETHCC side event on July 16-17th, that will feature Technical Workshops (BOS) hosted by Pagoda, a Horizon Pitch Competition, small ETH research group workshops (invite only), and other speaker sessions, keynotes, and panels. You can’t forget about our exclusive networking and happy hours!</p>



<p>Learn from the best in the NEAR ecosystem about what makes the BOS so revolutionary. Ask your questions. Learn in-person. Make connections!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Agenda: NEAR at ETHCC</h2>



<p>NEAR’s 2-day ETHCC side event will be located at the <a href="https://www.mnhn.fr/fr/privatiser-l-amphitheatre-verniquet">Museum National D’Histoire Naturelle: Verniquet</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Day 1: Technical Day&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>11am &#8211; 12pm: Breakfast bites &amp; Networking &#8211; Cafe au laits and pastries</li>



<li>12-12:30pm: Stateless Validation &#8211; Invite Only Research Group&nbsp;</li>



<li>12:30-1pm: Token Economics &#8211; Invite Only Research Group&nbsp;</li>



<li>1-1:30pm: BOS Vision&nbsp;</li>



<li>1:30-2pm: BOS for Devs&nbsp;</li>



<li>2-2:30pm: BOS Tech Breakdown for Partners&nbsp;</li>



<li>2:30-3pm: Simona/ETH Session&nbsp;</li>



<li>3pm-4pm: Programming Break, Happy hour guests arrive&nbsp;</li>



<li>4pm &#8211; 7pm: Happy Hour &#8211; Appetizers and drinks&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Structure for Day 2: Founders Day&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>11am &#8211; 12pm: Networking and Co-working: Cafe au laits and pastries</li>



<li>12pm-12:30pm: Pantera Capital Workshop&nbsp;</li>



<li>12:30-1pm: Proximity Workshop&nbsp;</li>



<li>1-1:30pm: Simona/ETH Session&nbsp;</li>



<li>1:30-2pm: Pitchfest Guests arrive&nbsp;</li>



<li>2-4pm: Horizon Pitch Fest&nbsp;</li>



<li>4pm &#8211; 7pm: Horizon Pitch Competition Happy Hour: Aperol spritz and appetizers</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">NEAR Speakers at ETHCC</h2>



<ul>
<li>Illia Polosukhin, CEO of Pagoda, Co-Founder of NEAR</li>



<li>Matt Stephenson, Head of Cryptoeconomics, Pantera Capital</li>



<li>Vy Le, Bain Capital</li>



<li>Kendall Cole, Co-Founder and Director of Proximity</li>



<li>Mya Shofany, Regulatory Lead, NEAR Foundation</li>



<li>Bowen Want, Director of Protocol, Pagoda</li>



<li>And more!</li>
</ul>



<p>Stay updated on the complete slate of confirmed speakers and sessions at Near.org/ETHCC.&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/near-ethcc-tickets-655229297467?aff=oddtdtcreator"><strong>Register for NEAR at ETHCC</strong></a></div>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://near.org/"><strong>Explore the BOS</strong></a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-step-into-the-open-web-on-the-bos/">NEAR at ETHCC: Step into the Open Web on the BOS</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
