<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Infrastructure Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/infrastructure/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/infrastructure/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:31:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Infrastructure Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/infrastructure/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Vistara Lands in the NEAR Ecosystem for Seamless Base Layer Roll-up Deployment</title>
		<link>/blog/vistara-lands-in-the-near-ecosystem-for-seamless-base-layer-roll-up-deployment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20704</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR is welcoming Vistara, the groundbreaking rollup deployment framework, into the fold. Vistara is set to seamlessly integrate with the …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/vistara-lands-in-the-near-ecosystem-for-seamless-base-layer-roll-up-deployment/">Vistara Lands in the NEAR Ecosystem for Seamless Base Layer Roll-up Deployment</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR is welcoming <a href="https://twitter.com/vistaralabs">Vistara</a>, the groundbreaking rollup deployment framework, into the fold. Vistara is set to seamlessly integrate with the BOS for the end-to-end, multi-chain deployment of rollups. This alliance will accelerate the pace of blockchain innovation, making rollup deployment faster, more efficient, and accessible across multiple chains for all developers.</p>



<p>Vistara stands out as a game-changing one-click <a href="https://docs.vistara.dev/">rollup deployment framework</a> that simplifies creating application-specific rollups across multiple blockchains. Streamlining the intricate rollup deployment process into a straightforward, single-click operation, Vistara will build a front-end on the BOS to make user-friendly, multi-chain rollup deployment a reality.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-simplifying-multi-chain-roll-ups-with-vistara-on-the-bos">Simplifying multi-chain roll-ups with Vistara on the BOS&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Existing frameworks such as Cosmos SDK and Substrate have sought to streamline certain software components in decentralized applications but often leave developers tied to one ecosystem that they must completely understand and master. Vistara will now present a unique solution by combining the BOS with backend chains like Ethereum and Celestia.</p>



<p>Vistara’s emphasis on simplifying rollup component creation aligns with NEAR&#8217;s vision of user-centric decentralization and a serverless Web3. With this new BOS front-end integration, developers in the NEAR ecosystem and beyond can now build and deploy rollups in one convenient location.</p>



<p>The result will be a user-friendly design that makes the deployment of a rollup as simple as selecting an option from a dropdown menu. The integration will also encourage a wider range of developers to build with rollups on the BOS with any chain, leading to a more diverse pool of innovations and robust growth.</p>



<p>Vistara’s integration not only simplifies the process but also expands the scope for innovation. It demystifies rollup creation, making it accessible to a broader range of developers. This inclusivity fuels a more diverse pool of applications, fostering growth and vibrancy within the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-vistara-and-bos-breaking-base-layer-building-barriers">Vistara and BOS breaking base layer building barriers</h2>



<p>Developing decentralized applications on base layers can be a complex process. Coordination of node operators, high costs, and extended development times are among the major challenges. However, Vistara is designed to confront these issues directly, streamlining the process and fostering efficiency.</p>



<p>Rollups — technologies that bundle or &#8216;roll up&#8217; side-chain transactions into a single transaction — provide an effective solution. They help developers bypass the difficulties associated with building decentralized networks. Vistara leverages this rollup technology, pushing the NEAR ecosystem towards application-specific rollups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The solution effectively untangles the complexities tied to base layer dependencies, forging a development environment on the BOS that stretches beyond traditional base layer confines. With Vistara, multi-chain developers can now bring their applications to life more swiftly and efficiently than ever before.</p>



<p>To sum up, Vistara&#8217;s user-friendly, multi-chain rollup deployment capabilities on the BOS will have a huge impact on the NEAR ecosystem and beyond. The integration will take much of the complexity out of rollup deployment for anyone, helping Web3 creators, builders, and developers bring their applications to life faster than ever.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/vistara-lands-in-the-near-ecosystem-for-seamless-base-layer-roll-up-deployment/">Vistara Lands in the NEAR Ecosystem for Seamless Base Layer Roll-up Deployment</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation Partners with Absolute Labs to Accelerate How Brands Connect with Customers in Web3</title>
		<link>/blog/near-foundation-partners-with-absolute-labs-to-accelerate-how-brands-connect-with-customers-in-web3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 13:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20444</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a new partnership with Absolute Labs, a company revolutionizing Web3’s marketing stack. Its “Wallet …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-partners-with-absolute-labs-to-accelerate-how-brands-connect-with-customers-in-web3/">NEAR Foundation Partners with Absolute Labs to Accelerate How Brands Connect with Customers in Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a new partnership with <a href="https://absolutelabs.io/">Absolute Labs</a>, a company revolutionizing Web3’s marketing stack. Its “Wallet Relationship Management™ platform can be used by Web2 brands and Web3 startups alike to acquire, convert and retain customers on the Open Web. </p>



<p>To help in this endeavor, the company <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/absolute-labs-announces-8-million-150000487.html">announced</a> an $8M seed round of funding at NFT NYC in the past week. Other funding partners include backers like Samsung Next, Aglae Ventures, Sparkle Ventures (Animoca Brands), The Luxury Fund and MoonPay. </p>



<p>”We are thrilled to have the NEAR Foundation as a partner in helping us to accelerate how marketing is done in the next Internet,” says Samir Addamine, Absolute Labs’ CEO and co-founder. “Both our organizations share a vision to accelerate the world’s transition to decentralized marketplaces and more open, transparent and valued user engagement, so it’s a great fit for us.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-is-wallet-relationship-management">What is Wallet Relationship Management</h2>



<p>Wallet Relationship Management (WRM™) starts with the premise that wallets hold the keys to everything Web3 — from proving identity, providing access to value-rich brand experiences, facilitating payments, creating “ownership” opportunities for customers, and much more. Combining on-chain data from wallets along with assets that Web2 brands can also inject from their Web2 systems, this platform supports all facets of the marketing funnel, from acquisition to conversion and retention of loyalty.</p>



<p>Users of the platform can gain deep insights into their customers and their on-chain preferences and behaviors, identify actionable segments to track and engage, and craft cross-chain and cross-channel (Web2 and Web3) campaigns to develop and nurture relationships</p>



<p>Absolute Labs customers can also use WRM to reactivate dormant wallet customers by using the WRM dashboard to distribute meaningful incentives such as rewards tokens, NFTs, and more. </p>



<p>To date, Absolute Labs has 40+ companies using their services. With WRM, these customers get an enterprise-grade suite of connectors and APIs to seamlessly integrate with their existing marketing tech stack. </p>



<p>Absolute Labs has an incredibly strong product and is a fantastic addition to the NEAR ecosystem. Their Wallet Relationship Management platform is a clear market leader in the burgeoning Web3 martech space, and is already an indispensable component of the modern marketing stack. By bringing Absolute Labs into the NEAR ecosystem, it creates a seamless Web3 on-ramp for brands  and will enable them to engage, retain, and reactivate customers like never before.</p>



<p>DISCLOSURE: <em>Any information shared in this announcement regarding our partnership with Absolute Labs should not be considered as a binding agreement or representation, and may be subject to change without notice. The information presented in this communication is for informational purposes only and should not be construed as investment advice. Any decisions made based on this information are solely the responsibility of the individual or entity making them.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-partners-with-absolute-labs-to-accelerate-how-brands-connect-with-customers-in-web3/">NEAR Foundation Partners with Absolute Labs to Accelerate How Brands Connect with Customers in Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance Custody Adds $NEAR Token and NEP-141 Standard to its Infrastructure</title>
		<link>/blog/binance-custody-adds-near-token-and-nep-141-standard-to-its-infrastructure/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to share its newest integration with Binance Custody, an institutional-grade digital asset custody solution. By supporting …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/binance-custody-adds-near-token-and-nep-141-standard-to-its-infrastructure/">Binance Custody Adds $NEAR Token and NEP-141 Standard to its Infrastructure</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to share its newest integration with Binance Custody, an institutional-grade digital asset custody solution. By supporting the NEP-141 standard, Binance Custody enables any institutional user with $NEAR holdings to make use of their highly secure storage infrastructure. The integration also makes it easier for Binance Custody to provide future support for any NEP-141 compatible tokens from projects building on NEAR.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For those not yet in the know, NEP-141 is simply a set of rules that determine how tokens on NEAR can operate. It’s an upgrade from the earlier NEP-21 standard by being simpler for users and developers as well as being cheaper and more efficient.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://nomicon.io/Standards/Tokens/FungibleToken/Core"><em>Click here</em></a><em> to learn more about NEAR’s NEP-141 standard</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-storing-near-and-nep-141-compatible-tokens-on-binance-custody">Storing NEAR and NEP-141 compatible tokens on Binance Custody</h2>



<p>What does it mean to be able to store NEAR and NEP-141 compatible tokens on Binance Custody? It means institutional users benefit from an integrated ecosystem built to help them manage their assets with world-class security standards backed by multi-party computation technology. Binance Custody is an independent, compliant, and audited custodial solution that currently supports over 230 digital assets.</p>



<p><a href="https://academy.binance.com/en/articles/custodial-vs-non-custodial-wallets-what-s-the-difference"><em>Click here</em></a><em> to learn the difference between custodial and non-custodial wallets&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>“We’re very excited to be part of NEAR’s journey as their institutional custody partner,” said Athena Yu, VP of Binance Custody. “With this integration, $NEAR token holders benefit from our secure, integrated security and liquidity solutions. We welcome any project building on the NEAR protocol to reach out to us to learn how our institutional infrastructure can help them scale with peace of mind.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Security on Binance Custody</h2>



<p>Platform security is paramount, and Binance Custody makes it easy for institutional users to safely store their digital assets. With this integration, Binance Custody allows investors to not only store their $NEAR tokens securely, but also benefit from liquidity opportunities thanks to the custodian’s integration with the vast Binance ecosystem, which includes the world’s largest crypto exchange by trading volume.</p>



<p>“A core mission for NEAR is building an ecosystem of diverse communities,” says NEAR Foundation CEO Marieke Flament. “With this partnership, NEAR can welcome to the NEAR ecosystem the many financial institutions that have turned to Binance Custody as their trusted provider for digital assets custody and settlement solutions.”</p>



<p>Binance Custody offers a growing suite of solutions currently including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Qualified Wallet: </strong>institutional-grade cold vault<strong> </strong>storage</li><li><strong>Prime Wallet</strong>: warm wallet infrastructure offering instantaneous transactions between Binance Custody and the Binance exchange, with sub-accounts.</li><li><strong>Binance Mirror</strong>: matches an institution’s cold storage custody funds with 1:1 availability on their Binance exchange account to access deep liquidity venues.</li><li><strong>Cold Convert</strong>: trade tokens from cold storage with zero counterparty risk and customized slippage tolerance without compromising on security.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Legal Disclaimer: </em></strong><em>The information contained in this press release is not directed at nor intended for use by any users, investors or prospective investors, and may not under any circumstances be relied upon when making a decision to invest in any NEAR tokens. Information in this release is not financial/investment advice, please seek independent financial advice.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/binance-custody-adds-near-token-and-nep-141-standard-to-its-infrastructure/">Binance Custody Adds $NEAR Token and NEP-141 Standard to its Infrastructure</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Teams With Google Cloud to Accelerate Web3 Startups</title>
		<link>/blog/near-teams-with-google-cloud-to-accelerate-web3-startups/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 12:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18589</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a new partnership between Google Cloud and NEAR Protocol. Going forward, Google Cloud will …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-teams-with-google-cloud-to-accelerate-web3-startups/">NEAR Teams With Google Cloud to Accelerate Web3 Startups</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation is excited to announce a new partnership between Google Cloud and NEAR Protocol. Going forward, Google Cloud will provide technical support for NEAR grant recipients. Open and developer-friendly, Google Cloud will support devs as they build and scale their Web3 projects and dApps.</p>



<p>If you’re developing on NEAR, this is great news—the partnership will supercharge blockchain innovations. Developers will even more easily create without limits as they build dApps and help onboard the masses into Web3.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We are thrilled to be collaborating with those who pioneered the Internet as we know it,” says Marieke Flament, CEO of the NEAR Foundation. “This partnership marks a new chapter for us as we continue to offer the best support possible for the next generation of visionaries choosing to build on the NEAR protocol.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-powering-near-developers-with-google-cloud">Powering NEAR developers with Google Cloud</h2>



<p>In the last year, NEAR has grown exponentially thanks to its super-fast, incredibly secure, and infinitely scalable protocol. There are now over 20 million accounts, 200 million transactions to date, and 300,000 to 400,000 transactions per day on the NEAR network. Building upon the momentum of NEARCON 2022, which showcased the NEAR ecosystem’s vibrancy, <a href="http://awesomenear.com/">800 projects</a> are now building on the protocol.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How will the hundreds of projects currently building on NEAR benefit from the Google Cloud partnership?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Google Cloud provides the infrastructure for NEAR’s Remote Procedure Call (RPC) node provider to <a href="https://www.pagoda.co/">Pagoda</a>, NEAR’s Web3 startup platform. This allows developers to deploy code quickly, securely, and seamlessly. Pagoda helps developers easily and rapidly launch dApps on NEAR through a library of pre-audited templates and auto-generated contract user interfaces.</p>



<p>&nbsp;“We will be supporting NEAR and giving Web3 developers the most secure, reliable, and sustainable cloud infrastructure on which they can build and scale,” Carlos Arena, Director of&nbsp;<a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/financial-services/google-cloud-launches-dedicated-digital-asset-team">Digital Assets</a> at Google Cloud. “We continue to support tomorrow’s leaders in creating new products and services on blockchain-based platforms.”</p>



<p>For more information on how Google Cloud is working to support Web3 innovation, check out <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/financial-services/google-cloud-launches-dedicated-digital-asset-team">Google Cloud’s Digital Assets blog</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-teams-with-google-cloud-to-accelerate-web3-startups/">NEAR Teams With Google Cloud to Accelerate Web3 Startups</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR and Circle Announce USDC Support for Multi-Chain Ecosystem&#160;</title>
		<link>/blog/near-and-circle-announce-usdc-support-for-multi-chain-ecosystem/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Big news coming out of the Converge22 conference in San Francisco this week. Circle Internet Financial, a global digital fintech …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-and-circle-announce-usdc-support-for-multi-chain-ecosystem/">NEAR and Circle Announce USDC Support for Multi-Chain Ecosystem&nbsp;</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Big news coming out of the Converge22 conference in San Francisco this week. <a href="https://www.circle.com/en/usdc">Circle</a> Internet Financial, a global digital fintech firm and the issuer of USD Coin (USDC), announced a partnership with NEAR that will make USDC widely available on the NEAR ecosystem by the end of 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Having USDC on NEAR is definitely a reason to celebrate. Circle will also make USDC available on other platforms to support a multi-chain ecosystem.  </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-powering-near-developers">Powering NEAR developers&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Bringing USDC to NEAR will help empower developers to integrate stablecoin payments flows into their Javascript and  Rust-based decentralized applications. This will unlock a new wave of accessibility for Web2 builders moving into Web3. It will also serve a vital role in NEAR’s mission of Web3 mass adoption, while helping developers build without limits.</p>



<p>“The multi-chain expansion increases USDC’s native availability from eight ecosystems to thirteen, and enables blockchain developers building on USDC and their users to experience greater liquidity and interoperability within the crypto economy,” said Joao Reginatto, VP of Product at Circle. “Extending multi-chain support for USDC opens the door for institutions, exchanges, developers and more to build their innovations and have easier access to a trusted and stable asset.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bringing USDC to NEAR is a big win for developers, who will now be able to integrate stablecoin payment flows into Javascript or Rust-based dApps. This will help usher in a new wave of accessibility for Web 2 builders making the shift to Web3.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-to-know-about-stablecoins">What to know about stablecoins</h2>



<p>A stablecoin is simply a cryptocurrency that is “pegged” to a more traditional currency like USD or EURO. Through various treasury and/or collateral models, they are designed to keep a 1:1 value, or parity, with their pegged counterparts. Stablecoins can also be pegged to credit and/or debt or have no collateral at all, as seen in algorithmic stablecoins.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Their presence in the Web3 ecosystem brings a sense of familiarity for natives and newcomers alike. A stablecoin is also a sort of on-ramp to understanding token economics—the gas that powers Web3 and beyond.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While designed to reduce cryptocurrency volatility, stablecoins present their own set of risks. When centralized, stablecoins can be victims of hacks, theft, or even over-printing which can lead to hyperinflation. If an algorithmic stablecoin experiences algorithmic failure, as happened with Terra and its sister currency, Luna, the stablecoin can fail. If a stablecoin is fractionally reserved instead of fully backed, there can be a bank run that triggers a dramatic stablecoin price drop.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br><em>Visit <a href="https://ref.finance/">ref.finance</a> for more information including the risks associated with&nbsp; investments.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-and-circle-announce-usdc-support-for-multi-chain-ecosystem/">NEAR and Circle Announce USDC Support for Multi-Chain Ecosystem&nbsp;</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aurora Partners With ConsenSys, Bringing MetaMask, Infura and More Ethereum Tools to NEAR</title>
		<link>/blog/aurora-consensys-partnership-metamask-infura/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aurora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=15392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Aurora, the Ethereum scaling solution that allows projects built on Ethereum to utilize the cutting-edge technology of the NEAR Protocol, …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/aurora-consensys-partnership-metamask-infura/">Aurora Partners With ConsenSys, Bringing MetaMask, Infura and More Ethereum Tools to NEAR</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://aurora.dev/">Aurora</a>, the Ethereum scaling solution that allows projects built on Ethereum to utilize the cutting-edge technology of the NEAR Protocol, is partnering with <a href="https://consensys.net/">ConsenSys</a>, the enterprise blockchain company to provide access to its suite of developer tools.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The partnership aims to empower both the <a href="/">NEAR</a> and Ethereum ecosystems by improving developer facilities &#8211; through the availability of the product suite &#8211; with the goal of increasing cross-chain interoperability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The product suite features projects including <a href="https://metamask.io/">MetaMask</a>, <a href="https://infura.io/">Infura</a>, <a href="https://consensys.net/quorum/">ConsenSys Quorum</a>, <a href="https://trufflesuite.com/">Truffle</a>, <a href="https://consensys.net/codefi/">Codefi</a>, and <a href="https://consensys.net/diligence/">Diligence</a>. MetaMask is the primary way a global user base of over 21 million monthly active users interact with applications on Web3. Over 350,000 developers use Infura to access Ethereum, IPFS and Layer 2 networks. In addition, 4.7 million developers create and deploy smart contracts using Truffle and ConsenSys Diligence has secured more than $25 billion in smart contracts with its hands-on dapp audits and testing tools.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We are thrilled to join forces with ConsenSys on our shared mission of empowering the Ethereum ecosystem and extending its economy,” said Alex Shevchenko, the CEO of Aurora Labs.</p>



<p>The partnership means ConsenSys will now have official participation in the ongoing development of the AuroraDAO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We are excited to be partnering with the talented Aurora and NEAR protocol teams. Developer interest in EVM-compatible scaling solutions continues to grow at the same pace as the rapid expansion of the Web3 ecosystem, says E.G. Galano, Co-Founder and Head of Engineering at Infura.</p>



<p>“We believe developers will benefit from the addition of Aurora to the Infura product suite by enabling them to utilize the NEAR network with the EVM tooling they are already familiar with.”</p>



<p>Infura is directly involved in the <a href="https://medium.com/nearprotocol/aurora-creates-dao-as-part-of-its-community-led-vision-d9181bb79dfa">AuroraDAO</a>, which hands over key decision making to its community as a part of its vision to create a scaling solution that is as decentralized as possible.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>About Aurora</strong></h2>



<p>Aurora is an EVM built on the NEAR Protocol, delivering a turn-key solution for developers to operate their apps on an Ethereum-compatible, high-throughput, scalable and future-safe platform, with low transaction costs for their users.</p>



<p><strong>Join Aurora’s community</strong></p>



<ul><li><a href="https://t.me/auroraisnear">Telegram</a></li><li><a href="https://discord.aurora.dev/">Discord</a> </li><li><a href="https://twitter.com/auroraisnear">Twitter</a> </li><li><a href="https://aurora.dev/">Website</a></li></ul>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/aurora-consensys-partnership-metamask-infura/">Aurora Partners With ConsenSys, Bringing MetaMask, Infura and More Ethereum Tools to NEAR</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR’s Private Shard: Infrastructure for Enterprise, Built on the Open Web</title>
		<link>/blog/near-launches-private-shard-for-enterprise/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 20:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://near.flywheelstaging.com/?p=14654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For business, privacy is important. Whether it be the transfer of confidential information to partners, or protecting customers’ data. Blockchain …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-launches-private-shard-for-enterprise/">NEAR’s Private Shard: Infrastructure for Enterprise, Built on the Open Web</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>For business, privacy is important. Whether it be the transfer of confidential information to partners, or protecting customers’ data. Blockchain has privacy baked into its DNA. But attempts at bringing enterprise and blockchain together have struggled.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Historically, businesses approached the ground-breaking technology by adopting the consortium model. Company A would invite its partners or companies in the same ecosystem to build a blockchain. But almost as soon as these consortiums started, they ran into issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Privacy is baked into blockchain&#8217;s DNA, but businesses have struggled to harness its potential.</p>



<p>Concerns around control and access merged with the headache of trying to move data from one company’s IT systems &#8211; often built on legacy software &#8211; to the blockchain in a way that could be interpreted by another company’s proprietary software. Then you have the thorny issue of throughput, fees and other associated costs with writing and storing data on the blockchain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is an issue we at NEAR have been thinking about deeply, and we believe we have the perfect solution to help enterprises embrace blockchain and the Open Web. We call it <strong>Private Shards.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-private-shards-blending-the-public-and-private-seamlessly-and-securely">Private Shards: Blending the public and private seamlessly and securely&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Since the inception of NEAR, it was always designed to be a sharded network: an interconnected global system of users, businesses, and infrastructure providers. As part of NEAR’s design is the ability to partition shards to suit different use cases.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignnone size-large wp-image-14230 size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="546" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/private-shard-1-1024x546.png" alt="" class="wp-image-14657" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/private-shard-1-1024x546.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/private-shard-1-300x160.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/private-shard-1-768x410.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/private-shard-1.png 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>In consortium models, blockchains aren&#8217;t interoperable.</figcaption></figure>



<p>For example, a hospital’s medical data, information on students at a university, or sensitive manufacturing data. All of these datasets have different requirements and needs. On NEAR, a private shard can be created to suit all of these needs, without the need for each of those businesses to build a blockchain from scratch.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the consortium model, each of those use cases would need a separate system that catered for the different requirements. Not on NEAR.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The NEAR blockchain gives enterprises the ability to build private shards that can still be connected to the public blockchain. Why would a business want such a feature? Let’s look at the use cases above.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s say a hospital housed its records on a private shard, but a patient gets sick overseas and a doctor needs access to his or her records. On NEAR, a doctor &#8211; whose identity could be publicly verifiable &#8211; could make a request to the private shard for access to those files simply, and securely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the factory example, there are aspects of manufacturing that need to be private, but then there are other aspects that need to be public. Let’s say a customer wants to know when a product has been built and shipped. A private shard could publish that data to the public blockchain seamlessly.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>In order for mass adoption to occur, blockchain needs to be able to blend the public and the private seamlessly, but safely. Private Shards are NEAR’s solution to that challenge, and it’s as simple as starting a node on AWS or AliCloud. Let’s explore how.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-do-private-shards-work">How do Private Shards work?&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Given private shards operate as a shard on the NEAR network, it means that public chain contracts can call into private shard contracts and vice versa.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is done via the same mechanism that handles cross-shard routing, which is completely transparent to the users and developers and doesn’t require any additional work (public contracts don’t even need to know they are interacting with private ones). Let’s look at a use case: Two private shards want to interact with each other without routing through public shards, how is this achieved? The shared identity space.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignnone size-large wp-image-14229 size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="546" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/private-shard-2-1024x546.png" alt="" class="wp-image-14658" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/private-shard-2-1024x546.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/private-shard-2-300x160.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/private-shard-2-768x410.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/private-shard-2.png 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>In private shards, blockchains can share information without compromising on security.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Each private shard gets its own name, similar to domains on the web. For example, if University of Berkeley and Tencent are using this system, they will have “berkeley.edu” and “tencent.com” accounts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Inside their private shards, specific applications will then have a sub-account, for example, if both of them are using some application to track ownership of real estate: “properties.berkeley.edu” and “properties.tencent.edu”. Selling a property between these two entities then would require a cross private shard transaction with potential public chain settlement later if later this information needs to be proven to the public parties.</p>



<p>Applications that these companies use will be built exactly the same as other applications on NEAR: smart contracts are built in Rust or Typescript. This allows creators to build frontends that can interact with these smart contracts, including sending cross-private and public shard transactions.</p>



<p>NEAR’s mission has been to bridge the gap between the internet of today and the blockchains that will power the future. There is already a company actively working on this solution &#8211; <a href="https://www.calimero.network/">Calimero&#8217;s Private Shards</a>.</p>



<p>Private Shards is a core part of that mission. It helps create an ecosystem where businesses, users, and partners can interact, and we invite anyone to join us in that mission to create a more open, and inclusive web.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-launches-private-shard-for-enterprise/">NEAR’s Private Shard: Infrastructure for Enterprise, Built on the Open Web</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR partners with Ceramic on cross-chain identity and dynamic data storage</title>
		<link>/blog/near-partners-with-ceramic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 15:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=10861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Partnership with Ceramic brings streaming data and cross-chain identity protocols to NEAR developers. Developers building on NEAR Protocol now have …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-partners-with-ceramic/">NEAR partners with Ceramic on cross-chain identity and dynamic data storage</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Partnership with Ceramic brings streaming data and cross-chain identity protocols to</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em> NEAR</em> </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">developers.</span></i></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Developers building on </span><a href="https://docs.near.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR Protocol</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> now have a powerful way to manage user identities and dynamic off-chain data in their applications. </span><a href="https://ceramic.network/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ceramic</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the decentralized network for data stream processing, now supports NEAR wallets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR is currently hosting an Open Web Community <a href="https://createbase.community/hackathon/">Hackathon</a> with a prize for integrating IDX profiles on Ceramic with a NEAR Sputnik DAO. To participate, check out the </span><a href="https://gov.nearpages.wpengine.com/t/2391"><span style="font-weight: 400;">hackathon prize</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">!</span></p>
<h2><b>Blockchain, Data, &amp; Identity: a full stack for Web3 developers</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR offers developers the most dev-friendly and end-user accessible infrastructure for building decentralized apps and services. Great Web3 and DeFi apps require more than a smart contract platform. They also need sophisticated, scalable, and dependable data management infrastructure for app builders using smart contracts. Ceramic provides advanced database-like features such as mutability, version control, access control, and programmable logic. It is also the foundation for </span><a href="http://idx.xyz/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">IDX</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Web3&#8217;s first cross-chain identity model.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the integration of Ceramic on NEAR Protocol, developers on NEAR can: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Build data-rich user experiences and social features on fully decentralized tech</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Give users cloud-like backup, sync, and recovery without running a centralized server</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Publish content on the open web without the need to anchor IPFS hashes on-chain</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leverage interoperable profiles, social graphs and reputations across the Web3 ecosystem</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Ceramic now supports NEAR wallets</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Starting today, developers building applications on NEAR can easily add support for Ceramic and IDX in their application with a seamless user experience. NEAR key pairs have been added as a supported signing and </span><a href="https://developers.ceramic.network/reference/javascript/blockchain/#currently-supported-blockchains"><span style="font-weight: 400;">authentication method</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for Ceramic&#8217;s data streams, so users can now perform transactions on Ceramic with their existing NEAR wallets. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Developers have already started combining NEAR and Ceramic to create new applications such as NEAR Personas, which </span><a href="https://vitalpoint.ai/near-digital-identity/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">links</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a NEAR wallet to a DID.</span></p>
<p><iframe title="NEAR Personas - Decentralized Identity Tutorial" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v2GzFFmuWDM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h2><b>About Ceramic: Decentralized data streams</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ceramic provides developers with database-like functionality for storing all kinds of dynamic, mutable content. This finally gives developers a Web3 native way to add critical features like rich identities (profiles, reputation, social graphs), user-generated content (posts, interactions), dynamic application-data, and much more.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://developers.ceramic.network/learn/overview/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ceramic&#8217;s unique stream-based architecture</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is designed to handle any type of data model at web-scale volume and latency. Built on top of open standards including IPFS, libp2p, and DIDs and compatible with any raw storage protocol like Filecoin or Arweave, all information stored on Ceramic exists within a permissionless cross-chain network that lets developers tap into an ever growing library of identities and data while using their preferred stack.</span></p>
<h2><b>IDX: Cross-chain identity and user-centric data</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Identity is the first use case enabled by Ceramic&#8217;s building blocks for open source information. </span><a href="http://idx.xyz/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">IDX (identity index)</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a cross-chain identity protocol that inherits Ceramic’s properties to provide developers with a user-centric replacement for server-siloed user tables. By making it easy to structure and associate data to a user&#8217;s personal index, IDX lets applications save, discover, and route to users&#8217; data.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The IDX SDK makes it simple to manage users and deliver great data-driven experiences using the same NEAR keys and wallets as developers and users are already relying on. Users can also link multiple keys, from any wallet and multiple blockchains, to the same identity. This is essential to developers who want to serve users over time, as it enables key rotation, data interoperability across accounts, and rich cross-chain profiles, reputations and experiences.</span></p>
<h2><b>Getting started with Ceramic on NEAR</b></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR is currently hosting an Open Web Community </span><a href="https://createbase.community/hackathon"><span style="font-weight: 400;">hackathon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">! There is a prize for integrating IDX profiles on Ceramic with theSputnik DAO platform, built on NEAR. For more information, head to the </span><a href="https://gov.nearpages.wpengine.com/t/2391"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR Forum</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
<li aria-level="1">To install NEAR, start with our <a href="https://docs.near.org/">documentation</a>.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To add IDX to your project, follow this </span><a href="https://developers.idx.xyz/build/installation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">installation guide</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To use Ceramic for streams without IDX, follow this </span><a href="https://developers.ceramic.network/build/installation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">installation guide</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regardless of which option you choose, you should also select 3ID Connect as your DID wallet during the </span><a href="https://developers.ceramic.network/build/authentication/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">authentication</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> process which handles the integration with NEAR wallets.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For questions or support, join the </span><a href="https://chat.ceramic.network/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ceramic Discord</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and the </span><a href="https://near.chat/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEAR Discord</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-partners-with-ceramic/">NEAR partners with Ceramic on cross-chain identity and dynamic data storage</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
