<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NEAR Vietnam Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/near-vietnam/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/near-vietnam/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 15:18:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>NEAR Vietnam Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/near-vietnam/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How Vietnam Became a Web3 Powerhouse </title>
		<link>/blog/how-vietnam-became-a-web3-powerhouse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR APAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Vietnam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Asia is Web3’s engine room. According to a report by Emergen Research, the Web3 global market is expected to be …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/how-vietnam-became-a-web3-powerhouse/">How Vietnam Became a Web3 Powerhouse </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Asia is Web3’s engine room. According to a report by <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/global-web-3-0-market-size-to-reach-usd-81-5-billion-in-2030--emergen-research-301559192.html">Emergen Research</a>, the Web3 global market is expected to be worth $81.5 billion by 2030, growing at an annual rate of more than 40%. Asia is set to capture most of that growth.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s because the region has some of the highest adoption rates of Web3 technologies anywhere in the world. In Japan, more than five million <a href="https://triple-a.io/crypto-ownership-japan-2023/">people currently own cryptocurrency</a>, the South Korean government became the first to <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/05/30/south-koreas-investment-in-the-metaverse-could-provide-a-blueprint.html">directly invest in the metaverse</a>, and &nbsp; <a href="https://www.bain.com/about/media-center/press-releases/sea/southeast-asias-digital-consumers-a-new-stage-of-evolution/">almost 70% of people in Southeast Asia</a> alone have used at least one metaverse-related tech in the last year.</p>



<p>One of the leaders in the region is Vietnam. In recent years, international investors have flooded into Vietnam and established funds specialising in blockchain – with capital inflows into non-fungible token (NFT) assets rising <a href="https://en.vietnamplus.vn/great-chance-for-vietnam-navigate-to-web-30-experts/244413.vnp">from 37 million USD to 4.8 billion USD</a> in 2021.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s why the NEAR Foundation is one of the leading investors in Asia, thanks <a href="https://www.nftgators.com/near-foundation-accelerates-web3-growth-in-asia-with-alibaba-cloud-partnership/">to its partnerships</a> with the likes of Alibaba Cloud, and why it’s hosting its first major conference in Vietnam.</p>



<p>Taking place September 8-12 <a href="https://nearapac.org/">NEAR APAC</a> will bring together more than 100 global blockchain leaders to discuss blockchain’s unlimited future through the latest blockchain technology updates, development trends, and how blockchain ecosystems drive Web3 mass adoption.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-vietnam-on-the-rise">Vietnam on the rise&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Vietnam has all the ingredients to become a Web3 super power. The country has&nbsp;</p>



<p>more than <a href="https://inspius.com/insights/data-on-remote-vietnam-software-engineers/">400,000 skilled software engineers</a>, produces 50,000 IT graduates annually, and has an <a href="https://sunbytes.io/why-software-outsourcing-to-vietnam/">IT</a> labour force more than a million strong.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The nation’s software engineers rank at an impressive <a href="https://inspius.com/insights/data-on-remote-vietnam-software-engineers/">8th place</a> globally in terms of capability — 95% of which have bachelor’s degrees or higher in IT. It’s unsurprising then to hear that Vietnam now has <a href="https://vir.com.vn/opening-up-capital-flows-for-local-blockchain-startups-94821.html">3,800 blockchain-related projects</a>, 200 venture capital funds, and 100 project incubation funds to support the country&#8217;s startups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vietnam&#8217;s tech landscape is now full of startups and innovation hubs fostering creativity in Web3. Local incubators and accelerators provide mentorship, resources, and networking opportunities for Web3 entrepreneurs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That growth also has government support. In 2021, <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2021/07/04/vietnam-prime-minister-asks-central-bank-to-study-crypto-pursue-pilot-implementation-report/">Vietnamese Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh</a> greenlit the country’s &#8220;e-government&#8221; development strategy designed to create regulatory clarity for Web3 projects. Last year, the country launched <a href="https://blockchain.vn/en/about">its first official blockchain association</a>, which is helping blockchain builders and business owners become a bigger part of the regulatory conversation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Its chairman, Hoang Van Huay, has <a href="https://vietcetera.com/en/crypto-curious-vietnam-committed-to-speeding-up-blockchain-development">shared the Vietnam Blockchain Association’s commitment</a> to “providing consultation on building legal framework, regulations, and standards in developing services and products on blockchain”. This commitment is part of a broader mission to accelerate the growth of blockchain technology in Vietnam.</p>



<p>It’s no wonder then that Vietnam <a href="https://vietcetera.com/en/vietnam-leads-global-cryptocurrency-adoption-index-in-2022">ranks first</a> in the Global Cryptocurrency Adoption Index released by Chainalysis, up from 10th place the year before.&nbsp;<br>Vietnam is on the rise, and the NEAR Foundation is here to support it. <a href="https://nearapac.org/">Join us at NEAR APAC on 8-12 September 2023 in Ho Chi Minh City.</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/how-vietnam-became-a-web3-powerhouse/">How Vietnam Became a Web3 Powerhouse </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
