<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Captain&#039;s Call Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/captains-call/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/captains-call/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 19:27:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.orghttps://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Captain&#039;s Call Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/captains-call/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>ICC Launches ‘Captain&#8217;s Call’ Game on NEAR to Level Up Cricket Fandom During World Cup</title>
		<link>/blog/icc-launches-captains-call-game-on-near-to-level-up-cricket-fandom-during-world-cup/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Captain's Call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cricket World Cup 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cricket fans are getting a Web3-powered path to engaging with their favorite international sport. NEAR Foundation and the&#160; International Cricket …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/icc-launches-captains-call-game-on-near-to-level-up-cricket-fandom-during-world-cup/">ICC Launches ‘Captain&#8217;s Call’ Game on NEAR to Level Up Cricket Fandom During World Cup</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Cricket fans are getting a Web3-powered path to engaging with their favorite international sport. NEAR Foundation and the&nbsp; International Cricket Council (ICC), the global governing body of cricket, just teamed up&nbsp; to explore different ways of getting fans closer to their favorite teams and players.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This ICC and NEAR partnership arrives just as the cricket world is watching the Men’s Cricket World Cup 2023. The partnership’s first cricket fan experience, the <em>Captain’s Call</em> gaming app, taps into the NEAR Protocol’s infinite scalability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Watch an animated primer below on the gameplay in <em>Captain&#8217;s Call.</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-level-up-cricket-fandom-with-captain-s-call-game">Level up cricket fandom with <em>Captain’s Call</em> game</h2>



<p>In <em>Captain’s Call</em>, ICC’s first app on the NEAR blockchain, cricket fans compete against each other for the chance of winning prizes. Developed by Wincast, <em>Captain’s Call</em> allows fans to strategize around bowling, batting, and fielding actions during live cricket matches.</p>



<p>To play, fans simply navigate to the ICC’s mobile apps or website, click on the Match Centre for the game they intend to watch, and submit their predictions before the match begins. Players then compete for a chance to win prizes, merchandise, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-beyond-captain-s-call">Beyond <em>Captain’s Call</em></h2>



<p>With NEAR and ICC, Web3 and and sports are on a path of continual innovation. A fan passport is currently in early discussions, which would enable fans to record their actions and memories in a tamper proof way, both on and off chain. <em>Captain’s Call</em> will serve as a template in creating other games that fuses other Web2 and Web3 worlds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of these sporting innovations are possible thanks to the Blockchain Operating System (B.O.S). With its full stack of Web3 tools and easy onboarding, partners like the ICC and others can take advantage of the world’s most highly scalable, community-driven, and secure blockchains that deliver proven, best-in-class performance that can support any kind of Web3 strategy.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Heed the Captain&#039;s Call: Play ICC&#039;s New Game for the Cricket World Cup" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1WS7uJVoMwM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/icc-launches-captains-call-game-on-near-to-level-up-cricket-fandom-during-world-cup/">ICC Launches ‘Captain&#8217;s Call’ Game on NEAR to Level Up Cricket Fandom During World Cup</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
